<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-08T20:42:43+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Knights In Shining Armour</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/08/knights-in-shining-armour" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Knights In Shining Armour" /><published>2019-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/08/knights-in-shining-armour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/08/knights-in-shining-armour">&lt;p&gt;This is my second attempt at writing a blog post today. The first was quite feminist-y and seeing as I &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/05/07/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist-ii&quot;&gt;wouldn’t call myself one&lt;/a&gt;, about halfway through I wondered to myself if I am just
virtue signalling, trying to be a knight in shining armour, the perennial ally, the guy who
isn’t like all the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is solely down to intention - my motivations for the now-axed post may have been
impure, and had I really written from a place of genuine desire for the betterment of women’s
treatment in society, maybe I wouldn’t have felt a little nauseous come the final paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least part of me genuinely &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; want gender equality in our society. Many of my closest
friends are women, and some of my greatest inspirations come from said women around me. I also
feel like we don’t really have the collective energy to spend on fixing these kinds of social issues, and that we face much more pressing problems as a society that we need to be united in
dealing with &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. So maybe I’m not a knight in shining armour. Just a squire. Or perhaps a noble steed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, what is the correct course of action? Maybe it is to do smaller, quieter
things. To be mindful of the way I talk to and about women, to re-examine my own beliefs and
biases, to try to do things better myself in the day to day, and see if others follow. That
seems slow though, maybe bigger, bolder action is necessary, and seeing as I am by and large a
~little bitch~ coward, writing this blog is about as big and bold as I get. But it feels diffifcult to do that in the right way, so it’s difficult, so I feel uncomfortable and unsure doing it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, maybe I should stop whining as per, and remember that once again, I am not the victim.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Feminism" /><summary type="html">This is my second attempt at writing a blog post today. The first was quite feminist-y and seeing as I wouldn’t call myself one, about halfway through I wondered to myself if I am just virtue signalling, trying to be a knight in shining armour, the perennial ally, the guy who isn’t like all the others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build All The Things IV</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/07/build-all-the-things-iv" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build All The Things IV" /><published>2019-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/07/build-all-the-things-iv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/07/build-all-the-things-iv">&lt;p&gt;I’m super lazy about checking whether or not these posts actually get published successfully, I essentially run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; and then go do something else with my life. Despite doing this every day, it turns out that I am incapable of doing it correctly consistently, and frequently receive messages from concerned readers that I have not published a post for that day or the previous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try and rectify this, as well as learn some Python/get into the habit of automating things, I’ve written a script that should hopefully handle publishing as well as testing any new posts -
you can view it &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jonnyspicer/jonnyspicer.github.io/blob/master/publish.py&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; This post was in fact published using the script - I didn’t have to enter a single git command, it’s all handled in one block of Python code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Said code is admittedly very, very bad - I should use unittest or py.test rather than a DIY one, but I couldn’t get the latter working and it seemed relatively trivial to do myself. I also shouldn’t repeat myself so much and I think my method of handling the git commands is exceptionally ugly, but I still know barely any of this language so please be gentle with me!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Software Engineering" /><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">I’m super lazy about checking whether or not these posts actually get published successfully, I essentially run git push and then go do something else with my life. Despite doing this every day, it turns out that I am incapable of doing it correctly consistently, and frequently receive messages from concerned readers that I have not published a post for that day or the previous.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Candid Photos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/06/candid-photos" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Candid Photos" /><published>2019-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/06/candid-photos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/06/candid-photos">&lt;p&gt;This is probably gonna sound super pretentious, but w/e… contrived, posed photos annoy me far more than I know they should. In pursuit of doing it for the ‘gram,
something about trying so hard and taking yourself way too seriously irks me like nothing else. Maybe I’m just jealous because whenever I try to take a picture like that I never know what to do with myhands in photos, idk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Candid photos on the other hand, make me so happy. Trying to capture a genuine moment with one of my friends, be it a smile, a grimace at the exceptionally off-colour joke
I just told, or just something goofy, brings me a lot of joy and I think is far more rewarding than trying to find the best angles and the perfect lighting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Misc" /><summary type="html">This is probably gonna sound super pretentious, but w/e… contrived, posed photos annoy me far more than I know they should. In pursuit of doing it for the ‘gram, something about trying so hard and taking yourself way too seriously irks me like nothing else. Maybe I’m just jealous because whenever I try to take a picture like that I never know what to do with myhands in photos, idk?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cloudflare vs 8chan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/05/cloudflare-vs-8chan" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cloudflare vs 8chan" /><published>2019-08-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/05/cloudflare-vs-8chan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/05/cloudflare-vs-8chan">&lt;p&gt;This morning, &lt;a href=&quot;https://new.blog.cloudflare.com/terminating-service-for-8chan/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare announced&lt;/a&gt; that they would no longer be providing their services to the ‘free speech’-centric messagebaord 8chan, a move that will fairly inevitably lead to it being DDoSed and booted off the internet for some short amount of time. This was Cloudflare’s response to the two recent mass shootings in the state, with at least one of the shooters appearing to have posted his ‘manifesto’ to 8chan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there is a compelling argument to be made that Cloudflare have no right to play judge, jury or executioner, and discontinuing their service to 8chan, as they have in the past with the Daily Stormer, sets a dangerous precedent. I don’t agree though - Cloudflare are a private company, even if they now offer a very public service by propping up a huge portion of total web traffic, and as such are entitled to make any decision they like. While I have never been on 8chan, I’m not going to make any effort to defend it, and think there is a good chance it is every bit as much of a propagator of hate speech as the mainstream media might suggest, and it’s good to know that the decision makers at Cloudflare are scrupulous enough to kick the most extreme sites off their platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well… I say that, but this is 100% a business move, especially with the arguably insensitively timed, virtue-signalling-y blog post. But if free market effects cause companies to do follow some kind of moral code, then I don’t think that’s such a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem though, as acknowledged in said blog post, is that it’s not going to do anything. 8chan will easily find another security provider, and the site will be back up in a matter of days, if not hours. It will continue to provide a safe heaven for the alt right to share their vitriol, and now the genie is out of the bottle, it won’t go back in. 8chan could be chased around the internet, kicked off of every service provider out there, it’d find a way to service, much like The Pirate Bay has. Even if it was shut down, it would inevitably rear it’s ugly head in one form or another shortly afterward. The nature of my beloved internet is such that once born, something cannot die, no matter how despicable and reprehensible it may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare giving 8chan the boot isn’t the answer to the problem of perpetuating extreme views on the internet, but it pains me to say that I don’t have any better suggestions right now either.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="The Web" /><category term="Social Issues" /><summary type="html">This morning, Cloudflare announced that they would no longer be providing their services to the ‘free speech’-centric messagebaord 8chan, a move that will fairly inevitably lead to it being DDoSed and booted off the internet for some short amount of time. This was Cloudflare’s response to the two recent mass shootings in the state, with at least one of the shooters appearing to have posted his ‘manifesto’ to 8chan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 106th British Chess Championships</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/04/the-106th-british-chess-championships" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 106th British Chess Championships" /><published>2019-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/04/the-106th-british-chess-championships</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/04/the-106th-british-chess-championships">&lt;p&gt;This week the 106th edition of the British Chess Championships took place in Torquay, incidentally in the same venue in which I competed in the U14 section many years ago.
It certainly had some thrills and spills, not least with IM Richard Palliser receiving back to back walkovers when he had black against a GM on both occasions in rounds three
and four, leading to some fairly wild accusations from anonymous kibitzers on the internet. While he would play well in his other games and eventually claim joint third, the
competition was always going to be two horse race as soon as the final entry list had been announced, with Micky Adams and David Howell being the thoroughbreds in question.
Adams emerged triumphant, scoring an emphatic 7.5/9 while undefeated to beat Howell’s similarly undefeated 7/9 in a clear second, but the real story I’ve been following all
week is that for the first time in a long time, Guernsey and Jersey have used their qualification spots to send a player to represent themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we get to how the Guernsey representative did, I want to engage in a little schadenfreude at the expense of our Channel Island ocusins, and note that Tito Kahn of Jersey
unfortunately did not have such a great tournament, managing 0.5/8 (with a bye in round 7) and unfortunately propping up the score table. As lovely as Tito is, he forgot my name
at the Inter Insular, so I’m going to call that karma, and justice has now been restored to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guernsey’s Chris Holland on the other hand put up an exceptionally solid 4/9, despite having limited tournament fitness and a very strong field littered with titled players. Chris beat
Tito in round 3, proving that his 8 move Inter Insular draw from May was in fact total bullshit just as we’d suspected, and continued his strong showing to gain rating points and do the
island proud. I’m going to claim some credit and say that him regularly annihlating me in the league was good practice for playing players 1.5x my rating - well done Chris!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Chess" /><summary type="html">This week the 106th edition of the British Chess Championships took place in Torquay, incidentally in the same venue in which I competed in the U14 section many years ago. It certainly had some thrills and spills, not least with IM Richard Palliser receiving back to back walkovers when he had black against a GM on both occasions in rounds three and four, leading to some fairly wild accusations from anonymous kibitzers on the internet. While he would play well in his other games and eventually claim joint third, the competition was always going to be two horse race as soon as the final entry list had been announced, with Micky Adams and David Howell being the thoroughbreds in question. Adams emerged triumphant, scoring an emphatic 7.5/9 while undefeated to beat Howell’s similarly undefeated 7/9 in a clear second, but the real story I’ve been following all week is that for the first time in a long time, Guernsey and Jersey have used their qualification spots to send a player to represent themselves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Slightly More Planned Year (So Far)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2019/08/04/the-slightly-more-planned-year-so-far" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Slightly More Planned Year (So Far)" /><published>2019-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2019/08/04/the-slightly-more-planned-year-so-far</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2019/08/04/the-slightly-more-planned-year-so-far">&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been a very long time since I wrote anything in this blog, and I think an update long overdue at this point. In December &lt;a href=&quot;/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year&quot;&gt;things were bleak&lt;/a&gt;, I was in a very dark place and had struggled for months with feeling like I couldn’t really talk to anyone about it. I was frustrated at the lack of progress with therapy, putting a huge amount of pressure on myself at work, and felt undateable and unloveable in my social life. I was scared, lonely, and desperately trying to find a way out that didn’t involve hurting everyone around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s obvious given that I am writing this now but fortunately I did find said escape route, and subsequently a lot has changed in a short space of time. It all started with a website (which I’m not going to link) devoted to the topic of suicide, discussing its many facets with as little judgment either way as possible. There were studies and statistics, discussion of different methods, ways to get help - the tone was meant to be impartial even though the subject is one of extreme taboo. After perusing through the areas of the site dedicated more to practicality than sentimentality, I decided to read the ‘my story’ section, written by the site’s creator. In it, he described his own unsuccessful attempt to take his life, and his long road to (relative) happiness. On paper, he had it all - a respected, well paying job, he was a handsome guy and in good shape so he got plenty of romantic interest, he had a great network of close friends around him. Or at least, so he thought. Some time after regaining consciousness following an overdose which was intended to be fatal, the individual in question eventually realised that the reason he was unable to contentment was because he was not himself with any of the people around him - he hid away his true feelings, his personality, the things which could have brought him a genuine connection with the people around him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh shit, I thought as I read it. It’s me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gauntlet had been laid down - to be authentic with the people around me. Not to pretend everything was fine; to express my emotions no matter how terrifying a prospect that may be. So slowly, painfully, I gave it a go with a couple of people, and lo and behold, they were both amazing about it. They listened to me, withheld any judgment, and helped pull me out of the hole I was mired in. Spurred on by this initial success, I became increasingly vulnerable with a larger number of people, and the result has been incredible - where I once felt totally isolated, now I have so many relationships that matter to me and that bring me happiness, it’s sometimes difficult to make enough time for all of them. I took the risk by telling the truth, and it has paid off a hundredfold, now I cannot espouse it’s value enough. Honesty has made me so happy in the past few months, and brought me closer to people now than I had previously thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, this year has gone significantly more to plan than last year. I’ve yet to get kicked out of the new flat which I moved into with Sam in January, and actually I’d like to think we’re rather good tenants. I was a little more realistic with my nest-flying plans this time around, so admittedly I am still living quite close to my folks, but the sense of freedom and autonomy that comes from living on my own once more has brought a certain peace and purpose to my life. I’ve got a new job, which I started in May, still following the developer path, but this time doing more software-based work and less on the web. The people there are lovely, the stack is powerful, a lot of the problems we’re solving are ones that interest me, and overall I’m very happy there - the stress levels are markedly lower, and it really feels like I have the rest of my life back. I’m sleeping better, eating better, and finding it easier to make time to see friends or go to the gym after work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job switch is one of two big, perhaps even life-changing events that have happened in the past 7 months, the other being my somewhat well documented trip to New York. That experience was one that I hope will never forget, and the connections that I strengthened and made while I was there were so strong and brought me so much joy, that they really solidified for me what I suspected when I read that story of recovering from a failed suicide all those months ago - that what will make me happy in life, is other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confidence in myself gained on that transatlantic voyage translated into my once-barren dating life becoming rather spicier, and any notion of myself as unloveable has been swept back under the carpet. Furthermore, recent events have meant that my long-held belief (read: excuse) that if I want to attract the kind of people that I’d like to be in a relationship with then I’m going to have to lose weight/look different has similarly evaporated and I’m left with the slightly concerning byproduct that actually, there’s nothing wrong with me and maybe I could have a healthy relationship one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lifestyle has changed a lot too - it’s astounding how much of a difference not being miserable all the time will make when considering whether or not to go for a run, or see friends at the beach. For the past couple of months I have been out of the house with friends more evenings than not, and while the introvert in me is writhing in agony, he now occupies a far less significant portion of my consciousness than he needs in order to have a meaningful effect on my wellbeing. Guernsey is beautiful - the sun, the sea, the beaches - and I have taken them far too granted for the majority of my life. My friends are all beautiful too, even though they all have their fair share of flaws (not least having poor taste in company); now I am in a better place, connecting with them has been easier and more rewarding than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes, things are going well, and I hope it does not come across as some kind of brag, because I really don’t want to be that kind of person. The aim is very much more that it serves as an example of how things can get a lot better in a very short space of time, even when the present situation may be dire, and that there’s great importance in not giving up hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still work to be done though. While it’s important to acknowledge that progress has been made, and to revel in that, it would be naive to think that that is the end of the story, that I am now destined to ride off into the sunset on my horse made of pure serotonin. I’m acutely aware that my current state of relative wellbeing may be precariously balanced atop a run of fortunate life events, and while I have the motivation to do so, I ought to put preventative measures into place to avoid any future backsliding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been plenty of moments where I have felt the spindly fingers of anxiety wrapping themselves around my brain, or I’ve been unsure of how to handle a problem and the ever-present solution of yeeting myself off a cliff has re-emerged in my otherwise serene thought processes. The latter is no longer a valid option though, and while I am going to allow myself to feel anxiety when it’s appropriate, I’m not going to let it control me like it used to. My relationships, both with other people and myself, will always need active and frequent work, and I still want to try every day to push to be a better person lest I stagnate in my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I am feeling better in myself, I want to devote more of my time and effort to standing up for the causes I believe in, and to finding a hill to die on. Wanting to be accepted by everyone around you is fine when you hate yourself and need the validation, but once you love yourself, if you don’t fight for what you think is right then you’re failing at the very thing I said was what made me happy: being honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know what form all this is going to take yet. Maybe I’ll write a tonne of preachy blog posts about social equality, maybe I’ll become a vegan, maybe I’ll start a punk band and write lyrics about The Man. All I know is that it’s not enough to do nothing anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Well, it’s been a very long time since I wrote anything in this blog, and I think an update long overdue at this point. In December things were bleak, I was in a very dark place and had struggled for months with feeling like I couldn’t really talk to anyone about it. I was frustrated at the lack of progress with therapy, putting a huge amount of pressure on myself at work, and felt undateable and unloveable in my social life. I was scared, lonely, and desperately trying to find a way out that didn’t involve hurting everyone around me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Honesty II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/03/radical-honesty-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Honesty II" /><published>2019-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/03/radical-honesty-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/03/radical-honesty-ii">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2017/10/17/radical-honesty&quot;&gt;Radical Honesty&lt;/a&gt; has been both on my mind and my lips a lot recently. After having conversations about it with some of my favourite people in the world I think I am onboard with it than ever - perhaps
still not fullblown, yes-you-do-look-fat-in-that-dress honesty, but certainly &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/05/03/i-love-you-ii&quot;&gt;I-love-you&lt;/a&gt; honesty. The kind where you have difficult conversations when they’re important,
even if you’re nervous, the kind where you’re unashamed to tell someone how you feel about them, the kind where you have no secrets, you own everything you say, do and feel. The expected value is off the charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now the blog is back, I’d like to recommit myself to writing uncomfortably, painfully honestly here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Radical Honesty has been both on my mind and my lips a lot recently. After having conversations about it with some of my favourite people in the world I think I am onboard with it than ever - perhaps still not fullblown, yes-you-do-look-fat-in-that-dress honesty, but certainly I-love-you honesty. The kind where you have difficult conversations when they’re important, even if you’re nervous, the kind where you’re unashamed to tell someone how you feel about them, the kind where you have no secrets, you own everything you say, do and feel. The expected value is off the charts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">50 Ways To Show Someone You Love Them Without Having Sex</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/02/50-ways-to-show-someone-you-love-them-without-having-sex" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="50 Ways To Show Someone You Love Them Without Having Sex" /><published>2019-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/02/50-ways-to-show-someone-you-love-them-without-having-sex</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/02/50-ways-to-show-someone-you-love-them-without-having-sex">&lt;p&gt;I’ve never spoken especially highly of the sex education I received at school, as frankly I feel like it left me wholly unprepared for the complex, emotional realities of sex itself. At the fairly young age of 13 or so, I distinctly remember the inhabitants of our
all male form being handed out purple leaflets, emblazoned with the religion-reminiscent heading ‘50 ways to show someone you love them without having sex’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now here’s the thing. I can’t remember 49 of the things on the list - I’m sure I could hazard a guess and probably get some obvious ones, hold hands, cook them dinner etc etc. But there is one I very explicitly do remember, as something I thought of as bizarre and uncouth over 10 years ago, and my opinion is little changed since - cut their toenails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite not knowing what any of them are, I am confident in saying that I would do any of the remaining 49 displays of affection before I would cut someone else’s toenails. And I would definitely, definitely have sex with them first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is the new bar I should set for trying to find a life partner - somebody I love so much, I’d happily cut their toenails?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Relationships" /><summary type="html">I’ve never spoken especially highly of the sex education I received at school, as frankly I feel like it left me wholly unprepared for the complex, emotional realities of sex itself. At the fairly young age of 13 or so, I distinctly remember the inhabitants of our all male form being handed out purple leaflets, emblazoned with the religion-reminiscent heading ‘50 ways to show someone you love them without having sex’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What’re You Feeling?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/01/whatre-you-feeling" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What're You Feeling?" /><published>2019-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/01/whatre-you-feeling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/01/whatre-you-feeling">&lt;p&gt;Every so often when I’m chatting to slvrsluger, he’ll ask me what I’ve been thinking about recently. It’s a question I usually welcome, as it precedes many interesting conversations - I frequently have indeed had something on my mind recently, but it’s not always easy to steer a conversation towards a certain topic, especially if it has been a personal matter to me. Between men, we don’t
talk about our feelings you know, so this particular line of questioning can be a little disarming, undoubtedly a good thing in this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was recently suggested to me that the question ‘what are you feeling?’ could be a meaningful upgrade on the ‘what are you thinking?’ question, and I am inclined to agree. It serves a similar purpose, to surprise the questionee into displaying some vulnerability, but it is far more effective, and gives a lot less room to manouevre around the machismo-stoic response of ‘nothing’. 
Us men have a remarkable capacity to think nothing, but (at least in my experience) a greatly diminished ability to &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s going to be my new go-to. I feel… sleeeeeepy. But happy. What’re you feeling?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Every so often when I’m chatting to slvrsluger, he’ll ask me what I’ve been thinking about recently. It’s a question I usually welcome, as it precedes many interesting conversations - I frequently have indeed had something on my mind recently, but it’s not always easy to steer a conversation towards a certain topic, especially if it has been a personal matter to me. Between men, we don’t talk about our feelings you know, so this particular line of questioning can be a little disarming, undoubtedly a good thing in this scenario.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Hedonic Treadmill III</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/31/the-hedonic-treadmill-iii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Hedonic Treadmill III" /><published>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/31/the-hedonic-treadmill-iii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/31/the-hedonic-treadmill-iii">&lt;p&gt;Yet more thoughts on the HedTread, as I’ve decided I’m going to start calling it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it exists, would it really matter so much? My own fear of it comes from the idea that I mignt never completely shake off
my melancholic affliction, that any periods of happiness will inevitably be short-lived and that I’ll invariably slide backwards into
greyness. This is assuming that the HedTread refers to every human having an emotional baseline, with meaningful deviation thereof being impossible, and furthermore that my baseline is significantly below ‘contented’, but perhaps this is a flawed assumption. If
everybody has a default emotional state, perhaps it is simple contentment, neutrality, 0 on the y axis of the graph in my mind.
It seems possible that I’ve spent most of my life on some kind of reverse HedTread - perhaps attempting to run down an ascending
escalator of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If neutrality is indeed the norm, maybe striving to be happier without ever making much progress would not be such a bad thing.
As (I think) &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/20/book-reviews-notes-from-underground-by-fyodor-dostoevsky&quot;&gt;Dostoyevsky was getting at&lt;/a&gt;, working
towards a goal seems more fundamental to the human condition than actually achieving it. Chasing true happiness, no matter how unattainable, might give purpose to one’s life, and can there be anything more important in life than purpose? Happiness seems very much akin to enlightenment in this way - maybe there is a compelling argument to be made that they are in fact synonymous - and I’m sure many who are chasing nirvana understand that the journey is far more important than their impossible goal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Yet more thoughts on the HedTread, as I’ve decided I’m going to start calling it…</summary></entry></feed>