<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-31T13:41:33+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Unplanned Year</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Unplanned Year" /><published>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year">&lt;p&gt;
  It’s fair to say that looking back at 2018, it was a radical departure from the
  plan. At the start of the year, I had been rudely awakened from the fever dream
  of ‘professional' poker and found myself lying in the cold pool of sweat that
  was not having a clue what I am going to do with my life. I had been forced to
  deviate from the path I had chosen, and had arrived at what felt more like a
  cul-de-sac than a fork in the road.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  To look further back in time, only a few short years ago I had been at university reading law, with a long
  term girlfriend. I was going to become an advocate, marry her, make an unnecessary
  amount of money, buy a boat and have 2.4 children and a hypoallergenic dog.
  Neither the law nor the lady panned out, so then I got a job as a sports trader
  and rented a flat. Then the plan became to rise through the ranks, become a god-tier
  market analyst, work hard and smart enough to make the company an amount of money
  exponentially more unnecessary than the one aforementioned, and be justly rewarded
  with a portion of it myself. I had officially fled the nest, I was never going
  to move back in with my parents, I would find a new partner and be less impetuous
  about the whole plan-to-be-together-forever thing. I was an Adult, with a capital A.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Obviously that didn’t work out either. It turned out that once again, I had
  displayed exceptionally poor judgment in selecting people close to me, and my
  roommate got us kicked out. Around that time I donked my way to a wholly undeserved
  $25k score in an MTT, and paired my lack of judgment with truly breathtaking
  naïveté by quitting my job and sheepishly moving back in with my parents to play
  poker full time. I slowly bled away the money I had earned over the next few months,
  meanwhile neither furthering my career nor acknowledging my deteriorating mental
  health. In a moment of blind optimism, I once again tried to flee my parents’
  metaphorical basement, by packing a suitcase and heading across the Atlantic,
  to Mexico. I vowed to never come back; I would work hard to overcome my poker
  woes, and enjoy the lifestyle of a digital nomad for the rest of my days. I
  would start a travel Instagram filled with more clichés than a Buzzfeed listicle
  and proceed to have sex with untold numbers of free-spirited
  backpackers who hadn’t showered in weeks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In retrospect, I really don’t understand how I thought that was actually going
  to a work. I’m equal part ashamed of myself and impressed at my own lack of touch
  with reality. This time last year, on the verge of having a breakdown
  that could well have ended my life, I flew back to Guernsey, and moved back in
  with my parents again. I had no job and no plan, but on the bright side I had
  the mother of all existential and identity crises to keep me warm at night. It
  wasn’t actually all that warm: to continue the metaphor, if my self esteem was
  a temperature, it was -273.15°C. The particles of my soul appeared to have ceased
  all vibrations. Everything I had built my identity around had evaporated and I
  really, truly felt like a failure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I survived for three months doing absolutely nothing, spending 15 hours a day
  playing Runescape, leaving the house once a week or less. I didn’t even think
  about the future, only bearing to take one day at a time, focusing solely on my
  virtual life, the entirety of my socialising being with members of my online clan. My character
  seemed to have his life in far better order than I did - he set goals and
  accomplished them. He was perseverant, successful and respected.  If my life
  goals were to complete quests, slay mythical beings and rescue damsels in distress,
  I could’ve learned a lot from being more like him. I was doing my best to numb
  myself to the visceral pain of reality, but I knew living off my parents’ pity
  forever was not a viable lifestyle choice. My less-than-comprehensive ‘plan’
  was to focus on improving my mental health first, and worry about actively
  participating in society later.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  As if I was not already abusing my privilege enough at this point, the universe
  delivered me another lightning bolt of unwarranted good karma at the end of March.
  I dread to think what manner of grim persecution I must’ve faced in a previous life
  to be so fortunate in this one. Out of nowhere, I got an email from my now-employers
  asking if I wanted to interview for a web development position, after having
  speculatively sent them my CV 4 years prior.
  My initial response could be summed up as ‘uhh…. are you sure?’, and much to my
  surprise the answer was yes. This surprise turned to full-blown bafflement upon
  being offered the job in question - what would it be like working for an employer
  that seemed to have such low hiring standards? Had they seen through my ruse of
  confidence and aptitude at the interview, and upon realising how pathetic my existence
  was, decided to offer me the position out of pure compassion? Was I the dog in
  the shelter that nobody else would take home at Christmas, after a lifetime of
  neglect, my fur matted and eyes milky?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It seems not, I had actually fooled them. I can only imagine what the other
  candidates were like. The job pool for developers here is more of a job puddle,
  so I suppose it shouldn’t be that much of a shock to me that they were faced
  with a best-of-a-bad-bunch situation. And here I am, 9 months later, having
  started with no meaningful knowledge of programming whatsoever, now a somewhat
  passable web developer. I’ve picked up quite a few marketable skills: front-end
  CSS and Javascript, back-end PHP, git, Linux, basic server admin and devops.
  I’ve read Hacker News every day for months and have discovered a newfound adoration
  of technology, startups and ideas, as dumb as the last one might sound. The
  industry has given me some sense of hope about the future, that there are people
  genuinely trying to make others’ lives better. I have increased the number of
  acronyms I know by several orders of magnitude, but I still have no clue why
  programmers like recursive ones so much - they’re not funny guys. You can do
  better. Stop it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It seems like I’ve at least accrued some good career capital in 2018 then, but
  has my mental health improved similarly over the last 9 months?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  No, of course not. Don’t be stupid.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I can’t really review the year fairly without talking about my health struggles.
  At the start of the year I was a true NEET, and seemed to have no direction in life at all. Now,
  I leave the house every day, have a full time job and have signed a lease for
  a flat, so you might think I am doing significantly better, but in truth, I don’t
  think I am.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Despite being high functioning, I have been battling depression as frantically as ever
  and I would say this has been one of the worst years of my life in
  that regard. It is a war of attrition, and it has been raging for a long
  time now. Where a proud rockface of motivation and emotional resilience once
  stood, an unforgiving sea of misery has eroded the cliffs such that they are crumbling
  and the homesteads atop them are in an evermore precarious position. I’ve struggled with it
  for 10 years, but when I was younger there was still a sense of hope that this
  was merely teenage angst, and I might grow out of it the same way I grew out of
  eczema and stuffed toys. This year has well and truly brought home the point that
  that isn’t going to happen and that any change is going to be slow, difficult
  and painful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Speaking about depression has become a little easier, but one component
  of it is still a taboo and immensely hard to speak about, even though it is
  the element most necessary to talk about openly and honestly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Talking about suicide is a little bit like talking about the menstrual cycle
  (hear me out). I didn’t get the best sex-ed in school, and when I was a teenager
  with a girlfriend for the first time, I thought I had the basics covered, but
  really I had no clue about how the whole period thing works. One month my it turned out that
  she was late by a couple of days, and I had no idea whether this was normal
  and fine or she was 100% pregnant and I needed to start re-planning my life accordingly.
  On one hand I was a dumb kid, but on the other hand I was in a terrifying situation
  with a lot less information than I would’ve liked. I think trying to talk to
  someone about suicidality is often the same - if I say to someone “I’ve been
  thinking about killing myself recently”, they really have no way of knowing if
  I mean that one rogue thought popped into my head and I have no dangerous intentions
  whatsoever, or if I am planning on ending it all tonight and this is my final
  goodbye. I have had that conversation with a few people this year and every time
  I think I have done a poor job of articulating the reality of the situation and
  explaining what I would like them to do to help me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The truth is, the concept of suicide is a big part of my life, and so I need to
  talk about it. I suppose a big part of the reason it’s difficult to talk about
  is because it can worry the other person, they can feel a sense of responsibility,
  and the knowledge may become a painful burden to them. To try to allay any of
  these worries you might have dear reader, I would like to tell you with a reasonable
  amount of certainty that I will never actually go through with killing myself,
  perhaps barring any major changes to my life circumstances.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There’s always been a part of me that very strongly wants to keep on living,
  and sometimes it is more noticeable than others. I think the fact it is part of my
  consciousness is a good reason to keep going. Given that I have not previously
  taken my own life despite reaching what felt like rock bottom on multiple occasions,
  it seems very unlikely that I will do it in the future, another positive sign.
  Right now I am also more hopeful about improving my health going forward than
  I have been in a long time, maybe ever, for reasons I have already talked about
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/12/david-goggins-ii&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/30/beware-of-dog-ii&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
  I’ve thought about it a lot and felt for a long time like there is a choice to
  be made between killing myself and trying to get better, accepting that the
  latter will be even more agonizing then I feel like my current situation is.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=46GwJbrMghQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  Get busy living or get busy dying,&lt;/a&gt; as one might say.
  So, I have finally made a choice to get better, no matter how harrowing that experience may be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Again, that might sound positive, but to be honest I am struggling with it. The
  main attraction of suicide is that it offers a solution to all your problems,
  albeit an inelegant one. With that solution removed, I am back to the drawing
  board on all the things that are causing me pain in the first place. I feel
  directionless and terrified at the prospect of trying to deal with everything.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But I am determined to deal with it nonetheless. I suppose I'll have to take baby steps.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So that was the unplanned year. Making any kind of plan for next year seems somewhat
  futile - perhaps my life will take another wholly unexpected turn and I make another
  suitably angular career change or end up in some far-flung part of the world or get married
  to someone I’ve yet to meet. Perhaps nothing will change, and I can just copy
  and paste this post for my 2019 year-in-review piece.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am making one plan though - to try everything I can to get better. Happy New Year, friends.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">It’s fair to say that looking back at 2018, it was a radical departure from the plan. At the start of the year, I had been rudely awakened from the fever dream of ‘professional' poker and found myself lying in the cold pool of sweat that was not having a clue what I am going to do with my life. I had been forced to deviate from the path I had chosen, and had arrived at what felt more like a cul-de-sac than a fork in the road. To look further back in time, only a few short years ago I had been at university reading law, with a long term girlfriend. I was going to become an advocate, marry her, make an unnecessary amount of money, buy a boat and have 2.4 children and a hypoallergenic dog. Neither the law nor the lady panned out, so then I got a job as a sports trader and rented a flat. Then the plan became to rise through the ranks, become a god-tier market analyst, work hard and smart enough to make the company an amount of money exponentially more unnecessary than the one aforementioned, and be justly rewarded with a portion of it myself. I had officially fled the nest, I was never going to move back in with my parents, I would find a new partner and be less impetuous about the whole plan-to-be-together-forever thing. I was an Adult, with a capital A. Obviously that didn’t work out either. It turned out that once again, I had displayed exceptionally poor judgment in selecting people close to me, and my roommate got us kicked out. Around that time I donked my way to a wholly undeserved $25k score in an MTT, and paired my lack of judgment with truly breathtaking naïveté by quitting my job and sheepishly moving back in with my parents to play poker full time. I slowly bled away the money I had earned over the next few months, meanwhile neither furthering my career nor acknowledging my deteriorating mental health. In a moment of blind optimism, I once again tried to flee my parents’ metaphorical basement, by packing a suitcase and heading across the Atlantic, to Mexico. I vowed to never come back; I would work hard to overcome my poker woes, and enjoy the lifestyle of a digital nomad for the rest of my days. I would start a travel Instagram filled with more clichés than a Buzzfeed listicle and proceed to have sex with untold numbers of free-spirited backpackers who hadn’t showered in weeks. In retrospect, I really don’t understand how I thought that was actually going to a work. I’m equal part ashamed of myself and impressed at my own lack of touch with reality. This time last year, on the verge of having a breakdown that could well have ended my life, I flew back to Guernsey, and moved back in with my parents again. I had no job and no plan, but on the bright side I had the mother of all existential and identity crises to keep me warm at night. It wasn’t actually all that warm: to continue the metaphor, if my self esteem was a temperature, it was -273.15°C. The particles of my soul appeared to have ceased all vibrations. Everything I had built my identity around had evaporated and I really, truly felt like a failure. I survived for three months doing absolutely nothing, spending 15 hours a day playing Runescape, leaving the house once a week or less. I didn’t even think about the future, only bearing to take one day at a time, focusing solely on my virtual life, the entirety of my socialising being with members of my online clan. My character seemed to have his life in far better order than I did - he set goals and accomplished them. He was perseverant, successful and respected. If my life goals were to complete quests, slay mythical beings and rescue damsels in distress, I could’ve learned a lot from being more like him. I was doing my best to numb myself to the visceral pain of reality, but I knew living off my parents’ pity forever was not a viable lifestyle choice. My less-than-comprehensive ‘plan’ was to focus on improving my mental health first, and worry about actively participating in society later. As if I was not already abusing my privilege enough at this point, the universe delivered me another lightning bolt of unwarranted good karma at the end of March. I dread to think what manner of grim persecution I must’ve faced in a previous life to be so fortunate in this one. Out of nowhere, I got an email from my now-employers asking if I wanted to interview for a web development position, after having speculatively sent them my CV 4 years prior. My initial response could be summed up as ‘uhh…. are you sure?’, and much to my surprise the answer was yes. This surprise turned to full-blown bafflement upon being offered the job in question - what would it be like working for an employer that seemed to have such low hiring standards? Had they seen through my ruse of confidence and aptitude at the interview, and upon realising how pathetic my existence was, decided to offer me the position out of pure compassion? Was I the dog in the shelter that nobody else would take home at Christmas, after a lifetime of neglect, my fur matted and eyes milky? It seems not, I had actually fooled them. I can only imagine what the other candidates were like. The job pool for developers here is more of a job puddle, so I suppose it shouldn’t be that much of a shock to me that they were faced with a best-of-a-bad-bunch situation. And here I am, 9 months later, having started with no meaningful knowledge of programming whatsoever, now a somewhat passable web developer. I’ve picked up quite a few marketable skills: front-end CSS and Javascript, back-end PHP, git, Linux, basic server admin and devops. I’ve read Hacker News every day for months and have discovered a newfound adoration of technology, startups and ideas, as dumb as the last one might sound. The industry has given me some sense of hope about the future, that there are people genuinely trying to make others’ lives better. I have increased the number of acronyms I know by several orders of magnitude, but I still have no clue why programmers like recursive ones so much - they’re not funny guys. You can do better. Stop it. It seems like I’ve at least accrued some good career capital in 2018 then, but has my mental health improved similarly over the last 9 months? No, of course not. Don’t be stupid. I can’t really review the year fairly without talking about my health struggles. At the start of the year I was a true NEET, and seemed to have no direction in life at all. Now, I leave the house every day, have a full time job and have signed a lease for a flat, so you might think I am doing significantly better, but in truth, I don’t think I am. Despite being high functioning, I have been battling depression as frantically as ever and I would say this has been one of the worst years of my life in that regard. It is a war of attrition, and it has been raging for a long time now. Where a proud rockface of motivation and emotional resilience once stood, an unforgiving sea of misery has eroded the cliffs such that they are crumbling and the homesteads atop them are in an evermore precarious position. I’ve struggled with it for 10 years, but when I was younger there was still a sense of hope that this was merely teenage angst, and I might grow out of it the same way I grew out of eczema and stuffed toys. This year has well and truly brought home the point that that isn’t going to happen and that any change is going to be slow, difficult and painful. Speaking about depression has become a little easier, but one component of it is still a taboo and immensely hard to speak about, even though it is the element most necessary to talk about openly and honestly. Talking about suicide is a little bit like talking about the menstrual cycle (hear me out). I didn’t get the best sex-ed in school, and when I was a teenager with a girlfriend for the first time, I thought I had the basics covered, but really I had no clue about how the whole period thing works. One month my it turned out that she was late by a couple of days, and I had no idea whether this was normal and fine or she was 100% pregnant and I needed to start re-planning my life accordingly. On one hand I was a dumb kid, but on the other hand I was in a terrifying situation with a lot less information than I would’ve liked. I think trying to talk to someone about suicidality is often the same - if I say to someone “I’ve been thinking about killing myself recently”, they really have no way of knowing if I mean that one rogue thought popped into my head and I have no dangerous intentions whatsoever, or if I am planning on ending it all tonight and this is my final goodbye. I have had that conversation with a few people this year and every time I think I have done a poor job of articulating the reality of the situation and explaining what I would like them to do to help me. The truth is, the concept of suicide is a big part of my life, and so I need to talk about it. I suppose a big part of the reason it’s difficult to talk about is because it can worry the other person, they can feel a sense of responsibility, and the knowledge may become a painful burden to them. To try to allay any of these worries you might have dear reader, I would like to tell you with a reasonable amount of certainty that I will never actually go through with killing myself, perhaps barring any major changes to my life circumstances. There’s always been a part of me that very strongly wants to keep on living, and sometimes it is more noticeable than others. I think the fact it is part of my consciousness is a good reason to keep going. Given that I have not previously taken my own life despite reaching what felt like rock bottom on multiple occasions, it seems very unlikely that I will do it in the future, another positive sign. Right now I am also more hopeful about improving my health going forward than I have been in a long time, maybe ever, for reasons I have already talked about here and here. I’ve thought about it a lot and felt for a long time like there is a choice to be made between killing myself and trying to get better, accepting that the latter will be even more agonizing then I feel like my current situation is. Get busy living or get busy dying, as one might say. So, I have finally made a choice to get better, no matter how harrowing that experience may be. Again, that might sound positive, but to be honest I am struggling with it. The main attraction of suicide is that it offers a solution to all your problems, albeit an inelegant one. With that solution removed, I am back to the drawing board on all the things that are causing me pain in the first place. I feel directionless and terrified at the prospect of trying to deal with everything. But I am determined to deal with it nonetheless. I suppose I'll have to take baby steps. So that was the unplanned year. Making any kind of plan for next year seems somewhat futile - perhaps my life will take another wholly unexpected turn and I make another suitably angular career change or end up in some far-flung part of the world or get married to someone I’ve yet to meet. Perhaps nothing will change, and I can just copy and paste this post for my 2019 year-in-review piece. I am making one plan though - to try everything I can to get better. Happy New Year, friends.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beware of Dog II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/30/beware-of-dog-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beware of Dog II" /><published>2018-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/30/beware-of-dog-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/30/beware-of-dog-ii">&lt;p&gt;
  There is a dog I have heard barking for the past couple of years. I have grown
  incredibly scared of the sound the dog makes - far more scared than the Mexican
  chihuahua. Hearing it has given me full blown panic attacks, in a way that
  nothing else in my life does. It's definitely got worse over the years. I find
  it really hard to talk about how afraid I am of the noise, I'm deeply ashamed
  of it, because I know I shouldn't feel the way I do. I know that my fear is
  not grounded in reality, and that is alarming in of itself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Anyway, last night I saw the dog. And once I did, I wasn't scared. In fact, it
  was kinda nice, it's a cute dog.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I've been advised a lot recently to 'allow myself to feel my feelings' and other
  similar cookie fortunes. In the wake of last night I have certainly felt a lot of
  feelings today, and have done my best to embrace both the painful and the
  comfortable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Fortunately I wouldn't hear the dog bark very often, so I wouldn't say that
  it was necessarily having a huge effect on my life, but it is definitely
  some of the strongest anxiety when I do. I am hopeful that if I can overcome
  my fear of the dog, I will be able to come anything else I struggle with.
  Wish me luck.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">There is a dog I have heard barking for the past couple of years. I have grown incredibly scared of the sound the dog makes - far more scared than the Mexican chihuahua. Hearing it has given me full blown panic attacks, in a way that nothing else in my life does. It's definitely got worse over the years. I find it really hard to talk about how afraid I am of the noise, I'm deeply ashamed of it, because I know I shouldn't feel the way I do. I know that my fear is not grounded in reality, and that is alarming in of itself. Anyway, last night I saw the dog. And once I did, I wasn't scared. In fact, it was kinda nice, it's a cute dog. I've been advised a lot recently to 'allow myself to feel my feelings' and other similar cookie fortunes. In the wake of last night I have certainly felt a lot of feelings today, and have done my best to embrace both the painful and the comfortable. Fortunately I wouldn't hear the dog bark very often, so I wouldn't say that it was necessarily having a huge effect on my life, but it is definitely some of the strongest anxiety when I do. I am hopeful that if I can overcome my fear of the dog, I will be able to come anything else I struggle with. Wish me luck.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lynx Titan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/29/lynx-titan" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lynx Titan" /><published>2018-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/29/lynx-titan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/29/lynx-titan">&lt;p&gt;
  I am 100% sure I've written about Lynx Titan before, but I can't find where...
  anyway, he finally did it. The Swedish madman has achieved 200m experience in
  every skill on Oldschool Runescape, becoming the first player to do so. It's
  taken him at least 20000 hours over the last 4 years, maybe closer to 25000.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am still undecided as to whether this is a legendary achievement that should
  be marked in the annals of gaming history, or if this is a colossal waste of time
  and the kid should like, get a job or a girlfriend or something. 
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><summary type="html">I am 100% sure I've written about Lynx Titan before, but I can't find where... anyway, he finally did it. The Swedish madman has achieved 200m experience in every skill on Oldschool Runescape, becoming the first player to do so. It's taken him at least 20000 hours over the last 4 years, maybe closer to 25000. I am still undecided as to whether this is a legendary achievement that should be marked in the annals of gaming history, or if this is a colossal waste of time and the kid should like, get a job or a girlfriend or something.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Honesty Problem</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/28/the-honesty-problem" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Honesty Problem" /><published>2018-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/28/the-honesty-problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/28/the-honesty-problem">&lt;p&gt;
  In only the third post on this blog, I wrote about
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2017/10/17/radical-honesty&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Radical Honesty.&lt;/a&gt;
  I talked about about Radical&lt;i&gt;ish&lt;/i&gt; Honesty, which I am now going to call
  Radish Honesty for short, and how I thought it would do me good to try to embrace
  it. Well, over one year later, I have done a bad job of that, so it's time to
  revisit it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Recently, I have become somewhat convinced that a big part of my potential future happiness
  will come from being more honest and open with the people in my life, about
  how I am really feeling (eg actually tell people when I'm depressed and how bad it is).
  I am hoping that talking more about my 'true self' or whatever will help me
  feel more connected and help my overall mental health.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The problem is... if I am employ Radish Honesty with the people around me, I
  more than likely going to be a bit of a Negative Nelly. My friends are going to
  ask me if I'm alright and I'm going to say 'no' and then spontaneously burst
  into tears. I feel like that might get old fast though - so what am I going to
  do?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm pretty scared if I follow all the self help, therapy bullshit advice of
  'be yourself' and 'be vulnerable' and blah blah blah, that I'll just be a
  burden, the miserable friend nobody wants to be around. My poor mental health has
  become a worryingly large part of my identity and personality, and now I don't
  know what else is left. We hear it a million times a day - 'surround yourself
  with positive people' - but I'm not a positive person. What if nobody wants
  me around?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">In only the third post on this blog, I wrote about Radical Honesty. I talked about about Radicalish Honesty, which I am now going to call Radish Honesty for short, and how I thought it would do me good to try to embrace it. Well, over one year later, I have done a bad job of that, so it's time to revisit it. Recently, I have become somewhat convinced that a big part of my potential future happiness will come from being more honest and open with the people in my life, about how I am really feeling (eg actually tell people when I'm depressed and how bad it is). I am hoping that talking more about my 'true self' or whatever will help me feel more connected and help my overall mental health. The problem is... if I am employ Radish Honesty with the people around me, I more than likely going to be a bit of a Negative Nelly. My friends are going to ask me if I'm alright and I'm going to say 'no' and then spontaneously burst into tears. I feel like that might get old fast though - so what am I going to do? I'm pretty scared if I follow all the self help, therapy bullshit advice of 'be yourself' and 'be vulnerable' and blah blah blah, that I'll just be a burden, the miserable friend nobody wants to be around. My poor mental health has become a worryingly large part of my identity and personality, and now I don't know what else is left. We hear it a million times a day - 'surround yourself with positive people' - but I'm not a positive person. What if nobody wants me around?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Social Prescription</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/27/social-prescription" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Prescription" /><published>2018-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/27/social-prescription</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/27/social-prescription">&lt;p&gt;
  When perusing Hacker News today I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/british-doctors-may-soon-prescribe-art-music-dance-singing-lessons-180970750/&quot;
  rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this article,&lt;/a&gt; describing how British GPs
  are going to begin making 'social prescriptions', such as visiting museums or
  taking dance or singing lessons.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  These kinds of activities can allegedly not only help stave off various
  cognodegenerative diseases, but also help with mental health problems such as mine.
  So... should I do these?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I did love playing trumpet in a youth jazz band back in the day. I haven't played
  in years, and I'm not sure if I could exactly practice in my new flat next month -
  I can't imagine my neighbours would take too kindly to it. But, I could do that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I've always wanted to learn to dance, but given how anxious I feel when
  thinking about taking lessons, I struggle to see how it could lessen my anxiety.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am exceptionally bad at drawing and painting, but perhaps I could learn. One
  of my friends is a model for a life drawing class, I think it could be pretty
  funny to surprise her by showing up one day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The museums in Guernsey don't exactly thrill me. I feel like once you've been
  once, you've been a million times.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Is this my problem - that I write off everything straightaway without trying it?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">When perusing Hacker News today I came across this article, describing how British GPs are going to begin making 'social prescriptions', such as visiting museums or taking dance or singing lessons. These kinds of activities can allegedly not only help stave off various cognodegenerative diseases, but also help with mental health problems such as mine. So... should I do these? I did love playing trumpet in a youth jazz band back in the day. I haven't played in years, and I'm not sure if I could exactly practice in my new flat next month - I can't imagine my neighbours would take too kindly to it. But, I could do that. I've always wanted to learn to dance, but given how anxious I feel when thinking about taking lessons, I struggle to see how it could lessen my anxiety. I am exceptionally bad at drawing and painting, but perhaps I could learn. One of my friends is a model for a life drawing class, I think it could be pretty funny to surprise her by showing up one day. The museums in Guernsey don't exactly thrill me. I feel like once you've been once, you've been a million times. Is this my problem - that I write off everything straightaway without trying it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The State of the Blog II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/26/the-state-of-the-blog-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The State of the Blog II" /><published>2018-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/26/the-state-of-the-blog-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/26/the-state-of-the-blog-ii">&lt;p&gt;
  A couple of weeks ago, I wrote about whether or not I still wanted this blog to
  be purely 'for me' or if I wanted to try to share more. Today, the answer is
  definitely, definitely that I still want it to be for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Even considering trying to market the blog a little made me feel under a lot of
  pressure to write longer, higher quality posts every day, but the reality is that
  if I am tired and depressed (which is most days), then I just want to write a short
  post. And writing something short is &lt;i&gt;fine,&lt;/i&gt; because it still serves the
  purpose I had when I started this blog, which was just to get in the habit of
  writing &lt;i&gt;something&lt;/i&gt; every day. Even if that something is short because
  I'm having a rough time, I think that's better than nothing, or forcing myself
  to write something long.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I feel like my posts this last week have been a bit short and maybe not quite
  as good as some were the week before that. I'm not gonna beat myself about it
  though, and I am about halfway through my 2018 year in review piece and it's
  looking like a long one, so you have that to look forward to.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Blogging" /><summary type="html">A couple of weeks ago, I wrote about whether or not I still wanted this blog to be purely 'for me' or if I wanted to try to share more. Today, the answer is definitely, definitely that I still want it to be for me. Even considering trying to market the blog a little made me feel under a lot of pressure to write longer, higher quality posts every day, but the reality is that if I am tired and depressed (which is most days), then I just want to write a short post. And writing something short is fine, because it still serves the purpose I had when I started this blog, which was just to get in the habit of writing something every day. Even if that something is short because I'm having a rough time, I think that's better than nothing, or forcing myself to write something long. I feel like my posts this last week have been a bit short and maybe not quite as good as some were the week before that. I'm not gonna beat myself about it though, and I am about halfway through my 2018 year in review piece and it's looking like a long one, so you have that to look forward to.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflecting On: Ramblings I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/25/reflecting-on-ramblings-i" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflecting On&amp;#58; Ramblings I" /><published>2018-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/25/reflecting-on-ramblings-i</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/25/reflecting-on-ramblings-i">&lt;p&gt;
  I think &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2017/12/26/ramblings-i&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ramblings I&lt;/a&gt;
  is probably my favourite post from Mendokusai. Written a year ago tomorrow, it
  was when I was in the eye of the storm, a surprisingly moment of tranquility
  amid a torrent of anguish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The sentiment I expressed is one I would do well to remember more often, if I
  were ever to do some kind of daily affirmation type-thing, then this would likely
  be a part of it. 'Why do I have to be so ground down in order to feel so much
  love for the people around me?'
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I think Ramblings I is probably my favourite post from Mendokusai. Written a year ago tomorrow, it was when I was in the eye of the storm, a surprisingly moment of tranquility amid a torrent of anguish. The sentiment I expressed is one I would do well to remember more often, if I were ever to do some kind of daily affirmation type-thing, then this would likely be a part of it. 'Why do I have to be so ground down in order to feel so much love for the people around me?'</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Booking Flights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/24/booking-flights" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Booking Flights" /><published>2018-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/24/booking-flights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/24/booking-flights">&lt;p&gt;
  A year ago today, on the brink of a spectular mental breakdown, I booked a
  (very expensive) transatlantic flight for the next day, and spent 10 hours on
  Christmas tipsy and sleep deprived 35000ft above the big blue ocean. I was a bit
  of a mess to the say the least.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This year I am booking more flights, and I'm still a mess, but not quite as bad
  as last time. They're for a trip to go see one of my favourite bands and stay
  with one of my oldest friends next month, and I know it's going to make me
  very happy. I haven't solved any of the problems that I felt I was facing this
  time last year, but I think I have grown a little as a person, and I've got some
  ideas about how I'm going to figure my shit out.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Merry Christmas y'all ✌️
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">A year ago today, on the brink of a spectular mental breakdown, I booked a (very expensive) transatlantic flight for the next day, and spent 10 hours on Christmas tipsy and sleep deprived 35000ft above the big blue ocean. I was a bit of a mess to the say the least. This year I am booking more flights, and I'm still a mess, but not quite as bad as last time. They're for a trip to go see one of my favourite bands and stay with one of my oldest friends next month, and I know it's going to make me very happy. I haven't solved any of the problems that I felt I was facing this time last year, but I think I have grown a little as a person, and I've got some ideas about how I'm going to figure my shit out. Merry Christmas y'all ✌️</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading List</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading List" /><published>2018-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list">&lt;p&gt;
  I'd like to read more. I've been thinking about doing one of those stupid 'read
  x books in y time intervals', maybe a book a week for the whole year. I am pretty
  sure I won't keep it up for the whole year, but it'd be fun to try. Here's my
  reading list so far (suggestions appreciated):
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Mikhail Bulgakov - The Master and Margarita
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    David Goggins - Can't Hurt Me
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Nassim Nicholas Taleb - Black Swan
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Nassim Nicholas Taleb - Skin in the Game
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Malcolm Gladwell - Blink
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Robert Pirsig - Zen and the Art of Motorycle Maintenance
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Jack Kerouac - On the Road
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Jack Kerouac - The Dharma Bums
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    George Watsky - How to Ruin Everything
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Tim Ferriss - Tools of Titans
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Steven Kotler - The Rise of Superhuman
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Fyodor Dostoevsky - Notes from Underground
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Fyodor Dostoevsky - The Double
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Ben Schwartz, Laura Moses - Things You Should Already Know About Dating, You Fucking Idiot
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Noam Chomsky - On Anarchism
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    David Eagleman - Incognito
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Alan Watts - The Way of Zen
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Viktor Frankl - Man's Search for Meaning
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Julian Baggini - The Pig That Wants to be Eaten
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    David Foster Wallace - Infinite Jest
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Leonard Mlodinow - The Drunkard's Walk
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Cal Newport - Deep Work
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Matthew Walker - Why We Sleep
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Michael Pollan - How to Change Your Mind
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Yuval Noah Harari - Homo Deus: A Brief History of Tomorrow
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Chris Voss - Never Split the Difference
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Jocko Willink - Extreme Ownership
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Jordan Peterson - 12 Rules for Life
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Venedikt Erofeev - Moscow to the End of the Line
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Witold Gombrowicz - Ferdydurke
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Jaroslav Hašek - Adventures of the Good Soldier Svejk
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Vladimir Nabokov - The Defense
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Liu Cixin - The Dark Forest
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Liu Cixin - Death's End
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Isaac Asimov - Foundation
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Isaac Asimov - Foundation and Empire
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Isaac Asimov - Second Foundation
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think I'll try and do reviews on Sundays, to keep on track. Good luck me.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I'd like to read more. I've been thinking about doing one of those stupid 'read x books in y time intervals', maybe a book a week for the whole year. I am pretty sure I won't keep it up for the whole year, but it'd be fun to try. Here's my reading list so far (suggestions appreciated): Mikhail Bulgakov - The Master and Margarita David Goggins - Can't Hurt Me Nassim Nicholas Taleb - Black Swan Nassim Nicholas Taleb - Skin in the Game Malcolm Gladwell - Blink Robert Pirsig - Zen and the Art of Motorycle Maintenance Jack Kerouac - On the Road Jack Kerouac - The Dharma Bums George Watsky - How to Ruin Everything Tim Ferriss - Tools of Titans Steven Kotler - The Rise of Superhuman Fyodor Dostoevsky - Notes from Underground Fyodor Dostoevsky - The Double Ben Schwartz, Laura Moses - Things You Should Already Know About Dating, You Fucking Idiot Noam Chomsky - On Anarchism David Eagleman - Incognito Alan Watts - The Way of Zen Viktor Frankl - Man's Search for Meaning Julian Baggini - The Pig That Wants to be Eaten David Foster Wallace - Infinite Jest Leonard Mlodinow - The Drunkard's Walk Cal Newport - Deep Work Matthew Walker - Why We Sleep Michael Pollan - How to Change Your Mind Yuval Noah Harari - Homo Deus: A Brief History of Tomorrow Chris Voss - Never Split the Difference Jocko Willink - Extreme Ownership Jordan Peterson - 12 Rules for Life Venedikt Erofeev - Moscow to the End of the Line Witold Gombrowicz - Ferdydurke Jaroslav Hašek - Adventures of the Good Soldier Svejk Vladimir Nabokov - The Defense Liu Cixin - The Dark Forest Liu Cixin - Death's End Isaac Asimov - Foundation Isaac Asimov - Foundation and Empire Isaac Asimov - Second Foundation I think I'll try and do reviews on Sundays, to keep on track. Good luck me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Value of Conversation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/22/the-value-of-conversation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Value of Conversation" /><published>2018-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/22/the-value-of-conversation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/22/the-value-of-conversation">&lt;p&gt;
  If there's one thing that Chicago Joey taught me, it's &lt;s&gt;how to talk to women&lt;/s&gt;
  &lt;s&gt;that you should never fold to 3bets in PLO&lt;/s&gt; the value of conversation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Today, a particularly wise friend of mine asked if my anxiety had ever served me
  well. I'd never really considered it before, but the answer was yes - there had
  been times when avoiding people, or heavily censoring my own thoughts and feelings
  had been the appropriate response to the situation I was in. The problem is that
  now I have learned this behaviour, its lingering presence in my psyche is no
  longer useful to me, and it has dug its quivering, sweaty heels in, so to speak.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Having a simple, honest conversation with someone I respected gave me this gem
  of pure clarity and insight into my own life, a conclusion that I may never
  have arrived at on my own. People are wonderful, thank you Joey.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">If there's one thing that Chicago Joey taught me, it's how to talk to women that you should never fold to 3bets in PLO the value of conversation. Today, a particularly wise friend of mine asked if my anxiety had ever served me well. I'd never really considered it before, but the answer was yes - there had been times when avoiding people, or heavily censoring my own thoughts and feelings had been the appropriate response to the situation I was in. The problem is that now I have learned this behaviour, its lingering presence in my psyche is no longer useful to me, and it has dug its quivering, sweaty heels in, so to speak. Having a simple, honest conversation with someone I respected gave me this gem of pure clarity and insight into my own life, a conclusion that I may never have arrived at on my own. People are wonderful, thank you Joey.</summary></entry></feed>