<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Miss Anthropocene Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After teasing the album for almost an entire year (which I think is ridiculous), Grimes &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt;
released her long-awaited followup to 2015 art-pop behemoth Art Angels in the form of her new LP,
Miss Anthropocene. The title is in my book a winner, being a pun on misanthropy and the 
anthropecene era, which naturally we are currently living through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the album having been in the works for so long, I had already listened to all of the singles
quite a bit, and being 5 in number they contribute 50% of the total songs on the record (6/11 if
you have the Japanese edition bonus track).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Miss Anthropocene feels like a natural evolution of Grimes’ style, forging into new
territory while retaining all the quintessential trademarks of her music. The vast ambient
soundscapes are difficult to liken to anything else I’ve heard - imagine if Aphex Twin were a
post metal band, and you’ll be in the right ballpark. Her signature soprano vocals are mellifluous
over the top of the rich layers beneath, and her songwriting and lyricism is, as always, far
superior to most other pop artists. The only thing I really don’t like about it is the introduction
to the final track, ‘IDORU’, which sounds &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much like a car alarm that I refuse to accept that
it could be anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that the album is solid, and has already earned several repeat listens, although it’s
doubtful to be a contender for my album of the year. 7.5/10 - now to wait and see what the baby
is going to be called.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/25/miss-anthropocene-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/25/miss-anthropocene-review</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Infinite Jest&amp;#58; I've Written a Novel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, Josh and I had a conversation about how we’d never write a novel, because we’d want it to
be our own Infinite Jest, and neither of us are any David Foster Wallace. It seemed like a thankless
creative endeavour as we would both set wholly unrealistic and unattainably high bars for ourselves,
and so we would simply never even try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, according to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jonnyspicer/jonnyspicer.github.io/blob/master/wordcount.py&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;calculations&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve actually written enough words in the last 3 and a bit years to
constitute a fairly beefy novel: approximately 150,862 (in reality it is probably higher as that
script only splits words by spaces, and I quite like doing that-thing-where-you-hyphenate-all-the-words). According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://self-publishingschool.com/how-many-words-in-a-novel/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this completely arbitrary source&lt;/a&gt;, that’s more words than any
category of non-technical book they list. Admittedly, it’s still not quite Infinite Jest, which,
according to Ryan Compton, weighs in at a hefty &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryancompton.net/2014/06/06/statistical-features-of-infinite-jest/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;577,608 words.&lt;/a&gt; Clearly a lot of my words are (exceptionally) low quality,
but still, I clearly have it in me to write the kind of volume required for a novel, and in a
reasonable amount of time, as I am demonstrably not a full time writer, nor do I consider blogging
a hobby, it usually only occupies ten minutes of my day. So, perhaps, one day…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/24/infinite-jest-ive-written-a-novel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/24/infinite-jest-ive-written-a-novel</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Great Game</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received a welcome reminder as to why PLO is lovingly dubbed “The Great Game”, and all
other variants are secondary to it. It’s simply this; in PLO, you can bluff and get called by
worse hands. Can a game be any greater than that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/23/the-great-game</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/23/the-great-game</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Peaceful Battle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are surprsied when I tell them how long our
chess league matches take - at least a couple of hours - and
seemingly can’t imagine spending so much time doing so little. But I find it very easy these days, and in fact I
would happily do it for longer if I had the chance. I find
the game very meditative and present - when I sit down to play, nothing else in the world matters, or even really exists, there is simply myself, my opponent, and the board.
It’s a wonderful opportunity to have a comparatively quiet
mind for a couple of hours every week, and I would strongly
recommend it to all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/22/a-peaceful-battle</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/22/a-peaceful-battle</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buho</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight I’m going to a fancy Mexican restaurant. Only, the thing is, as someone who can now pretentiously claimed that they lived in Mexico briefly, I know there’s no such thing as an
&lt;em&gt;authentic&lt;/em&gt; fancy Mexican restaurant. If it isn’t fried in 3 pigs worth of pork fat and served
to you by a 400lb, 5’2 Mexican lady who clearly hates you because you’re white and your Spanish
sucks, then it simply isn’t legitimate Mexican cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, fake-ass fancy Mexican is still &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; tasty and the tequila tastes the same either
which way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/21/buho</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/21/buho</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Staff Car Parks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The parking situation at the local hospital is, frankly, a fucking nightmare. It’s always so full that not only are there no spaces, but cars are scattered all over the shop, protruding onto the
roads and paths and just making the whole experience unnecessarily cumbersome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however, a staff car park. The forbidden fruit - an oasis of gravel and opportunity amidst
the frozen tundra of why-are-there-never-any-fucking-spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I parked there, because life is too short not to. Fuck the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/20/staff-car-parks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/20/staff-car-parks</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Violent Video Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time violent video games got a bad rap, and I think by and large people are pretty over it, but I actually think they can (potentially) be a powerful &lt;em&gt;positive&lt;/em&gt;
tool for catharsis and emotional regulation. My evidence is purely anecdotal of course, but after a long, stressful, angry day today, I sat down this evening to murder hordes
of zombies in Killing Floor 2, its tech-death soundtrack blaring through my headphones. Having played through a few levels, my body count now in the thousands, I already feel a
lot calmer, and have processed some of rage and frustation
today has inflicted upon me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/19/violent-video-games</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/19/violent-video-games</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things That Are More Therapeutic Than Therapy IV&amp;#58; Swimming in the Sea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My GP spent a good portion of our January appointments trying to persuade me that I should join the local sea swimming group, and that it would be good for my mental health. I
would’ve been infinitely more open to the idea in any other month, but January just seemed a little too optimistic. Now we’re knee deep in &lt;del&gt;clu&lt;/del&gt; February though, I
decided to take the plunge, both figuratively and literally, and joined them bright and early at 7am this morning. The air temperature was an invigorating 8 degrees celsius,
and I don’t want to even think about what the water temperature was. It was bracing, invigorating, and life-affirming, but really the best bit was what came after. Once I’d
managed an entire length of the pool (!!) we got out and peered east, across the water to Herm and Sark, silhouetted by the dawn. And then, to warm up, one of my newfound
swimming companions showed us some kind of dance/chant/thing to warm up as we faced the sun. Sharing that, with complete strangers, was how I think life should be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/18/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-iv58-swimming-in-the-sea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/18/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-iv58-swimming-in-the-sea</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adjusting For Your Own Biases</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I am wholly indebted to the poker lifestyle for is an awareness of my own biases. A lot of the discussion surrounding
poker’s mental game revolves around how to identify and correct for biases in your decision making, in order to improve said decisions,
and now I do my best to question my own biases in other aspects of life. Arrogantly, I think I do so reasonably well - at the very
least better than I did pre-poker - but this is only half the battle, and I worry I am very much losing the second half. If you
know you’re biased towards one option when making a decision, how do you actually go about correcting for it? Over-correcting
is just as unhelpful as being biased in the first place… How can you quantify bias, without ending up in some levelling-war
death-spiral? Hang on, I think my nose is bleeding…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/17/adjusting-for-your-own-biases</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/17/adjusting-for-your-own-biases</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things That Are More Therapeutic Than Therapy III&amp;#58; Bumpy Flights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having had to brave Storm Dennis from inside his bowels at approximately 24000ft in the air,
today was a jarring reminder of the deepset fear brought on by in-flight turbulence. The acute anxiety experienced as an aircraft rolls, pitches and yaws its perrilous way toward the ground
is an excellent opportunity to practice how to deal with things outside of our own control. Rationally, I knew that I was essentially completely safe, and this situation was far less dangerous than
basically every time I drive a car. I knew there was nothing I could do about it; my catastrophisizing was not going to change the weather, for regrettably I am not Zeus himself. All I could do was
close me eyes, breath, and accept my current reality, and as it turns out, I did live to fight another day. I think the practicee in these kinds of scenarios is invaluable, as they are very intense
but also very simple, and so any skills learned can easily be transplanted into social situations - or at least I hope so. Still, I’m glad I’m not flying again anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/16/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-bumpy-flights</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/16/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-bumpy-flights</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>