<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Satire's Golden Age</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are living in a bizarro timeline where satire and authenticity are homogenous and indistinguishable, such that the former is wholly effortless, and I worry that satire-as-an
-artform is soon to be lost to the sands of time. I recently watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CEVdca9U9LM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;We Like Sportz&lt;/a&gt;, a mere 11 years old, and
it already feels a little forced and somewhat out of place amongst today’s ultra-meta satirical landscape (although I still think it’s hilarious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the barrier for legitimately excellent satire is simply much higher, now it is easier to come by in mediocrity… Maybe if I ever get round to writing my novel, it’ll
be a caricaturish magnum opus. Did I mention I’m reading Infinite Jest?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/28/satires-golden-age</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/28/satires-golden-age</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Barkley Marathons II</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows what The Barkley Marathons is, knows that you have to be insane to enter it. To actually complete it, you have to be a physical and psychological freak of
nature - a case study for textbooks spanning a variety of fields - make sure you donate your body and brain to science after you die trying to swim across the Atlantic etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, there is Jared Campbell. His trail and ultrarunning CV is certainly impressive: he’s completed the legendary Hardrock 100 ten times, including winning it in 2010.
But it’s his accomplishments at the Barkley that mark him as a one-of-a-kind. He is one of only 15 people to have ever completed the Barkley Marathons, one of two to have
repeated that feat, and the only person to have made it through all 5 gruelling loops three times. And on top of all that… he keeps entering. He had to drop out last year
after his first loop because of an ankle injury. Why, when you accomplish something so utterly ludicrous as completing the Barkley, would you not be satisfied, nor when you
have done so twice or thrice, and you feel the need to repeatedly push yourself to the farthest extremes of your soul over and over?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat ironically, I think being the kind of person who will enter the Barkley after having already completed it three times is one of the few indicators that you are the
kind of person who might actually complete the infernal task a single time in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/27/the-barkley-marathons-ii</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/27/the-barkley-marathons-ii</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ego in Chess II</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I had the pleasure of playing &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/13/ego-in-chess&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; in the
league once more. It wasn’t quite over in 18 moves… but it was close, only 22, and this time
he wasn’t ill. He did still say something hilarious to me though, after my win (my third consecutively against him), “I don’t know what it is, I always seem to get compromised positions
against you… I think you’re a bad stylistic matchup for me”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come on bro, just say I am better than you, it’s not going to hurt - at least not physically… 
Once again it feels good to indulge in my own ego though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/26/ego-in-chess-ii</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/26/ego-in-chess-ii</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Miss Anthropocene Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After teasing the album for almost an entire year (which I think is ridiculous), Grimes &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt;
released her long-awaited followup to 2015 art-pop behemoth Art Angels in the form of her new LP,
Miss Anthropocene. The title is in my book a winner, being a pun on misanthropy and the 
anthropecene era, which naturally we are currently living through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the album having been in the works for so long, I had already listened to all of the singles
quite a bit, and being 5 in number they contribute 50% of the total songs on the record (6/11 if
you have the Japanese edition bonus track).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Miss Anthropocene feels like a natural evolution of Grimes’ style, forging into new
territory while retaining all the quintessential trademarks of her music. The vast ambient
soundscapes are difficult to liken to anything else I’ve heard - imagine if Aphex Twin were a
post metal band, and you’ll be in the right ballpark. Her signature soprano vocals are mellifluous
over the top of the rich layers beneath, and her songwriting and lyricism is, as always, far
superior to most other pop artists. The only thing I really don’t like about it is the introduction
to the final track, ‘IDORU’, which sounds &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much like a car alarm that I refuse to accept that
it could be anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that the album is solid, and has already earned several repeat listens, although it’s
doubtful to be a contender for my album of the year. 7.5/10 - now to wait and see what the baby
is going to be called.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/25/miss-anthropocene-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/25/miss-anthropocene-review</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Infinite Jest&amp;#58; I've Written a Novel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, Josh and I had a conversation about how we’d never write a novel, because we’d want it to
be our own Infinite Jest, and neither of us are any David Foster Wallace. It seemed like a thankless
creative endeavour as we would both set wholly unrealistic and unattainably high bars for ourselves,
and so we would simply never even try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, according to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jonnyspicer/jonnyspicer.github.io/blob/master/wordcount.py&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;calculations&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve actually written enough words in the last 3 and a bit years to
constitute a fairly beefy novel: approximately 150,862 (in reality it is probably higher as that
script only splits words by spaces, and I quite like doing that-thing-where-you-hyphenate-all-the-words). According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://self-publishingschool.com/how-many-words-in-a-novel/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this completely arbitrary source&lt;/a&gt;, that’s more words than any
category of non-technical book they list. Admittedly, it’s still not quite Infinite Jest, which,
according to Ryan Compton, weighs in at a hefty &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryancompton.net/2014/06/06/statistical-features-of-infinite-jest/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;577,608 words.&lt;/a&gt; Clearly a lot of my words are (exceptionally) low quality,
but still, I clearly have it in me to write the kind of volume required for a novel, and in a
reasonable amount of time, as I am demonstrably not a full time writer, nor do I consider blogging
a hobby, it usually only occupies ten minutes of my day. So, perhaps, one day…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/24/infinite-jest-ive-written-a-novel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/24/infinite-jest-ive-written-a-novel</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Great Game</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received a welcome reminder as to why PLO is lovingly dubbed “The Great Game”, and all
other variants are secondary to it. It’s simply this; in PLO, you can bluff and get called by
worse hands. Can a game be any greater than that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/23/the-great-game</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/23/the-great-game</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Peaceful Battle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are surprsied when I tell them how long our
chess league matches take - at least a couple of hours - and
seemingly can’t imagine spending so much time doing so little. But I find it very easy these days, and in fact I
would happily do it for longer if I had the chance. I find
the game very meditative and present - when I sit down to play, nothing else in the world matters, or even really exists, there is simply myself, my opponent, and the board.
It’s a wonderful opportunity to have a comparatively quiet
mind for a couple of hours every week, and I would strongly
recommend it to all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/22/a-peaceful-battle</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/22/a-peaceful-battle</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buho</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight I’m going to a fancy Mexican restaurant. Only, the thing is, as someone who can now pretentiously claimed that they lived in Mexico briefly, I know there’s no such thing as an
&lt;em&gt;authentic&lt;/em&gt; fancy Mexican restaurant. If it isn’t fried in 3 pigs worth of pork fat and served
to you by a 400lb, 5’2 Mexican lady who clearly hates you because you’re white and your Spanish
sucks, then it simply isn’t legitimate Mexican cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, fake-ass fancy Mexican is still &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; tasty and the tequila tastes the same either
which way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/21/buho</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/21/buho</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Staff Car Parks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The parking situation at the local hospital is, frankly, a fucking nightmare. It’s always so full that not only are there no spaces, but cars are scattered all over the shop, protruding onto the
roads and paths and just making the whole experience unnecessarily cumbersome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however, a staff car park. The forbidden fruit - an oasis of gravel and opportunity amidst
the frozen tundra of why-are-there-never-any-fucking-spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I parked there, because life is too short not to. Fuck the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/20/staff-car-parks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/20/staff-car-parks</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Violent Video Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time violent video games got a bad rap, and I think by and large people are pretty over it, but I actually think they can (potentially) be a powerful &lt;em&gt;positive&lt;/em&gt;
tool for catharsis and emotional regulation. My evidence is purely anecdotal of course, but after a long, stressful, angry day today, I sat down this evening to murder hordes
of zombies in Killing Floor 2, its tech-death soundtrack blaring through my headphones. Having played through a few levels, my body count now in the thousands, I already feel a
lot calmer, and have processed some of rage and frustation
today has inflicted upon me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/19/violent-video-games</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/19/violent-video-games</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>