<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The End of Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning I got up at 5:35am, to discover it was still dark outside. It was the first time it’d been black outside my window upon
waking in months, and I was hit by a sudden pang of &lt;a href=&quot;https://polly.gg/2019/08/26/new-year-new-me&quot;&gt;post-season melancholy&lt;/a&gt; - the
summer is over, for another year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason I am sad is because it’s been quite the summer for me, possible the best of the past decade. I can’t remember a
year where I spent so much of it outside in the sun, spent so much time with my friends, or went swimming in the sea so often. I even
have a bit of a tan, which is practically unheard of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed a lot as a person over the summer too. My confidence and self-esteem have grown to the point where I borderline love myself. I don’t hate having photos taken of me anymore (not as much at least). I feel more comfortable carrying a conversation,
being myself, and looking in the mirror. It’s pretty neat. So maybe I do not need to reinvent myself in time for academic new year -
I am pretty happy with where I am. I don’t need to set too many lofty goals or high expectations for the near future, and just enjoy
things as they are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/27/the-end-of-summer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/27/the-end-of-summer</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TI9</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday saw the final of The International 9, the Dota2 World Championships, hosted for the first time in Asia, in the Mercedes-Benz Arena, Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one hand, TI has been a little repetitive over the past couple of years - the prizepool is huge, the format is complicated, there’s only so much you can do with an event of this nature, and Valve
already appear to be doing it. On the other, the tournament will always have a special place in my heart, and the storylines it creates are always fantastical, no matter how the brackets might turn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year was no different. World champions of two years ago, Team Liquid, were unceremoniously dumped into the lower bracket and had to fight through from the BO1 stage. EG broke their third place curse -
by coming 5th. Home favourites PSG.LGD couldn’t quite make it to the finals, crashing out in third. Alliance and Navi both played in a TI for the first time since 2016, and heartbreakingly
didn’t meet one another at any point in the tournament. VP imploded after having reached
the upper bracket. NIP sucked, amidst their organisation being embroiled in a massive scandal
outside of the server. I could go on and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest story was of course OG, last year’s champions. After finishing only 10th in the Dota Pro Circuit, they barely made it to the event without having to go through the qualifiers
again. Their wunderkind safelaner, Ana, had only returned to the team in March after having
taken a break from competitive play. No team has ever won two TIs, but nobody seemed to have
told OG that their Cinderella’s ball shouldn’t go on this long. They battled through the upper
bracket, beating some of their old teammates on EG along the way and relegating PSG.LGD to
the lower bracket final before coming up against Team Liquid, off the back of a miraculous lower bracket run, in the final.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And honestly, they kinda stomped them. The way they played was sublime. After this performance,
they are arguably the greatest team in the history of the game. Ceb, the coach who was never
meant to be a professional player, is now a two time world champion. N0tail, a player who
I’ve followed since he was on Fnatic.eu in 2012, is now the highest earning esports player in
the world, with just shy of $7 million in earnings. Jerax has gone from being on the QPad Red
Pandas to being one of the best supports in the world. Topson has transitioned from pubstar
into competitive monster. And Ana has managed to casually carry his team to victory on the
game’s biggest stage twice, all while seemingly largely apathetic about the whole affair. They
even made it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-49471963&quot;&gt;onto the beeb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to a TI is one of the foremost items on my bucket list, and it was announced that next
year the event will be held in Stockholm, making it much more feasible for me to actually go.
I’m full of hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/26/ti9</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/26/ti9</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self Control</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s now been a week of trying to go without both meat and alcohol. I want to talk about it without being preachy about it, however sadly I’m not sure the two are compatible, so, sorry in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason I gave up both of them was to try and feel better about myself, which certainly does not make me think or feel like I’m better than anyone who consumes those two things. Losing weight
is definitely a major driver in these changes, and I think cutting out alcohol is one of the best “easy” ways to meaningfully reduce my weekly calorie intake. Not eating meat, while not necessarily inherently
cutting down on the number of calories I consume, will force me to make conscious decisions about what foods I eat, which I hope will in turn lead to better self control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of self control, I think that is likely to be the biggest benefit to my new regime. Not feeling like I need to drink or binge-eat to regulate my emotions would be a huge step in the right direction,
and already making only a handful of “good” choices (like getting a tap water in the pub last night) have left me feeling proud of myself for not capitulating to the desires of my monkey brain like I so often do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I can keep it up, at least until Christmas. I’ll report back later with how it’s going, fingers crossed for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/25/self-control</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/25/self-control</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pomegranates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What on earth is the deal with pomegranates? They’re like
an alien’s brain or some shit. And they take so much time
for relatively little reward. Honestly a 4/10 fruit, must do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I needed to write a blog today and I’m going to the pub in 5 minutes, leave me alone.
)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/24/pomegranates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/24/pomegranates</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Russian Superfinals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in November I wrote about the &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/22/world-chess-championships&quot;&gt;World Chess Championships&lt;/a&gt; and mused that
people were overreacting to there being so many draws, and that clamouring for format and rule changes was largely unwarranted.
After the recent conclusion of the male and female editions of the Russian Superfinals, as well as with the ongoing Sinquefield Cup,
now I am much less convinced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter competition boasts some of the top players in the world, players who you would label as dynamic, aggressive, exciting
players.  The tournament has already taken a step towards avoiding draws, one
which the majority of top tier classical events have not, which is to not allow draws by agreement between the players, forcing
them to play on until a result is achieved by some other mechanism. Regardless, in the first five rounds, there have been 4 decisive games and 26 split points - two rounds were completely peaceful affairs, at least from the point of view of the scoreboard. As an
onlooker, what is the narrative here? Most players played about as expected. Very occasionally one player makes a natural, human mistake and loses. Yawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open edition of the Russian Superfinal was much the same. The calibre of the field is only slightly weaker than that of the Sinquefield Cup, which is hardly surprising given Russia’s historical chess pedigree. Across 11 rounds, there were 23 games with
a clear winner and 43 without, and it remained unclear until right at the end who the winner would be. For most of the tournament,
all of the players were within a point of each other, which in some ways is exciting, but again, what is the narrative here? I’m
not persuaded that it’s one of a nailbitingly close finish, especially when contrasted with the women’s event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, the players in said event were 200 points lower rated than their male counterparts, so one could argue the standard of chess is objectively lower. However, looking at the results table, it was a perfect reverse of the men’s event - with 43 decisive games and only 23 draws. This one did have a narrative: Girya flew out the gates, Kosteniuk and Gunina struggled, Goryachkina desperately trying to stay in the hunt for
the first half of the tournament. While Kosteniuk couldn’t catch a break, Gunina was resurgent, Pogonina suddenly emerged as frontrunner too, and when Goryachkina beat Girya in round 9, suddenly a miracle victory for her was possible. Girya
was no longer guaranteed to take the top prize, with Pogonina and Gunina also not yet out of contention. It all came down to
the final round, Girya took an early draw leaving a tiebreak a possibility, and Pogonina duly capitalised on it, before
succumbing to Girya in a final round Armageddon match anyway. Simply put: the storyline was much better. As a fan, you
could pick someone to root for (if you hadn’t guessed, I wanted Aleksandra Goryachkina to take the crown), and that added to the
enjoyment of watching the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draws in chess can still be wonderful, instructive, entertaining games, but perhaps the crux of it is how spectators engage
with tournament matches. If you are following the game live, absolutely a draw can be thrilling, and a very enjoyable experience -
if the game is interesting, the result is broadly irrelevant. However, when I go to check the results of tournament games I’ve not
been able to watch, I am much more inclined to go over the moves from a win than a draw - I know there’s guaranteed to be blood that
way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, until the best-in-the-world tournaments come up with a way to create a narrative, I’m going to skip watching the
Sinquefield Cup in favour of watching the top women’s events. The computer might not approve of the moves as much, but at
least they’ll put on a show.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/23/russian-superfinals</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/23/russian-superfinals</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GCSE Results</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is GCSE results day, and last night I was lucky enough to be able to help out with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mystudentevents.com/&quot;&gt;MyStudentEvents&lt;/a&gt; livestream for students who would be opening the dreaded envelope today. It gave me the opportunity
to relive a little of my own pre-results anticipation, but also to be able to survey the school examination landscape from a
distance further afar than I’d previously been able.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stream itself was an incredibly wholesome experience, and I was heartened to see how supportive people were of one another,
with numerous examples of kindness and empathy suggesting years far more advanced than 16. With that being said, the overwhelming
feeling I got from everybody participating was anxiety. Anybody getting their results today was clearly exceptionally nervous about
it, with many of them worrying about their parents’ expectations, and a huge amount of pressure was evident across the board. Now
I have some distance between myself and the events of results day, it feels difficult not to view the feeling that our exam system
generates as ridiculous - these people are 16, they are still children. Is it fair to make them feel like this at such a young age,
that they should all have to deal with so much so young?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, perhaps it is good practice for growing up, a character-building experience and one that is inevitable at some
point in life anyway. Either way, the academic chip on my shoulder feels more sore than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/22/gcse-results</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/22/gcse-results</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>rPi Plans</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I loathe the Internet of Things, raspberry pis are pretty neat, so I have dutifully ordered one of the new model 4s. I have some pretty exciting plans for it, including but not limited to;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting it up as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/&quot;&gt;pi-hole&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting up &lt;a href=&quot;https://openvpn.net/&quot;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configuring it to allow my PC to wake-on-LAN, so I can power on and then remote into that machine via the Pi over the internet;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running a cron to check the status of this website;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configuring a cron that can send automated tweets on my behalf and hopefully do something funky and interesting, very much inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iAOOdYsK7MM&quot;&gt;Hunter Scott’s DefCon talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll open source any of the code that I end up writing, and probably do a write up of any progress I make/challenges I face here. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/21/rpi-plans</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/21/rpi-plans</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Treasured Memories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I originally only wrote this as a daily post, but upon reflection I like it too much, and it is the spiritual successor to &lt;a href=&quot;/tartarus/2017/11/08/success&quot;&gt;Success&lt;/a&gt; which is probably my favourite post on the blog. As such, I felt it deserved a place here instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in the pub on Friday, I took it upon myself to try and stimulate some more interesting conversation amongst my male friends, instead of the usual soporific chat about work or cars or boats or some shit. In an effort to coax something vaguely resembling vulnerability out of them, I turned to my favourite source of disarming queries, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://36questionsinlove.com/&quot;&gt;36 questions for love&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to have a crack at number 18 - “what is your most treasured memory?” - but was met with no substantive answer from any of the parties present. I find it hard to believe that it’s possible for somebody to have &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; treasured memories, so decided that they were perhaps merely reluctant to be forthcoming about them, and maybe if I offered some experiences of my own, they might be more willing to reciprocate. So, here are 10 of my most treasured memories, in  vaguely chronological order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;skiing-in-wengenjungfrau-region-with-fleur&quot;&gt;Skiing in Wengen/Jungfrau Region with Fleur&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went skiing with my family every Christmas for 15 years or so in Wengen, Switzerland, and did most of it with the English speaking Downhill Only club, where I was lucky enough to meet Fleur. Both our families would spend the same weeks there for a few years, and so I got to know her pretty well, and I have some very fond memories of skiing and chatting with her. Her cynicism and dry wit, combined with painful intelligence, were all things I sought to emulate and I think she likely had a significant effect on how my personality developed as I grew up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-kiss-with-rozelle&quot;&gt;First kiss with Rozelle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has that one person they fall hopelessly in love with when they first go through puberty, and it’s all a bit of a mess. Rozelle was absolutely that person for me, I was as besotted as only a teenager can be, and I still remember the first time she kissed me, up against the sadly-now-removed swing set outside the Peninsula Hotel, at goodness knows what time in the morning. I’ve been chasing the butterflies I felt then ever since, having success on only a handful of rare occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beating-toby-at-chess-10th-march-2009&quot;&gt;Beating Toby at chess, 10th March 2009&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think of all the games of chess I have played in my life, this is fairly comfortably my favourite. At 14, playing in the top division of Guernsey’s chess league, beating Toby was the first time I’d beaten a titled player (admittedly he’s ‘only’ a candidate master, but that counts in my book). My chess trajectory was at its highest after that game, and I still remember the feeling of anticipation when I won a pawn, then a second, then liquidated into an endgame with such a big advantage I knew there was no way I was going to mess it up. I was shaking, it was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beating-fareed-and-ben-in-the-debating-cup&quot;&gt;Beating Fareed and Ben in the Debating Cup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My school-long rivalry with Fareed was pretty disgusting when I think about it, and something I am gently ashamed of, although I don’t think either of us could really be blamed for it. We were of course products of our environment, and that environment very much encouraged competition and egotism, so we went to war, determined to show our teachers and peers that we were the quickest thinking, most silver-tongued pretentious twats in the entire school. One of the greatest victories I ever scored against him was beating him in the semifinal of the senior debating cup, having lost to him the year before. Sadly I can’t remember what the motion was, but I do remember shouting ‘come on!’ in celebration when our names were announced winners, as a true testament to my lack of composure in that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seeing-foo-fighters-with-jack&quot;&gt;Seeing Foo Fighters with Jack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the last night of Reading Festival 2012, I was lucky enough to watch the Foo Fighters headline the main stage with Jack. A few beers in, totally exhausted but determined to enjoy the dying hours of our weekend, things suddenly became very emotional when the rest of the band momentarily took a backseat as Dave Grohl strummed an acoustic guitar while recounting stories of being in Nirvana and knowing Kurt Cobain. As someone moved by Cobain’s story, that night felt like something special, as if we were all part of something much bigger, all connected through Grohl’s reminiscence, and it’s stayed with me ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beating-york-including-higgs-at-roses&quot;&gt;Beating York (including Higgs) at Roses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I fenced for the uni, I was always the weakest member on the strongest team, which meant I felt a lot of pressure to perform. The sabreurs always had to carry the weaker foilists and epeeists if we were to have any chance of winning, and our annual varsity match against York, dubbed Roses after the war over 550 years prior, was no different. Lancaster won the toss and so got to decide the match order, and as usual the sabre match would be last, and would decide the outcome of the entire day. When it came down to us, we needed to beat the York sabreurs by 45 to 8 or more in order to win, with 45-9 being a draw. On home soil, with a Lancaster crowd cheering us on, I managed to fight through my nerves and helped the team win 45-6, the biggest margin of victory I’d ever been part of in a team match. For that night, we were heroes, and the party afterwards was electric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;driving-from-edinburgh-to-st-andrews-with-nick&quot;&gt;Driving from Edinburgh to St Andrews with Nick&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having not had much experience with driving anywhere other than Guernsey, on our second Poole-to-Scotland road trip I really fell in love with cruising through the countryside, very much so while navigating the B roads between Edinburgh and St Andrews in the snow. The Scottish scenery is unbelievably beautiful, there was nobody else on the roads, and we were strictly adhering to the speed limit. Probably. It was a wonderful experience with one of my best friends, and I won’t forget it in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meditating-at-cheesters-with-ted-and-mica&quot;&gt;Meditating at Cheesters with Ted and Mica&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While living in Mexico in 2017 with Ted and Mica, we all at various points were engaged in some form of meditation challenge with one another. As a trio we were all determined to do at least 30 minutes a day, and so when an evening downpour trapped us beneath an umbrella in Cheesters restaurant, we elected to simply meditate there and then, until the storm had passed. The feeling of closing one’s eyes and remaining completely still for 30 minutes in the middle of a public space was exhilarating, I could feel my cheeks burning bright red and my heart pounding. I had never been more aware of my place in relation to my surroundings, arguably the point of meditation. It was a unique experience which I would highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seeing-car-seat-headrest-with-fi&quot;&gt;Seeing Car Seat Headrest with Fi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the chance to see Car Seat Headrest live in Kentish Town on my birthday last year, with one of my oldest and dearest friends Fiona. CSH are a band that have meant a lot to me for several years, the music and lyrics of frontman Will Toledo are ones that I empathise strongly with, and have brought me a lot of comfort and hope during my time listening to them. To see Will and the boys in the flesh, with 1000 like-minded fans screaming all the words alongside me, alongside someone I love and care about deeply, was the perfect birthday present for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-brass-monkeysome-random-sports-bar-in-manhattanthe-subway-and-walk-back-to-astoria-with-polly&quot;&gt;The Brass Monkey/some random sports bar in Manhattan/the subway and walk back to Astoria with Polly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My trip to New York earlier this year was a life changing experience, and picking just one moment from it for this list was very difficult, as I treasure the entire duration of the trip. Our
last full day there was the pièce de résistance of our journey in my mind. Having spent 10 whole days together at this point, Polly and I had grown to know each other unusually well in such a short space of time, and already felt like best friends as we headed into Manhattan to sample more of its watering holes. The drinks flowed, radically honest conversations were had, we drunkenly held hands in the Brass Monkey, and she sung to me in the middle of the subway on the way home. It was the perfect end to the perfect trip.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//tartarus/2019/08/20/treasured-memories</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//tartarus/2019/08/20/treasured-memories</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Infest The Rats' Nest Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Friday, prolific genre-defying Aussie rockers released their 15th studio album, Infest The
Rats’ Nest, their take on a rather old school heavy metal sound mixed with a remarkably topical and contemporary message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KGATLW frequently have strong narratives running through their music and have produced a variety of concept albums, with this one being no difficult. The opening of the record describes humanity having made Earth uninhabitable, echoing the slogan popularised by Extinction Rebellion in the chorus of the opening track; “there is no Planet B”. The richest
in society are able to afford passage to a now-terraformed Mars, while those that remain on
Earth watch their world collapse on itself as society is ravaged by superbugs. A group of rebels attempt to journey to Venus, slingshotting themselves around the Sun in the process, but
the first ship gets too close and is incinerated. The second ship makes it to Venus before quickly realising that it is hellaciously hot and unbearable to live there, so make the choice
to make for Mars and invade - to infest the rats’ nest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presumably conscious decision not to adopt the modern heavy metal sound but rather make it more a homage actually works remarkably well. Despite going in a completely different direction to any of their other work, their are still plenty of unmistakably King Gizz riffs, as well as some of Ambrose’s signature harmonica playing. The story that is being told is
engrossing and compelling, and the dark and distorted music that it sits on top of complements
its dystopian tone. The album grew a lot on me after several playthroughs, and while I don’t
think it is going to be my favourite KGATLW album, it is very solid nonetheless: 8/10.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/20/infest-the-rats-nest-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/20/infest-the-rats-nest-review</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Changing The Dialogue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been struggling recently with the feeling that I am getting good at talking on the blog about how I want to make changes/make
a difference, but then taking no action in order to enact said change. Perhaps writing here does have some non-zero impact, but
either way it’s certainly not enough. It seems natural to start with something small and then work my way up to something bigger,
and over the weekend I realised what the first step should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retaining your school friends as an adult is a bit of a rollercoaster. On one hand, you spent a lot of time in the same environment,
on broadly similar paths, and have a lot of shared experiences together. On the other, as you get older, your paths diverge, your
interests and priorities change, you have more unique experiences. Your relationship is often still cast in the mould that it was
at school though - you still talk about the same things, in the same way. It becomes different to show your own growth in the context
of your relationship with them, you remain stuck in place, a snapshot of your former self, for fear of entering the unknown and
potentially losing a friendship that you’ve invested so much time and effort into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that last sentiment is simply the sunk cost fallacy in action - if my old friends don’t want to know the new me, then I
do not want to keep investing in them further. And so, at the risk of alienating my old school chums, things must change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means I must change - if anyone is going to catalyse an important change in the dialogue of the group then it may as well be me.
Some of the things we say are problematic, moreover some of the things &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; say when I’m with them are problematic, because I am
still playing the same character I was 10 years ago. It’s no longer acceptable to be desperate for validation, willing to say
anything wantonly offensive in order to get an easy laugh out of some teenagers. It’s no longer acceptable to bottle up my feelings
and perpetuate the notion that men must be stoic and unwavering at all times, when I am filled with sadness, anger, shame and fear on
a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be uncomfortable, but they are my friends, I love them and I want us all to be better, healthier people, and so here begins
my efforts to change our dialogues. Maybe if I can crack our rag-tag band, I can make progress with the world at large.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/19/changing-the-dialogue</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/08/19/changing-the-dialogue</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>