<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-12T19:19:53+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">30 Years of the Web</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/12/30-years-of-the-web" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="30 Years of the Web" /><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/12/30-years-of-the-web</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/12/30-years-of-the-web">&lt;p&gt;
  Today is the thirtieth birthday of the world wide web, the very technology behind
  how you are reading this right now. I've been surfing for roughly half that time,
  and over the years it has become an increasingly large part of my life, as it has
  for many other people. In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://webfoundation.org/2019/03/web-birthday-30/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  open letter,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strike&gt;Dr Frankenstein&lt;/strike&gt;
  Sir Tim Berners-Lee had some reservations about his creation and the path on
  which it was headed. His three main points are that the web now enables widespread,
  massive-scale criminality; corporate greed and exploitation; and previously untold
  access to polarising opinions which frequently amount to vitriol and hatespeech.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  He makes some good points. The internet is, at least in my mind, worse than it
  once was, to the extent tha it is no longer a slam-dunk net positive for humanity.
  I've spent a lot of time recently auditing my own use of both the web, and
  technology in general, to ensure that it is benifical in my life. The good news
  is that I am confident it is - but care must be taken to avoid slipping into
  bad habits which could change that, especially when millions of intelligent man-hours
  have gone into trapping me inside various walled gardens.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I do have some bad news for Timmy boy though. The reason he believed the web
  would be such a great thing is ultimately the same reason he takes issue today.
  The web is getting ever closer to living up to its world-wide moniker, and the
  more people there are regularly using the web, the more the web is shaped by
  the flaws of people. En masse state sponsored crime is hardly an idea unique to
  cyberspace, neither is corporate exploitation, neither is propagandha. So I'm
  afraid that all the open standards, goodwill and not-for-profit donations in the
  world (wide web) will not change the nature of the web now - only by restricting
  who can use it could we claw back what once was.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The internet reflects the other side of humanity too - the inherent good. It's
  not as obvious as the colossal piles of manure, but seek and ye shall find.
  People are still kind, funny, insightful, wondrous beings, and you can find
  those qualities aplenty in the right dark, secluded corners of the web.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This blog is absolutely not one such corner however.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Today is the thirtieth birthday of the world wide web, the very technology behind how you are reading this right now. I've been surfing for roughly half that time, and over the years it has become an increasingly large part of my life, as it has for many other people. In an open letter, Dr Frankenstein Sir Tim Berners-Lee had some reservations about his creation and the path on which it was headed. His three main points are that the web now enables widespread, massive-scale criminality; corporate greed and exploitation; and previously untold access to polarising opinions which frequently amount to vitriol and hatespeech. He makes some good points. The internet is, at least in my mind, worse than it once was, to the extent tha it is no longer a slam-dunk net positive for humanity. I've spent a lot of time recently auditing my own use of both the web, and technology in general, to ensure that it is benifical in my life. The good news is that I am confident it is - but care must be taken to avoid slipping into bad habits which could change that, especially when millions of intelligent man-hours have gone into trapping me inside various walled gardens. I do have some bad news for Timmy boy though. The reason he believed the web would be such a great thing is ultimately the same reason he takes issue today. The web is getting ever closer to living up to its world-wide moniker, and the more people there are regularly using the web, the more the web is shaped by the flaws of people. En masse state sponsored crime is hardly an idea unique to cyberspace, neither is corporate exploitation, neither is propagandha. So I'm afraid that all the open standards, goodwill and not-for-profit donations in the world (wide web) will not change the nature of the web now - only by restricting who can use it could we claw back what once was. The internet reflects the other side of humanity too - the inherent good. It's not as obvious as the colossal piles of manure, but seek and ye shall find. People are still kind, funny, insightful, wondrous beings, and you can find those qualities aplenty in the right dark, secluded corners of the web. This blog is absolutely not one such corner however.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Jesse Lacey Problem II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/11/the-jesse-lacey-problem-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Jesse Lacey Problem II" /><published>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/11/the-jesse-lacey-problem-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/11/the-jesse-lacey-problem-ii">&lt;p&gt;
  Nearly a year ago, I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;/tartarus/2018/04/15/the-jesse-lacey-problem&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  my decision to stop listening to the music of Jesse Lacey and his band Brand New,&lt;/a&gt;
  as a result of the accusations of sexual misconduct against him and his seeming
  admission-by-omission. In retrospect, writing that piece is probably aggressively
  virtue signalling, so to balance it out I will don my apologist's cap today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I've been pondering forgiveness a lot recently. Do I believe that any human
  being is truly evil? I don't think so. Admittedly this is according to Vice,
  but allegedly &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vice.com/en_us/article/vbwzny/inside-el-chapos-jury-a-juror-speaks-for-first-time-about-convicting-the-kingpin&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  even in El Chapo's trial, the jurors took pity on him, seeing him as product
  of his environment and not an inherently malign individual.&lt;/a&gt; I suspect
  they are probably right, and so it is tempting to forgive him - but intuitively
  it seems that we must draw the line somewhere. Some actions, even if misguided,
  must be deemed irredeemable in order to ensure our society can approximate functioning.
  But where should that line be?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's not for me to say - I am now ethics buff. The books are all on my to-read list,
  none on the read. But forgiveness seems important. I was reluctant to fall prey
  to my own biases in forgiving Lacey, when I would not have forgiven someone in
  an appreciably similar position who I had not felt a previous affinity towards.
  In the end, I feel like I can justify my decision - forgiveness is, as I said,
  important, and some forgiveness is better than none. Sometimes good people do
  bad things, and everybody makes mistakes - I could fill a novel with the things
  I have done of which I am not proud, do I really consider myself above Lacey,
  even if I have not done what he has?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The counterargument here is that I am invalidating, or perhaps selectively ignoring
  the experience of the victims. If left unchecked (or indeed supported by a large
  fanbase), perhaps someone who has hurt another could continue to hurt yet more
  innocent people. Perhaps therein lies where I draw the line - I will forgive
  anyone who I believe is repentant, and would not cause harm in the same way again.
  And I believe that that is the way Lacey feels.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Today, I listened through Brand New's entire discography for the first time in a year. It was spine-chilling,
  glorious, euphoric. Welcome back, Jesse.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Ethics" /><category term="Social Issues" /><summary type="html">Nearly a year ago, I wrote about my decision to stop listening to the music of Jesse Lacey and his band Brand New, as a result of the accusations of sexual misconduct against him and his seeming admission-by-omission. In retrospect, writing that piece is probably aggressively virtue signalling, so to balance it out I will don my apologist's cap today. I've been pondering forgiveness a lot recently. Do I believe that any human being is truly evil? I don't think so. Admittedly this is according to Vice, but allegedly even in El Chapo's trial, the jurors took pity on him, seeing him as product of his environment and not an inherently malign individual. I suspect they are probably right, and so it is tempting to forgive him - but intuitively it seems that we must draw the line somewhere. Some actions, even if misguided, must be deemed irredeemable in order to ensure our society can approximate functioning. But where should that line be? It's not for me to say - I am now ethics buff. The books are all on my to-read list, none on the read. But forgiveness seems important. I was reluctant to fall prey to my own biases in forgiving Lacey, when I would not have forgiven someone in an appreciably similar position who I had not felt a previous affinity towards. In the end, I feel like I can justify my decision - forgiveness is, as I said, important, and some forgiveness is better than none. Sometimes good people do bad things, and everybody makes mistakes - I could fill a novel with the things I have done of which I am not proud, do I really consider myself above Lacey, even if I have not done what he has? The counterargument here is that I am invalidating, or perhaps selectively ignoring the experience of the victims. If left unchecked (or indeed supported by a large fanbase), perhaps someone who has hurt another could continue to hurt yet more innocent people. Perhaps therein lies where I draw the line - I will forgive anyone who I believe is repentant, and would not cause harm in the same way again. And I believe that that is the way Lacey feels. Today, I listened through Brand New's entire discography for the first time in a year. It was spine-chilling, glorious, euphoric. Welcome back, Jesse.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self Love</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/10/self-love" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self Love" /><published>2019-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/10/self-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/10/self-love">&lt;p&gt;
  I struggle to love myself. By which I mean that I don't love myself - the struggles
  involved had yet to bear any fruit. But I really want to change that, because
  my low self esteem seems to be the root cause of almost all of my unhappiness,
  and following several conversations and a lot of ruminating on the topic, I
  think I need to start carving out time in my day, every day, to devote to
  learning how to love myself. I really feel like I am starting from the beginning,
  but at least I am finally starting.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I struggle to love myself. By which I mean that I don't love myself - the struggles involved had yet to bear any fruit. But I really want to change that, because my low self esteem seems to be the root cause of almost all of my unhappiness, and following several conversations and a lot of ruminating on the topic, I think I need to start carving out time in my day, every day, to devote to learning how to love myself. I really feel like I am starting from the beginning, but at least I am finally starting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moving on from the bonsai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/09/moving-on-from-the-bonsai" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving on from the bonsai" /><published>2019-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/09/moving-on-from-the-bonsai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/09/moving-on-from-the-bonsai">&lt;p&gt;
  So, at this point, the bonsai tree I bought is pretty dead, which speaks volumes
  about me. I am kinda sad that I couldn't nurture it, but the stakes were still
  fairly low - after all, it was only a $20 tree after all, not a child or something.
  In these situations, people have been advising me for years to try to draw
  some kind of positive from the experience, to reflect on what I have learned
  so that I do not kill any more tiny trees in the future. So, here are some of
  the things I learned during the miniature murder which I committed:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Do your research before you buy.&lt;/strong&gt; Don't let your ego get ahead
    of you, and assume you'll be able to figure it out, or just wing something
    that you've never done before. Do some research on what's involved with
    bonsai care, the best type of tree to buy, what your tree will need from you etc.
    And then go buy a tree, after you've done all that, you idiot.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/1h1eCU7.png&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Always fully commit.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Once you've realised your own lack of
    knowledge and admitted to yourself that actually, this is going to be a significant
    amount of work, own it. Don't pussyfoot around, now you have made a mistake,
    embrace it and throw yourself into putting it right.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Bonsais are needy motherfuckers.&lt;/strong&gt; Seriously - I didn't water it
    enough and it started dying, and then I watered it too much and it continued
    dying. Make up your goddamn mind.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have had to awkwardly hide the remains of the tree in my room before people
  visit the flat this evening as I am too ashamed of my own failure in my duty
  of care over the plant. RIP.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">So, at this point, the bonsai tree I bought is pretty dead, which speaks volumes about me. I am kinda sad that I couldn't nurture it, but the stakes were still fairly low - after all, it was only a $20 tree after all, not a child or something. In these situations, people have been advising me for years to try to draw some kind of positive from the experience, to reflect on what I have learned so that I do not kill any more tiny trees in the future. So, here are some of the things I learned during the miniature murder which I committed: Do your research before you buy. Don't let your ego get ahead of you, and assume you'll be able to figure it out, or just wing something that you've never done before. Do some research on what's involved with bonsai care, the best type of tree to buy, what your tree will need from you etc. And then go buy a tree, after you've done all that, you idiot. Always fully commit. Once you've realised your own lack of knowledge and admitted to yourself that actually, this is going to be a significant amount of work, own it. Don't pussyfoot around, now you have made a mistake, embrace it and throw yourself into putting it right. Bonsais are needy motherfuckers. Seriously - I didn't water it enough and it started dying, and then I watered it too much and it continued dying. Make up your goddamn mind. I have had to awkwardly hide the remains of the tree in my room before people visit the flat this evening as I am too ashamed of my own failure in my duty of care over the plant. RIP.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Python Koans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/08/python-koans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Python Koans" /><published>2019-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/08/python-koans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/08/python-koans">&lt;p&gt;
  Continuing on my journey to learn Python, this weekend I am going to try to
  smash through as many of these wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gregmalcolm/python_koans&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Python Koans&lt;/a&gt; as possible. I'll report back on Sunday evening with whether
  or not I gained any deep insight into either Python or the nature of human
  consciousness.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Software Engineering" /><category term="Python" /><summary type="html">Continuing on my journey to learn Python, this weekend I am going to try to smash through as many of these wonderful Python Koans as possible. I'll report back on Sunday evening with whether or not I gained any deep insight into either Python or the nature of human consciousness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trapped</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/07/trapped" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trapped" /><published>2019-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/07/trapped</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/07/trapped">&lt;p&gt;
  One of the strangest and most distressing characteristics of modern Western society
  (and likely other societies that I am not so familiar with) is its ability to
  ensure its participants feel psychologically trapped by some cycle therein.
  It could be a relationsip, a job or career path, a sexuality, a gender identity,
  or any one of the innumerable other norms which we feel overwhelming pressured
  into conforming towards.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I certainly feel trapped by these things. I had a clear path laid out by my
  environment from birth, and the rigidity of it has been slowly suffocating me
  ever since. Upon reflection, my feeling of entrapment seems obvious in my past
  writings, even if it wasn't explicitly acknowledged. Last month alone I mused
  about &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/02/16/what-we-want&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;setting out to
  get what I want, &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/02/19/the-grass-is-greener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  my contempt for using 'the grass is greener' as a means of oppressing hope&lt;/a&gt;
  and &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/02/21/re-an-honest-living&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;whether
  a change in collar would make me happier.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have struggled with identity for years - I take no pride in my background, I
  am scared of becoming like many of the people around me, I do not feel like I fit
  in, in a hopelessly self-aggrandizing, why-can't-you-see-everyone-feels-like-that-you-dick
  kind of way. I feel trapped inside the path that's set out for me, and one of
  my biggest fears is that I will die within its confines.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I've also spent some time contemplating and talking with friends about 'the goal'.
  You know, the biggie. The one that goes on your tombstone. I've felt particularly
  unsatisfied with my lack of answer to that existential question, but perhaps
  this is perfect - the dream is to feel truly free. To break out of any sense
  of obligation to those around me, to do what I want, to express myself honestly,
  to no longer be constrained to work 50 hour weeks behind a desk and live the 2.4
  kids lifestyle.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Relationships" /><category term="Career" /><summary type="html">One of the strangest and most distressing characteristics of modern Western society (and likely other societies that I am not so familiar with) is its ability to ensure its participants feel psychologically trapped by some cycle therein. It could be a relationsip, a job or career path, a sexuality, a gender identity, or any one of the innumerable other norms which we feel overwhelming pressured into conforming towards. I certainly feel trapped by these things. I had a clear path laid out by my environment from birth, and the rigidity of it has been slowly suffocating me ever since. Upon reflection, my feeling of entrapment seems obvious in my past writings, even if it wasn't explicitly acknowledged. Last month alone I mused about setting out to get what I want, my contempt for using 'the grass is greener' as a means of oppressing hope and whether a change in collar would make me happier. I have struggled with identity for years - I take no pride in my background, I am scared of becoming like many of the people around me, I do not feel like I fit in, in a hopelessly self-aggrandizing, why-can't-you-see-everyone-feels-like-that-you-dick kind of way. I feel trapped inside the path that's set out for me, and one of my biggest fears is that I will die within its confines. I've also spent some time contemplating and talking with friends about 'the goal'. You know, the biggie. The one that goes on your tombstone. I've felt particularly unsatisfied with my lack of answer to that existential question, but perhaps this is perfect - the dream is to feel truly free. To break out of any sense of obligation to those around me, to do what I want, to express myself honestly, to no longer be constrained to work 50 hour weeks behind a desk and live the 2.4 kids lifestyle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Knockoff Proleague</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/06/knockoff-proleague" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Knockoff Proleague" /><published>2019-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/06/knockoff-proleague</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/06/knockoff-proleague">&lt;p&gt;
  Proleague is back! Well, kind of. Naturally I wish it was still an offline event
  in Seoul, but the new Chinese team league is exciting nonetheless, and even
  if the quality won't be quite as high as Proleague at its peak, there are still
  plenty of players I am excited to watch, and the format is solid.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I will of course be rooting for Scarlett and her team, Newbee, but Jin Air Greenwings
  are definitely, definitely going to win. I have spent the past couple of years
  pining for a top level team league to grace my mornings, so I am very excited
  that one has finally returned!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="esports" /><summary type="html">Proleague is back! Well, kind of. Naturally I wish it was still an offline event in Seoul, but the new Chinese team league is exciting nonetheless, and even if the quality won't be quite as high as Proleague at its peak, there are still plenty of players I am excited to watch, and the format is solid. I will of course be rooting for Scarlett and her team, Newbee, but Jin Air Greenwings are definitely, definitely going to win. I have spent the past couple of years pining for a top level team league to grace my mornings, so I am very excited that one has finally returned!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chess is about disagreeing with people</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/05/chess-is-about-disagreeing-with-people" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chess is about disagreeing with people" /><published>2019-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/05/chess-is-about-disagreeing-with-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/05/chess-is-about-disagreeing-with-people">&lt;p&gt;
  One of the things that my old chess coach said to me that really stuck was that
  'chess is about disagreeing with people'. When your opponent plays a move, they
  are essentially saying to you 'this move is the best one' - and in order to win,
  you must disagree with them. They might say 'I see your threat - but I can defend
  like this and it will be nullified' or 'my attack will kill you' or 'my subtle
  reorganisation of my pieces will allow me to put a stranglehold on this game' and
  at every juncture, you must be seeking for the opportunity to disagree with them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think that a lot of good can come from disagreeing with people in life as well.
  Not purely for the sake of it, because that would make you an insufferable douche,
  but to challenge complacency. By disagreeing with someone, you give both parties
  an opportunity for new learnings, an understanding of different perspectives and
  broadened horizons. Disagreements can provide opportunity to re-evaluate
  a long outdated status quo, or simply to strengthen your confidence in your
  existing beliefs and opinions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One of the many things I dislike about myself is how reticent I am to disagree
  with people, and while part of that is due to my social bubble, it's something
  I'd like to work on.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Chess" /><summary type="html">One of the things that my old chess coach said to me that really stuck was that 'chess is about disagreeing with people'. When your opponent plays a move, they are essentially saying to you 'this move is the best one' - and in order to win, you must disagree with them. They might say 'I see your threat - but I can defend like this and it will be nullified' or 'my attack will kill you' or 'my subtle reorganisation of my pieces will allow me to put a stranglehold on this game' and at every juncture, you must be seeking for the opportunity to disagree with them. I think that a lot of good can come from disagreeing with people in life as well. Not purely for the sake of it, because that would make you an insufferable douche, but to challenge complacency. By disagreeing with someone, you give both parties an opportunity for new learnings, an understanding of different perspectives and broadened horizons. Disagreements can provide opportunity to re-evaluate a long outdated status quo, or simply to strengthen your confidence in your existing beliefs and opinions. One of the many things I dislike about myself is how reticent I am to disagree with people, and while part of that is due to my social bubble, it's something I'd like to work on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Industry Gurus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/04/industry-gurus" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Industry Gurus" /><published>2019-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/04/industry-gurus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/04/industry-gurus">&lt;p&gt;
  As part of a marketing thingy at work, our whole team got asked for some examples
  of people we look up to in the indsutry/regard as 'gurus' in their chosen field.
  I think a lot of the ones on my list were somewhat obvious and unoriginal choices,
  but here they are regardless:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brendan Eich&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yan Zhu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jen Simmons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Troy Hunt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addy Osmani&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vitalik Buterin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brian Kernighan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dennis Ritchie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Did I miss anyone obvious?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">As part of a marketing thingy at work, our whole team got asked for some examples of people we look up to in the indsutry/regard as 'gurus' in their chosen field. I think a lot of the ones on my list were somewhat obvious and unoriginal choices, but here they are regardless: Brendan Eich Yan Zhu Linus Torvalds Jen Simmons Troy Hunt Addy Osmani Vitalik Buterin Brian Kernighan Dennis Ritchie Did I miss anyone obvious?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">soO</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/03/soo" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="soO" /><published>2019-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/03/soo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/03/soo">&lt;p&gt;
  Today was the final day of the IEM Katowice Starcraft tournament, and it was
  an emotional one at that - soO, after coming 2nd in six GSL finals and a Blizzcon,
  finally overcame himself and emerged victorious by winning the IEM World Championship,
  After demonstrating that he was his own greatest opponent so many times, he proved
  himself a true champion by beating back his own mental demons and achieving his
  dream.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In the interview, not only was he crying (a rare thing for the Korean pros), but
  the translator was moved to tears as well. I may have joined her.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="esports" /><summary type="html">Today was the final day of the IEM Katowice Starcraft tournament, and it was an emotional one at that - soO, after coming 2nd in six GSL finals and a Blizzcon, finally overcame himself and emerged victorious by winning the IEM World Championship, After demonstrating that he was his own greatest opponent so many times, he proved himself a true champion by beating back his own mental demons and achieving his dream. In the interview, not only was he crying (a rare thing for the Korean pros), but the translator was moved to tears as well. I may have joined her.</summary></entry></feed>