<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts Before Working From Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is not the first day I have ever worked from home, however it marks the start of the first extended stretch
of working from home (at least that I have had while working in software). I thought it’d be interesting to write
down some of my expectations and plans on how to stay sane in the upcoming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I’ve tidied up my desk, which previously was a huge mess. Admittedly all that really means is that I’ve
relocated the mess elsewhere in my apartment, but at least my working area is now clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I plan on having work clothes and not-work clothes - essentially the former are jeans and the latter anything
but jeans. I hate jeans. But I think wearing them will be a nice way of mentally separating between the two modes of
existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, routine and exercise I think are going to be crucial. I’m going to try and keep up running as much as possible,
as well as do some kind of at-home workout, even if it’s only a couple of sets of push-ups each day. Having my productive
hours as 9-5 like usual and trying to have some kind of pre-work and post-work ritual are all parts of the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth, a common piece of advice seems to be to overcommunicate with your team - tell them when you’re at your desk working
first thing in the morning, when you’re taking a break, what the best way is to contact you, what you’re working on today,
etc etc. That seems like quite a lot but I’ll do my best; I’m sure I can easily tone it down if it’s too much. I’m also
obviously going to try to be as social as possible, as I’m sure we all are, to try and stave off loneliness in our
seclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m both excited and apprehensive about quarantine; on one hand, I think I could potentially be very productive from
home given the lack of people to distract me, as well as the extra flexibility I’ll have. I’ll be able to cook hot
lunches for myself, or go for a run on my lunchbreak and have a shower on my return, options I wouldn’t have at the
office, and my hours can also be more flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flip side will of course be lack of human interaction and how that’ll affect me. I don’t think there’s any point
dwelling on it though, as it’s not llike I have a choice; I’ll just have to do my best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/22/thoughts-before-working-from-home</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/22/thoughts-before-working-from-home</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stubborness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I really don’t want to write a blog post today. But I am stubborn, and as much as I don’t want to write
anything, I want Ted to win my money even less. We’ll see how long this stubbornness persists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/21/stubborness</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/21/stubborness</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pretending</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty jarring to see someone else exhibit some kind of negative behaviour that you know you
yourself are prone to, and last night I had that experience in spades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This person was pretending that everything that everything was fine and well and healthy and happy, and to their credit (or perhaps
not) they were doing an excellent job. But they were betrayed by multiple things around them, and I suspect they knew it, but still
the act continued. I wonder how much they thought they were putting on a show for other people, when it was pretty clear they were
pretending for their own sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was strange to see it so strongly in someone else. Usually in these situations I gain some amount of clarity on my own patterns
and feel the urge to break them, but in this case it was a little different. I felt a lot of empathy for the other person, and a
kind of sadness that the world works in such a way that they feel like they have to act like that. Part of me would love to end by
saying that I’d love to pretend less, and that I’d love for the world to pretend less, but I think that’s a pretty futile hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/20/pretending</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/20/pretending</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Calm Soul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day one of my friends described me as “a calm soul”, and it was an odd moment for me, because it didn’t ring true at all, especially coming from someone who is usually
unpleasantly perceptive. I know I try my damnedest to remain externally calm at all times, but inside it’s pretty non-stop tumult (is that a self-absorbed tihng to say?). I
don’t know if I want to be a calm soul either; calm is &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt;. Anger is righteous, eat the rich, burn the man etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/19/a-calm-soul</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/19/a-calm-soul</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guns Akimbo Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After presumably having made more money than one human being could ever spend in a lifetime, Daniel Radcliffe seems to have
decided that he is only going to do ridiculous, goofy, &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; movies that are entertaining to him, and frankly, I think
that’s great. &lt;em&gt;Guns Akimbo&lt;/em&gt; certainly satisfies all three of those adjectives. The writing is bad, and whenever it
appears to err into self-awareness, it course-corrects back to obliviousness near instantaneously. I’m almost certain
it employs the exact plot to at least seven other movies. To its credit, some of the VFX and sound is pretty good, and
Radcliffe’s performance just about makes it hang together. Oh, and it has Rhys Darby in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you love bad movies, and even moreso bad movies with Daniel Radcliffe in (a niche that is rapidly growing) then you’ll
love Guns Akimbo. Objectively; 3/10. Subjectively; 7/10&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/18/guns-akimbo-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/18/guns-akimbo-review</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Candidates Controversy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the FIDE Candidates Tournament plays its first round, situated in Yekaterinburg, Russia. It has already been a… tumultuous event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teimour Radjabov has pulled out, allowing Maxime Vachier-Lagrave to join the tournament after his much-discussed previous failure to qualify or gain the wildcard. Vladimir Kramnik -
one of the greatest players of all time - has withdrawn from commentary duty and publically criticised FIDE for allowing the tournament to continue in the current climate. FIDE
waved away Radjabov’s concerns while showing him little to no respect, but it is unclear what they will say in response to Kramnik - this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nigelshortchess/status/1235981114466095105&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;terrible tweet&lt;/a&gt; currently sums up FIDE’s attitude and also removed any and all positive sentiment that I may have held towards
him. Russia has ordered a blanket ban on all sporting events for the foreseeable future, but FIDE have decided that they aren’t bound by that due to not being a sport in the
technical sense. Wang is playing with no seconds, as they would all be coming from China and have to undergo mandatory 14 day quarantine (although this hasn’t stopped him
beating Ding with black in round 1). A video of Nepomniatchi refusing to shake hands with both Karpov and Giri is already going round the internet - which also seemed to be a
wise move, given that he went on to beat the latter, again with black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most egregious of all, the opening ceremony to the event went ahead, with more than &lt;em&gt;1000&lt;/em&gt; people present - with FIDE’s justification being that the players themselves were not
present, and only gatherings with greater than 5000 people had been banned nation-wide, despite that number being just 50 in Moscow. While players are free to withdraw, as
Radjabov has done, this is the pinnacle of all their chess careers - the penultimate step to becoming world champion - how can any of them reasonably turn it down? Nepo is
clearly unhappy and I suspect many of the other players are too, but they will not speak out against FIDE lest it jeopardise their own career. Being made to play under such
circumstances is deplorable, and I suspect further criticism will only be levied at FIDE as the tournament continues to unfold. Their attitude, with Arkady Dvorkovich now at the
helm, suggests that world chess is just as entwined with Russian political interests as it always has been, but this time the powers that be at FIDE seem to have even less shame
in displaying that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/17/candidates-controversy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/17/candidates-controversy</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intermittent Fasting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I mused for the millionth time upon what changes I was going to make to my diet in order to achieve the desired result, without falling pray to the notion that if I simply
repeat previous efforts, something will magically be different this time. Perhaps it seems a little foolish but I think it is important to keep trying, and furthermore to keep
trying different things, and eventually something will stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that I think I have a pretty good strategy this time, which is to take something that already works and apply it in a broader context - in this case
intermittent fasting. Having integrated the 16:8 into my lfiestyle fairly comfortable over the past couple of years, I think making the switch to OMAD 5x/week is going to
be both a logical transition and one that is best placed to combat the emotional/addictive behaviours I have around food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this with about an hour to go until dinnertime on day 1, and so far it’s felt like relatively smooth sailing - let’s see how long that lasts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/16/intermittent-fasting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/16/intermittent-fasting</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Underneath Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday Code Orange’s new record ‘Underneath’ dropped, their third under their present moniker and the followup to
their 2017 critically-acclaimed ‘Forever’. The band’s hardcore punk roots have gradually bled into heavier and heavier
territory, and &lt;em&gt;Underneath&lt;/em&gt; is fairly undeniably a metalcore record. The new album makes greater use of Reba Myers’
impressive clean vocals while still showcasing that Jami Morgan has put a lot of work into his own growls. The blend
their eclectic influences with their signature sound and a healthy dose of experimentation leaving an album that both
sounds unique and takes a lot of risks - which all pay off in spades. The record is a triumph, a successful evolution
of the bands’ sound which forges into new artistic ground without alienating their own fans, a feat that few musicians
seem to achieve these days (it reminds me a lot of how I feel like Slipknot’s post &lt;em&gt;All Hope Is Gone&lt;/em&gt; discography should
sound).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already a very serious contender for album of the year, well worth a listen if you like distorted guitars, double kick
bass drums and screaming. 8.5/10.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/15/underneath-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/15/underneath-review</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Folding at Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve deliberately refrained from writing about &lt;em&gt;la grippe du jour&lt;/em&gt; because it feels
like it’s all anyone else is writing about and I am forever a contrarian, however
today’s post is at least somewhat related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that SETI@home has gone into ‘hibernation’ while Berkeley scientists focus on
analysing their existing dataset, which admittedly must be pretty huge by now, and
given cryptos recent swan dive back to pre-2017 prices, there’s huge swathes of GPUs
simply idling across the globe, when they could all be doing their tiny little part
to better society. One pretty neat way to do so is to join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://foldingathome.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Folding@home&lt;/a&gt; party and put your spare processor cycles to
work by simulating protein folding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DeepMind recently brought &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/article/AlphaFold-Using-AI-for-scientific-discovery&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;protein folding to the attention of the wider tech community&lt;/a&gt; and while I won’t
pretend to understand any of the biochemistry involve, the computing aspect is pretty
interesting, and it’s an application of modern technology that is refreshing not-evil.
Sure, I might not have quite the hardware that Google are hooking DeepMind up with
to achieve such stellar results, but the idea that the handful of proteins I can
compute on my lowly GTX 970 might contribute to research into the &lt;em&gt;C-Word&lt;/em&gt; warms
my soul a little.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/14/folding-at-home</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/14/folding-at-home</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hand Anger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I was enjoying the recent uptick in player liquidity on Run It Once and was happily clicking buttons when a particular hand made me really &lt;em&gt;angry&lt;/em&gt;. The nice thing about
being a fun player is that now I can simply stop playing, take a step back and evaluate why exactly this hand irked me so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hand went as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Folds to hero in CO with AhKhQc8d, raises to 3.5bb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BTN calls, blinds fold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flop Ks8s2x hero bets 4.5bb, villain calls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;turn Ks8s2xAs pot 16.5bb, hero checks, villain bets 11bb, hero calls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;river Ks8s2xAs2x pot 38.5bb hero pots, villain calls and tables…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T663sssx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction is to inwardly chastise villain for making such a bad play - I think preflop is definitely -EV and every other street is at best breakeven. Why am I so angry?
It’s a sense of entitlement, one of the ways ego manifests itself in poker, because he made a ‘bad’ play, he doesn’t deserve to win my money. But maybe he had a sick read on me,
he felt he could outplay me in position despite having mediocre holdings, perhaps my large lead OTR was actually a lot more exploitable than I had thought. It’s also a spot
where in reality I think I am making a lot of EV, just in this case I happened to lose actual money. Even after a couple of million hands of poker, those spots still hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much my poker mental game is influenced by my mental health off the felt. If I needed less external validation, the kind I might get from winning money at poker and
thus proving some kind of intellectual superiority, I can’t help but feel that these spots wouldn’t tilt me so much. The obvious &lt;em&gt;sequitur&lt;/em&gt; is that I should work on my IRL
mental game and then things will fall into place at the tables, but perhaps the reverse might also be true?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/13/hand-anger</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/13/hand-anger</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>