<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>I also won and I will also win again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine thinking that you’d be able to win a last longer bet about blogs when it takes you &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sted9000/sted9000.github.io/compare/558dbf8b7a...5b23b63e58&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;six commits to even successfully publish one blog post…&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sted9000/sted9000.github.io/commits/2271c53548d9dac93a50754c1af64c4a0aa56507/_includes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Or six months to correctly spell your own name.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite thing about poker was always hurting other people’s egos, the money was just a convenient corollary. Everyone knows
you can’t just crush the fish or they’ll never play the game again, every so often you’ve got to lose a pot just to keep them on the
hook…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck buddy &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/11/i-also-won-and-i-will-also-win-again</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/11/i-also-won-and-i-will-also-win-again</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poker Hand Stories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After talking to Ongun and Marisa this week, and describing an emotion wholly unrelated to poker through the analogy of a poker hand
(much to Marisa’s dismay), I realised quite how powerful the emotions that poker hands carry with them. So much so that I find it
easier to convey almost any feeling to another player simply by conjuring up a hand in which I would feel such a feeling as I am
trying to describe, and knowing that they understand me better that way than they would should I try to express myself any other
way. It’s quite funny to think about, and makes me feel happy and special to be able to share this esoteric connection with only
a handful of people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/10/poker-hand-stories</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/10/poker-hand-stories</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things That Are More Therapeutic Than Therapy&amp;#58; Running</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During my very extensive experiences with things that aren’t more therapy, and my not-quite-as-extensive-but-still-very-respectable degree of experiences with things that &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;
therapy, and in said experiences I have found several examples of the former to be far more effective at achieving the latter’s stated aim than the lattter itself. One such
activity has been running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has taken about 6 weeks for me to get over the Christmas-induced motivation-slump-and-caloric-intake-megaspike, but I think I am finally there. Today was the first time this
year that I had gone for a training run without headphones - all I left the house with were my keys. By removing this most comfortable of distractions I had no choice but to
entertain the din of thoughts circling my consciousness, with only the beauty of the Talbot Valley and a gentle pain in my calves to draw my attention elsewhere. As I have
slowly cajoled myself into running regularly, I have found that my emotional state throughout is always a rollercoaster, though often a predictable one. Whatever unaddressed
anxieties might be swirling round in my brain duly make themselves towards its forefront, leaving in their wake a dinstinctly unpleasant taste in the mouth of my consciousness,
and much of my run is spent confronting and wrestling with whatever may have been bothering me, subconsciously or otherwise, rather than battling my legs and the pavement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s painful, but bizarrely some clarity always seems to be found in the last kilometre or so - I suspect the endorphins and knowledge that the end is nigh lend themsevles to
cultivating inner peace rather nicely. At the expense of sounding unnecessarily preachy, I’m sure spending the time outside, away from technology also helps a great deal. I
have certainly noticed that I frequently accomplish a much more meaningful reduction of mental entropy in an hour of running than I do in an hour of therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/09/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-running</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/09/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-running</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pride</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been an odd day, cacophanous with feelings. But above all, possibly for one of the first times ever, I am genuinely proud of myself. Maybe not under the most glowing of
circumstances, but progress has been clearly made today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/08/pride</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/08/pride</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Prisoner's Dilemma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a cynical take, but the more I think about it, the more I think life is essentially the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prisoner%27s_dilemma&quot;&gt;prisoner’s dilemma&lt;/a&gt;, but on a grand, recurring scale. In the purest prisoner’s dilemma, the optimal strategy is to
always defect, and the best possible outcome is when the protagonist defects and the antagonist cooperates. In applied situations,
one player can of course attempt to exert their influence on the other player to cooperate in order to increase their EV, as
demonstrated here wonderfully by none other than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6GhbT-zEfc&quot;&gt;Liv Boeree&lt;/a&gt; (on another note - the
comments on that video are hilarious/incredibly depressing depending on how you look at it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really, I think that is all life boils down to. Our systems are so broken and riddled with misaligned incentives, and why is
that? It’s because people are trying to persuade us to cooperate, so they might defect and exploit others for their own gain. It’s
inevitable in a capitalist society, where the stated aim is to maximise your own expected value (as seen through the lens of wealth), that
eventually people will work out optimal strategies for this game and exact them upon the rest of us. The lengths to which they go
to persuade us to cooperate is remarkable, and somewhat grim - it happens in every possible aspect of life. Even in schools, at a
young age, we espouse to children the values of being kind, generous and, uhh, cooperative - leaving them vulnerable to be exploited
by those who have no moral qualms about taking the defector’s path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it seems the correct strategy is to ignore those that would coerce you into cooperation and defect instead. I’ll let you know
how it goes (although if it goes well, I’ll preach that it went horribly in order to raise my own EV further).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/07/the-prisoners-dilemma</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/07/the-prisoners-dilemma</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Publishing blogs is hard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this post should be entitled “leaving a job half done”. I have good very good at &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt; a blog post every day, however it seems I am struggling to successfully
publish them, despite having a python script that theoretically handles the whole thing for me. The problem is of course that I have done half a job writing it, and that it
sort of does what I want, but the test is half written, and it has been left in a “good enough” state that frankly isn’t good enough, and it has already cost me 1 ETH, coming
dangerously close to costing me a second today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that I am going to spend my weekend writing it properly, and making sure I have a proper pipeline and alerting system too. Sorry Ted 😄.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/06/publishing-blogs-is-hard</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/06/publishing-blogs-is-hard</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lack of Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I’ve not found enough time to be able to write properly about what has on my mind today, which I am a little frustrated with myself about. With that being said, here
is what is hopefully to come in the following week on the blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Life, broken systems and the prisoner’s dilemma;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poker;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean Language;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kobe/Jacob;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saving people and saving oneself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have to dash to a social event which I organised, which includes an insane 14 person dinner reservation - almost certainly this is the biggest event that I have birthed
and coordinated myself. Don’t these people have better things to do with their time?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/05/lack-of-time</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/05/lack-of-time</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Man Club</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Firstly I lost the bet - oops. Fortunately Ted is a degenerate and instantly accepted to run it twice, and so now I am going to
Martingale the fuck out of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended the local men’s support group, descriptively titled “Man Club”, for the first time. In a social clime where
historical masculine archetypes have been labelled as toxic and deemd to be unbefitting modern men, we have been left bereft of
gender identity, with naught but a void in our psyche where stoicism once was - which is a little ironic when you think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I am over-egging it, of course being a man is still, in many ways, fine and great. But still, I think myself and a lot
of other men are quite disillusioned with their own gender roles and places within our social structure. The idea of men’s groups
is becoming more acceptable and appealing, and a men’s movement is gaining traction and legitimacy in our collective consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience reminded me both of the GTO club and of group therapy, two things where I felt deeply connected and accepted by a
group, and two threads of treasured memories. It was incredibly raw and vulnerable, in a way in which men aren’t in our day-to-day
lives, and of course that is one of its stated aims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s intense, but I’m hopeful about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/04/man-club</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/04/man-club</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Polyphia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I booked tickets and flights to Birmingham to go see arguably the hottest prog metal band out there right now, Polyphia. I’ve also managed to schedule in a home game,
an ale festival, and potentially another tattoo appointment into just 3 days, and now I am incredibly excited!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending money on these kinds of experiences has slowly become more and more of a no-brainer to me. Everything else seems completely pointless where I to choose to continue to
hoard it away, like Smaug on my pile of gold. Do you not think being a dragon under a mountain was an awfully lonely pursuit? I bet all he really wanted was someone to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/02/polyphia</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/02/polyphia</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Game Jam II</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I am once again participating in the &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/27/game-jam&quot;&gt;Global Game Jam&lt;/a&gt;, and after approximately 28 of our allotted 48 hours, we have already produced
something leaps and bounds ahead of last year’s effort. It has been frankly exhausting, but this time I can say that I’m genuinely proud of the work that myself and our team
have done and what we’ve been able to make in such a short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow our game will theoretically be available to play on the internet, so I’ll post a link and write a little more about it after the event is over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/01/game-jam-ii</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/01/game-jam-ii</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>