<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-29T06:25:24+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Book Reviews&amp;amp;colon; The Master and Margarita by Mikhail Bulgakov</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/28/book-reviews-the-master-and-margarita-by-mikhail-bulgakov" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Reviews&amp;colon; The Master and Margarita by Mikhail Bulgakov" /><published>2019-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/28/book-reviews-the-master-and-margarita-by-mikhail-bulgakov</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/28/book-reviews-the-master-and-margarita-by-mikhail-bulgakov">&lt;p&gt;Well, the whole 52 books in 52 weeks thing is looking admittedly unlikely to pan out, but I have nonetheless made some progress by finally finishing ‘The Master and Margarita’
by Mikhail Bulgakov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact it essentially took me 6 months to read, I thoroughly enjoyed Bulgakov’s magnum opus. Not published until 17 years after his death, and even then heavily censored, the novel can only really be described as absurd. Satan and a handful of his aides travel to Soviet Moscow and wreak havoc on its inhabitants, primarily its literary elite, through the use of transforming banknotes and disappearing dresses,
prophecies of imminent death and Behemoth, the black cat who frequently clutches a gun in his paw. All the while, Bulgakov also gives his own version of events surrounding the execution of Jesus, or Yeshua as he is
in the book, retold with Pontius Pilate seemingly the protagonist and Yeshua having only a lone disciple in Levi Matthew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very hard to ‘review’ this book, because it is truely so bizarre, and I have never read anything like it. It was a phenomenal read, perhaps because of its oddities rather than in spite of them. Trying to 
extract some kind of allegory or overarching message from the story is a job for a far greater intellect than me, but I cannot recommend it strongly enough purely as a romp through the ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9/10, a sensational read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books read this year: 3/52&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next book: Moscow to the End of the Line by Benedict Erofeev&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">Well, the whole 52 books in 52 weeks thing is looking admittedly unlikely to pan out, but I have nonetheless made some progress by finally finishing ‘The Master and Margarita’ by Mikhail Bulgakov.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iNcontroL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/27/incontrol" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iNcontroL" /><published>2019-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/27/incontrol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/27/incontrol">&lt;p&gt;Geoff Robinson, better known by his screenname, ‘iNcontroL’ passed away on July 20th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I’d never really understood why people get upset when a celebrity they’ve never met dies. But now, I think I sort of get it. Waking up to read the news that iNcontroL had died was a total shock to me, so much so that I didn’t initially think it could be real, like many others in the Starcraft community of which Geoff was a part for almost 20 years. He was only 33 years old when he suffered a pulmonary embolism which took his life with virtually no warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoff was a big part of why I got hooked on esports years ago, and why I continue to be so enamoured with Starcraft to this day, and so despite never having met or talked to him, I wanted to write a little about why he was so great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my earliest infatuations with the scene came in the form of the GD show, a news and opinions programme that was streamed live every Tuesday night at 8pm GMT from the GD Studio in Sweden. Geoff was one of the
regulars on the show, along with Adebisi, Semmler, Apollo, Hellspawn, wEppas, Statsman Bruno, Trance, Draskyl and of course 2GD himself. I had chess club at 7:30pm, but I would frequently try to finish my games quickly and then hurry home in the hopes of catching the tail end of the live broadcast. Geoff’s character was indomitable, a juggernaut of both intellect and humour, and Starcraft was blessed that a man of such
obvious talents chose to lend them to that game in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoff was also a regular on State of the Game and produced arguably the two best moments in the entire series - first by laying down the law on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9iSb5-X_2do&amp;amp;t=1s&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt; and then second by making &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fEcsmUx8CzU&quot;&gt;Day9 fall off his chair&lt;/a&gt;. His demeanour and love of life was evident to all, and he was an inspiration to many in the community through his dedication to the game and relentless optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years he has been the shining light on commentary panels, bringing unmatched humour and passion to each cast, uniting diehard fans and newcomers alike with his ability to analyse and simplify the intricacies of an exceptionally complex game. Future events simply won’t be the same without him.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="esports" /><summary type="html">Geoff Robinson, better known by his screenname, ‘iNcontroL’ passed away on July 20th.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Honesty Problem II&amp;amp;colon; The Honesty Solution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/26/the-honesty-problem-ii-the-honesty-solution" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Honesty Problem II&amp;colon; The Honesty Solution" /><published>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/26/the-honesty-problem-ii-the-honesty-solution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/26/the-honesty-problem-ii-the-honesty-solution">&lt;p&gt;It appears the break is over - in fact it lasted a lot less time than I’d anticipated. But, the fans have spoken, and who am I to
deny my loyal followers the quality content that they so crave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more serious note, the biggest reason I decided to write again today, and probably again tomorrow, and the day after, is that
I spent some time reading through a handful of my old posts. It was a thoroughly enjoyable experience - not because I am an even vaguely competent writer, but because they capture a snapshot of myself from the past. Revisiting all those moments in time was a surprisingly pleasant journey, and ellicited a string of wry smiles. There are many posts I have written here that I love and am proud of, and not continuing to write more seems like something I might regret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such post that I returned to was &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/28/the-honesty-problem&quot;&gt;The Honesty Problem&lt;/a&gt;, which I wrote while very
much struggling at the end of last year. It talks plainly about how I am scared to admit to the people around me how low I was feeling, at a time when I felt isolated and alone, and in retrospect is pretty obviously a cry for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, it somewhat worked. In the days that followed that post, I did tell my friends how bad things had gotten, how trapped I felt, and how afraid I was about the future. Funnily enough, none of them abandoned me or gave me any indication that I was
being a burden - in fact, it strengthened my relationships with them. In the time since, I have slowly been more honest with more people,
and the overwhelming sense of loneliness I felt barely 6 months ago has transformed into a feeling that I am surrounded at all times by people who love and care about me. While I once labelled the idea of being honest about how I feel as a “problem”, it has since
allowed me to feel a stronger connection to someone than I have in years, that I didn’t even think I had the capacity to feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was wrong on the 28th December 2018, and I’m immensely grateful I was. I like being wrong - sometimes at least. I’ve still got
further progress to make with honesty, but I am happy to rebrand it as a solution and not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you tomorrow, friends.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">It appears the break is over - in fact it lasted a lot less time than I’d anticipated. But, the fans have spoken, and who am I to deny my loyal followers the quality content that they so crave?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking a Break</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/30/taking-a-break" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking a Break" /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/30/taking-a-break</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/30/taking-a-break">&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to take a break from writing here daily, for a whole bunch of reasons, the main one being that I don’t have much time on most weekdays to do so and don’t feel that I have
been writing anything especially interesting here for a few weeks. Hopefully I will resume at some point, or get round to actually writing some longer pieces - none so far in 2019 is pretty poor!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I’ve decided to take a break from writing here daily, for a whole bunch of reasons, the main one being that I don’t have much time on most weekdays to do so and don’t feel that I have been writing anything especially interesting here for a few weeks. Hopefully I will resume at some point, or get round to actually writing some longer pieces - none so far in 2019 is pretty poor!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hay Fever</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/29/hay-fever" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hay Fever" /><published>2019-06-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/29/hay-fever</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/29/hay-fever">&lt;p&gt;Just a short one today, because I am dying. Hay fever absolutely sucks, and as hard as I am trying to will it away, it does not appear to be working.
Guess it’s time to load up on antihistimines on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Just a short one today, because I am dying. Hay fever absolutely sucks, and as hard as I am trying to will it away, it does not appear to be working. Guess it’s time to load up on antihistimines on Monday.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Hedonic Treadmill</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/28/the-hedonic-treadmill" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Hedonic Treadmill" /><published>2019-06-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/28/the-hedonic-treadmill</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/28/the-hedonic-treadmill">&lt;p&gt;I worry a little about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonic_treadmill&quot;&gt;hedonic treadmill&lt;/a&gt;. Things have been going great recently,
but what if my baseline happiness is actually far lower than I am at currently, and a decline
in my wellbeing is inevitable? Today I don’t feel as great as I have for much of the last 
month, even with very little reason - everything around me is  still wonderful. Hopefully it is
‘just one of those days’ and not my mood regressing towards the mean.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I worry a little about the hedonic treadmill. Things have been going great recently, but what if my baseline happiness is actually far lower than I am at currently, and a decline in my wellbeing is inevitable? Today I don’t feel as great as I have for much of the last month, even with very little reason - everything around me is still wonderful. Hopefully it is ‘just one of those days’ and not my mood regressing towards the mean.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sri Chinmoy Self Transcendence Race</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/27/the-sri-chinmoy-self-transcendence-race" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sri Chinmoy Self Transcendence Race" /><published>2019-06-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/27/the-sri-chinmoy-self-transcendence-race</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/27/the-sri-chinmoy-self-transcendence-race">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://3100.srichinmoyraces.org/&quot;&gt;Sri Chinmoy Self Transcendence Race&lt;/a&gt; is probably the dumbest thing I’ve ever heard of,
and so naturally also one of the greatest. Participants run 3100 miles around the ~800m course, naturally a block in Queens, NYC,
over the course of 52 days. During the process, the idea is that they experience self transcendence, and attain higher consciousness -
Chinmoy was a spiritual leader after all. Needless to say, each runner puts themselves through physical agony as they run 18 hour days,
and it’s not difficult to find tales of the racers going to A&amp;amp;E to receive treatment for truly next-level blisters, and I’m sure this
is part of the allure - suffering precedes enlightenment of course. Several previous finishers report out of body experiences, visions,
elation, essentially claiming to have reached the nirvana they were seeking through extreme physical exertion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t doubt that going through such an experience would provide you with a particularly unique insight into the human experience, and
the nature of our reality, but personally I’m gonna stick to plain old meditation and books.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Running" /><category term="Spirituality" /><summary type="html">The Sri Chinmoy Self Transcendence Race is probably the dumbest thing I’ve ever heard of, and so naturally also one of the greatest. Participants run 3100 miles around the ~800m course, naturally a block in Queens, NYC, over the course of 52 days. During the process, the idea is that they experience self transcendence, and attain higher consciousness - Chinmoy was a spiritual leader after all. Needless to say, each runner puts themselves through physical agony as they run 18 hour days, and it’s not difficult to find tales of the racers going to A&amp;amp;E to receive treatment for truly next-level blisters, and I’m sure this is part of the allure - suffering precedes enlightenment of course. Several previous finishers report out of body experiences, visions, elation, essentially claiming to have reached the nirvana they were seeking through extreme physical exertion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So This is What It’s Come To</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/26/so-this-is-what-its-come-to" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So This is What It's Come To" /><published>2019-06-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/26/so-this-is-what-its-come-to</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/26/so-this-is-what-its-come-to">&lt;p&gt;Apparently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/hey-advertisers-track-this/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is now the way that we’re fighting aggressive ad
tracking practices. Now, I know it’s mostly a joke - and also it’s not like a huge amount of Mozilla dev time has gone into this, I’m
sure it was knocked out in a couple of hours in one Friday afternoon. But, are the people who are still fighting for a free Internet really
advocating such ridiculous practices in order to circumvent tracking? I guess it is good to be able to poke fun at oneself, but in this
instance I think the scary thing about the joke is how worryingly believable as reality it is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Privacy" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Apparently, this is now the way that we’re fighting aggressive ad tracking practices. Now, I know it’s mostly a joke - and also it’s not like a huge amount of Mozilla dev time has gone into this, I’m sure it was knocked out in a couple of hours in one Friday afternoon. But, are the people who are still fighting for a free Internet really advocating such ridiculous practices in order to circumvent tracking? I guess it is good to be able to poke fun at oneself, but in this instance I think the scary thing about the joke is how worryingly believable as reality it is.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer League</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/25/summer-league" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer League" /><published>2019-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/25/summer-league</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/25/summer-league">&lt;p&gt;The Guernsey Chess Club’s summer league has officially started, and has made me realise quite how much fun the game can be. In the absence
of any kind of pressure to get results (other than that applied by my own ego) I am free to play spuriously, speculatively and hopefully spectacularly,
knowing that one particularly thrilling victory will more than make up for a handful of underwhelming losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, when we revert back to the winter league and things get all serious, which one way would I rather be playing?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="chess" /><summary type="html">The Guernsey Chess Club’s summer league has officially started, and has made me realise quite how much fun the game can be. In the absence of any kind of pressure to get results (other than that applied by my own ego) I am free to play spuriously, speculatively and hopefully spectacularly, knowing that one particularly thrilling victory will more than make up for a handful of underwhelming losses.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Emptying Your Amazon Basket, Forever</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/24/emptying-your-amazon-basket-forever" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emptying Your Amazon Basket, Forever" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/24/emptying-your-amazon-basket-forever</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/06/24/emptying-your-amazon-basket-forever">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I went to amazon.co.uk to buy a hat - more specifically, one to go running with. So naturally, I searched for ‘running cap’, 
and was quickly drawn to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/GADIEMENSS-Lightweight-Breathable-Outdoor-Running/dp/B07111ZHHG/ref=sr_1_7?keywords=running+cap&amp;amp;qid=1561380585&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-7&quot;&gt;this item&lt;/a&gt;,
in part due to it’s slightly garish colour, but also it’s price and large number of high rated reviews. When scrolling down to read
a couple of said reviews, I was surprised to see that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/customer-reviews/R2WYFI8JJK6IWV/ref=cm_cr_dp_d_rvw_ttl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B07111ZHHG&quot;&gt;the top review&lt;/a&gt;
claimed that upon receipt of the product, they had been offered a second one for free if they posted a 5 star review on the site.
Combined with an incredible proportion of the 249 reviews being 5* - 95% of them - I completely believe it to be true. And so I left
Amazon and went and bought a similarly priced cap from an online sporting goods retailer in the UK instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should come as no great surprise that Amazon’s reviews are being manipulated, there have been articles posted about it for years now,
and the system certianly lends itself to being gamed - especially when the stakes are sufficiently high, and naturally on the world’s
largest ecommerce platform, they’re as high as they come. Third party sellers are constituting more and more of Amazon’s choice of products,
as it becomes a paradise for drop shippers and scammers. An article in today’s New York Times suggests that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/23/technology/amazon-domination-bookstore-books.html&quot;&gt;Amazon couldn’t care less
about counterfeit products&lt;/a&gt;, and there are
hundreds of horror stories to be found with minimal Googling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their advertising practices are getting progressively more aggressive as well - the penny has dropped for Amazon that money is in
data right now, not products, but they figure why not both. I had to pay £10 extra to buy a Kindle without ads - sorry, without
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Amazon-Kindle-Paperwhite-Waterproof-Twice-Storage/dp/B07747FR44/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=kindle+paperwhite&amp;amp;qid=1561381354&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;‘special offers and sponsored screensavers.’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, not using Amazon will sacrifice some amount of convenience, but with a password manager and PayPal, it’s not much effort
at all to buy from other online retailers these days. And you won’t be contributing to Satan’s divorce proceeding legal fund in
the process, so you can sleep soundly in your bed at night as an added bonus.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Yesterday, I went to amazon.co.uk to buy a hat - more specifically, one to go running with. So naturally, I searched for ‘running cap’, and was quickly drawn to this item, in part due to it’s slightly garish colour, but also it’s price and large number of high rated reviews. When scrolling down to read a couple of said reviews, I was surprised to see that the top review claimed that upon receipt of the product, they had been offered a second one for free if they posted a 5 star review on the site. Combined with an incredible proportion of the 249 reviews being 5* - 95% of them - I completely believe it to be true. And so I left Amazon and went and bought a similarly priced cap from an online sporting goods retailer in the UK instead.</summary></entry></feed>