<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-17T18:29:44+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">An Ode to the Love Shack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/17/an-ode-to-love-shack" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Ode to the Love Shack" /><published>2019-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/17/an-ode-to-love-shack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/17/an-ode-to-love-shack">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you see a faded sign at the end of the road that says
“15 miles to the 
Love Shack”
Love Shack, yeah, yeah”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Fine Dining" /><summary type="html">If you see a faded sign at the end of the road that says “15 miles to the Love Shack” Love Shack, yeah, yeah”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Four Burners</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/16/the-four-burners" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Four Burners" /><published>2019-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/16/the-four-burners</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/16/the-four-burners">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/four-burners-theory&quot;&gt;The four burners theory&lt;/a&gt; is a neat summarisation of something I have been feeling a lot recently. When I ramp up the intensity at work, 
my health slips. When I try to spend more time with my friends, I don’t see my family as much as I would like to. It seems I can’t have it all at once, and reading somebody else’s 
thoughts on it has given me some fresh ones of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious one is: do I actually want to “really successful”? What does that even mean, and what metrics are we using? I will always choose happiness as my metric of choice 
for success, and I think there is a compelling argument that living a rounded life (the four burners on dim strategy) might be the way to maximise my happiness. Intuitively, this 
feels like the wrong solution though - as a function of my high expectations, I think I will likely have to turn a burner or two off, that I might excel in something else to secure 
the gratification I so desire. My career ambitions remain lofty, and I believe they’re eminently reachable, but might take some sacrifices to get there. My health is never going to be 
the burner that is switched off, but it is also unlikely to ever be put above all else either. Connecting with other people is what I think ultimately makes me happiest, so it seems 
the family and friends burners are important also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Mr Clear’s three options are all excellent, and worth considering. Embracing constraints is undoubtedly something I am going to try and do more - my time is limited, so I should 
try to ensure that as much of it as possible is spent on one of the aforementioned four buckets. Outsourcing would be significantly easier if I had more disposable income, but it could 
be something worth considering when contemplating future career decisions and salary considerations. As for seasons… I am as yet unswayed. I want it all, I want it now, and I expect 
I will always want it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one day I’ll figure it out. Expect a followup in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">The four burners theory is a neat summarisation of something I have been feeling a lot recently. When I ramp up the intensity at work, my health slips. When I try to spend more time with my friends, I don’t see my family as much as I would like to. It seems I can’t have it all at once, and reading somebody else’s thoughts on it has given me some fresh ones of my own.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Joy of Starting Over</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/15/the-joy-of-starting-over" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Joy of Starting Over" /><published>2019-05-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/15/the-joy-of-starting-over</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/15/the-joy-of-starting-over">&lt;p&gt;Starting from an entirely new tech stack this week has been challenging for reasons both numerous and obvious, but thusfar I am 
relishing the opportunity. Switching from *nix-like to Windows, PHP to C#, functional to object-oriented, AWS to Azure, jQuery to 
React, etc etc, all require adaptation and a huge volume of learning in order to be able to contribute meaningfully to new projects.
With that being said, one of my commits got merged into the master branch on day two of my new position, which I think deserves at 
least a tepid round of applause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The enormity of unacquired knowledge being dangled in front of me has left me feeling enthused about learning, and eager to catch up 
with my colleagues, and the fact that I get to write interesting programmes during the process is the cherry on the cake. Now if you’ll 
excuse me, I have to spend the rest of my evening figuring out how the fuck MVC works.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Career" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Software Engineering" /><summary type="html">Starting from an entirely new tech stack this week has been challenging for reasons both numerous and obvious, but thusfar I am relishing the opportunity. Switching from *nix-like to Windows, PHP to C#, functional to object-oriented, AWS to Azure, jQuery to React, etc etc, all require adaptation and a huge volume of learning in order to be able to contribute meaningfully to new projects. With that being said, one of my commits got merged into the master branch on day two of my new position, which I think deserves at least a tepid round of applause.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fake It Until You Make It</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/14/fake-it-until-you-make-it" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fake It Until You Make It" /><published>2019-05-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/14/fake-it-until-you-make-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/14/fake-it-until-you-make-it">&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard the phrase ‘fake it ‘til you make it’, and I hope we have all
regarded it with at least some modicum of suspicion. Faking anything is inherently
repressing some element of the truth, and in my personal experience, that hasn’t
gone so great for me. The FITYMI slogan is something I hear a lot though, primarily
in the context of social confidence, and during the past week I’ve revisited it
to see if I still think it’s a dangerous idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When selectively applied, I think there may be some merit to it. During my usual
ennui-fuelled Hacker News trawlings, I’ve read a little about changing one’s personality,
and while intuitively the notion invokes a slight sense of fear, it is something
I certainly want to (continue to) do. From my exceptionally limited understanding,
talking and writing using a more upbeat tone can actually influence you to
think more positively. And maybe there is some iota of wisdom in simply pretending
to be confident - it will be a challenge to learn how to pretend, but if I can overcome
it, then it might lead the way for meaningfully less anxiety in my life, something
that I would relish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The balance between being truthful when things aren’t going so great, but still
remaining resolute and framing things in a favourable light is going to be a tough
one to strike, but follow along dear reader, for you will get to see my attempts
at such a balancing act right before your very eyes in the weeks to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">We’ve all heard the phrase ‘fake it ‘til you make it’, and I hope we have all regarded it with at least some modicum of suspicion. Faking anything is inherently repressing some element of the truth, and in my personal experience, that hasn’t gone so great for me. The FITYMI slogan is something I hear a lot though, primarily in the context of social confidence, and during the past week I’ve revisited it to see if I still think it’s a dangerous idea.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Day of a New Era</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/13/first-day-of-a-new-era" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Day of a New Era" /><published>2019-05-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/13/first-day-of-a-new-era</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/13/first-day-of-a-new-era">&lt;p&gt;As one epoch comes to an end, so must a new one begin, which is precisely the case for my career as I began a new job today. 
My job title has contracted down to a worryingly vague ‘developer’, but I now share that with every single one of my colleagues, 
and it is nice to feel equal in title if not in knowledge or ability. I certainly do not feel equal in either of those two things, 
but that is immensely refreshing - being acutely aware of my own lack of understanding of a new tech stack has filled me with a 
rejuvenated sense of excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to the new challenges and new opportunities that come along with new employment. Hopefully this will be my era
of Reiwa as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Career" /><summary type="html">As one epoch comes to an end, so must a new one begin, which is precisely the case for my career as I began a new job today. My job title has contracted down to a worryingly vague ‘developer’, but I now share that with every single one of my colleagues, and it is nice to feel equal in title if not in knowledge or ability. I certainly do not feel equal in either of those two things, but that is immensely refreshing - being acutely aware of my own lack of understanding of a new tech stack has filled me with a rejuvenated sense of excitement.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Terry A Davis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/12/terry-a-davis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Terry A Davis" /><published>2019-05-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/12/terry-a-davis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/12/terry-a-davis">&lt;p&gt;This afternoon I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UCgoxQCf5Jg&quot;&gt;this intriguing documentary&lt;/a&gt; on TempleOS and its creator, 
Terry A Davis. Davis’ story is remarkable; a genius programmer who single-handedly created a complex operating system, who was 
also plagued by crippling mental illness that left him further and further out of touch with the real world, all documented on 
the internet for anyone to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one hand, Davis was a delusion narcissist, unrepentant racist and all round asshole, and it easy to be disgusted by him or 
to pity him as a victim of schizophrenia and dismiss him altogether. But his talent for software cannot be overstated, and despite 
the obvious and deep flaws in TempleOS - ie that he believed it allowed him to commune with God - in many ways it is a borderline 
miraculous achievement (see what I did there?). Had he been mentally healthy, who knows what innovations he may have been able to 
bring to the tech community - it seems reasonable to assume that he could’ve had a meaningful impact on the operating system landscape 
today as we know it, all on his own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video also offers some interesting reflections on the relationship between mental illness on the internet; both that it can enable 
those who are struggling, as well as leave them vulnerable to harrassment, but also that it can document their story, and give the 
world at large an insight into their lives that they might not otherwise have been afforded. In some ways, Davis deserved the following 
he had, and there was certainly some segment of it that was unironic and respectul in the interest they took in his life and work. I 
almost wish I had been aware of him before the fact, so that I could also have followed him, although I suspect I would’ve written 
him off too quickly as just another crazy person on the internet - the crystallisation of information presented in the documentary 
has made me think that perhaps I should reconsider not just Davis, but similar people in future situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite piece of potentially accidental wisdom from Davis during the video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That bird has no idea what he’s looking at, and yet, what does the bird do? Does he panic? No, he just does the best he can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Computer Science" /><summary type="html">This afternoon I watched this intriguing documentary on TempleOS and its creator, Terry A Davis. Davis’ story is remarkable; a genius programmer who single-handedly created a complex operating system, who was also plagued by crippling mental illness that left him further and further out of touch with the real world, all documented on the internet for anyone to see.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chess Inter Insular</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/11/chess-inter-insular" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chess Inter Insular" /><published>2019-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/11/chess-inter-insular</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/11/chess-inter-insular">&lt;p&gt;Today was the 82nd installation of the Channel Islands Inter-Insular; the annual chess match between Guernsey and Jersey, in recent years played 
across 16 boards. Jersey could only field a weakend side, with many of their top players regrettably absent, which paved the way for a historic 
occasion (for me at least) - my first time being part of a winning team since 2010, our board two getting his 2nd individual win since his debut 
in 1983, and Guernsey’s biggest margin of victory since 1965.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only managed a draw against my opponent who I would consider myself a favourite against, but as things transpired a loss would’ve been a fairer 
result so I am glad I was able to salvage a vital half a point, and furthermore do a job for the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After last year’s particularly upsetting loss where I felt somewhat responsible for Guernsey’s overall loss, I was immensely grateful to be able 
to redeem myself this year, and the pride I feel at the drubbing we have handed our island counterparts is one I will not soon forget. All that remains 
is to slowly crawl up the board order for the next few years until I have a shot at becoming Channel Island champion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Chess" /><summary type="html">Today was the 82nd installation of the Channel Islands Inter-Insular; the annual chess match between Guernsey and Jersey, in recent years played across 16 boards. Jersey could only field a weakend side, with many of their top players regrettably absent, which paved the way for a historic occasion (for me at least) - my first time being part of a winning team since 2010, our board two getting his 2nd individual win since his debut in 1983, and Guernsey’s biggest margin of victory since 1965.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The End of a Short Era</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/10/the-end-of-a-short-era" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The End of a Short Era" /><published>2019-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/10/the-end-of-a-short-era</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/10/the-end-of-a-short-era">&lt;p&gt;Today was my last day as a web dev for the small company that I’ve worked for over the past year and a bit. I deliberately 
don’t talk much about my job on here, but I would be remiss not devote one of these daily posts to some of the amazing 
people that I have had the opportunity to work alongside. After leaving my first full time job at the end of 2016 
relatively straightforwardly, in fact barely even saying goodbye for anyone, I was not prepared to for some of the 
emotional farewells I had to face this time round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great reminder both of my own ability to form meaningful connections with others, and of people’s general wondrousness 
that I felt such a strong bond to some of my colleagues despite us never necessarily talking much about our personal lives. 
Evidently the shared experience of solving problems together, overcoming issues large and small, bouncing back from failure 
and celebrating success was enough to make me feel very strongly. I really was not expecting to find myself feeling as sad 
as I did to say goodbye to my colleagues. It was a very humbling experience, but I am immensely grateful for it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Career" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today was my last day as a web dev for the small company that I’ve worked for over the past year and a bit. I deliberately don’t talk much about my job on here, but I would be remiss not devote one of these daily posts to some of the amazing people that I have had the opportunity to work alongside. After leaving my first full time job at the end of 2016 relatively straightforwardly, in fact barely even saying goodbye for anyone, I was not prepared to for some of the emotional farewells I had to face this time round.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Being Called Out</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/09/being-called-out" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Being Called Out" /><published>2019-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/09/being-called-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/09/being-called-out">&lt;p&gt;Being called out, especially when you immediately realise you are wrong, is an especially
unpleasant feeling. It’s also a curious one - my gut instinct is always to be defensive,
to argue that there has been no wrongdoing on my part, even when my gut instinct is
very much that I have made a mistake (or furthermore that I have made the mistake
as a result of a repeated pattern of behaviour), and simply apologising and saying
that I will reconsider my thoughts and words in the future seems all but impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swallowing one’s pride is a painful experience, especially when one’s whole
life they have been raised to be proud. Casting off that fuzzy wall of excuses
and actually admitting culpability is intuitively unthinkable, but, to really
grow as a person it is clearly necessary. My other gut reaction is to be self-deprecating,
to simply say that I’m a sub-par human being and so of course I embody undesirable
traits, but that is not going to help me either - and frankly it is this pattern
of thinking in general that I am keen to carve out of my own brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I think or say or do stupid things. And that’s absolutely fine, I think -
what is not fine is to continue to do them despite having been confronted with their
inherent stupidity. That is what would truly make me a shitty person.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Being called out, especially when you immediately realise you are wrong, is an especially unpleasant feeling. It’s also a curious one - my gut instinct is always to be defensive, to argue that there has been no wrongdoing on my part, even when my gut instinct is very much that I have made a mistake (or furthermore that I have made the mistake as a result of a repeated pattern of behaviour), and simply apologising and saying that I will reconsider my thoughts and words in the future seems all but impossible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/08/running-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running II" /><published>2019-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/08/running-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/08/running-ii">&lt;p&gt;After covering 17km in 3 days, surely a massive personal best for me, my body &lt;em&gt;hurts&lt;/em&gt;. My calves are aching and tight, and my 
feet have been pummeled, my arches ache even to walk and my blisters are truly vile. Today I took the day off, and I will likely 
take the next two days off as well, getting injured right at the start of my illustrious racing career seems unwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I hope this necessary R&amp;amp;R time doesn’t cause my newfound enthusiasm to wane. If the calorie counter on Strava is to be even 
vaguely believed, running could be the final piece of the e’er-mysterious weight loss puzzle. As much as it pains me to say it, 
running is kind of great - it gets you out of the house, you get fitter and healthier, you get to feel better about yourself, it 
can have a certain meditative quality - I already feel like I have learned a lot about myself during the tail end of some of routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And also there’s a certain someone that I have to annihilate at park run in June.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Health and Fitness" /><summary type="html">After covering 17km in 3 days, surely a massive personal best for me, my body hurts. My calves are aching and tight, and my feet have been pummeled, my arches ache even to walk and my blisters are truly vile. Today I took the day off, and I will likely take the next two days off as well, getting injured right at the start of my illustrious racing career seems unwise.</summary></entry></feed>