<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-10T18:32:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">I miss painting my nails</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/10/i-miss-painting-my-nails" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I miss painting my nails" /><published>2018-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/10/i-miss-painting-my-nails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/10/i-miss-painting-my-nails">&lt;p&gt;
  I am pretty sure I have already written a post to this exact effect but whatever,
  it is what has been on my mind today and so I want to write about it (again).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I miss painting my nails. The more I think about it, the more awesome it was. Sure,
  there were some uncomfortable moments - for example when my father asked me if I
  had begun painting them due to my 'mood'. The more I think about this question,
  the dumber I think it is. As my father, does he even need to question it? His
  tone was not entirely disapproving, but I knew he wished I had clear cuticles
  nonetheless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Another good one was when I was coaching at fencing. One of the younger kids
  asked me if I knew my nails were black - I said I had shut all 10 of them in
  a car door accidentally. Another, older one, 16 or so asked 'if I was a tranny
  now' - a comment which clearly shows how far my local community, if not many
  wider communities, have to go.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It was a great icebreaker though - random girls in bars would compliment me on
  them, and sometimes we'd have a conversation as a result. I'm not used to talking
  to girls I don't know in bars, but apparently it's something that a lot of men
  enjoy. Sometimes it was pretty intimidating, but sometimes I liked it. It was a
  good measure of a person almost immediately - if they thought it was weird or
  felt uncomfortable because of it, I probably didn't want to pursue any further
  interactions with them. If they commented positively on it and were supportive,
  then the opposite was true.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It was a wonderful act of self care too. In his defense, my father &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt;
  right to some extent - at a time when I was exceptionally low, taking time to
  apply the nail polish every week or so felt relaxing. I was doing something for
  myself, to make myself look... perhaps not better, but different, in a way I
  wanted to be. It was beautifully therapeutic, and I loved that aspect of it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Finally, it was a way to be different from those around me. In some awful,
  narcisstic, self aggrandizing, self absorbed hyper-bullshit kinda way, I have never
  felt like I belonged in my environment. I have wanted to be different, disdainful
  of the people I encountered every day, but I have always felt a strong compulsion
  to look and act the same way as them. This was my small, silent first step towards
  rebellion. Men around here don't paint their nails - but I do. I am not like the
  swathes of complacent, narrow-minded accountants that surround me. I was determined
  to do something to change my place in our micro-society, to affirm to myself
  and everyone else that I am &lt;strong&gt;not one of them.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I sound almost comically like Holden Caulfield. Perhaps, in consideration of the
  ideas above, Caulfield is not quite as insufferable as I had considered him to
  be on first read.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The point is, I miss painting my nails. I stopped because of my job, and I thought
  it could be weird or awkward, or that I might be treated differently because of it.
  I want to start again, but I'm too afraid to do so. I wish I wasn't.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I am pretty sure I have already written a post to this exact effect but whatever, it is what has been on my mind today and so I want to write about it (again). I miss painting my nails. The more I think about it, the more awesome it was. Sure, there were some uncomfortable moments - for example when my father asked me if I had begun painting them due to my 'mood'. The more I think about this question, the dumber I think it is. As my father, does he even need to question it? His tone was not entirely disapproving, but I knew he wished I had clear cuticles nonetheless. Another good one was when I was coaching at fencing. One of the younger kids asked me if I knew my nails were black - I said I had shut all 10 of them in a car door accidentally. Another, older one, 16 or so asked 'if I was a tranny now' - a comment which clearly shows how far my local community, if not many wider communities, have to go. It was a great icebreaker though - random girls in bars would compliment me on them, and sometimes we'd have a conversation as a result. I'm not used to talking to girls I don't know in bars, but apparently it's something that a lot of men enjoy. Sometimes it was pretty intimidating, but sometimes I liked it. It was a good measure of a person almost immediately - if they thought it was weird or felt uncomfortable because of it, I probably didn't want to pursue any further interactions with them. If they commented positively on it and were supportive, then the opposite was true. It was a wonderful act of self care too. In his defense, my father was right to some extent - at a time when I was exceptionally low, taking time to apply the nail polish every week or so felt relaxing. I was doing something for myself, to make myself look... perhaps not better, but different, in a way I wanted to be. It was beautifully therapeutic, and I loved that aspect of it. Finally, it was a way to be different from those around me. In some awful, narcisstic, self aggrandizing, self absorbed hyper-bullshit kinda way, I have never felt like I belonged in my environment. I have wanted to be different, disdainful of the people I encountered every day, but I have always felt a strong compulsion to look and act the same way as them. This was my small, silent first step towards rebellion. Men around here don't paint their nails - but I do. I am not like the swathes of complacent, narrow-minded accountants that surround me. I was determined to do something to change my place in our micro-society, to affirm to myself and everyone else that I am not one of them. I sound almost comically like Holden Caulfield. Perhaps, in consideration of the ideas above, Caulfield is not quite as insufferable as I had considered him to be on first read. The point is, I miss painting my nails. I stopped because of my job, and I thought it could be weird or awkward, or that I might be treated differently because of it. I want to start again, but I'm too afraid to do so. I wish I wasn't.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ASMR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/09/asmr" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASMR" /><published>2018-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/09/asmr</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/09/asmr">&lt;p&gt;
  Over the last couple of months I have discovered the wondrousness of ASMR - more
  specifically, watching and listening to videos which are designed to promote
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autonomous_sensory_meridian_response&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response.&lt;/a&gt; I listen to an 'intentional' ASMR video
  every night in bed, and I can honestly say I think they have massively improved
  my quality of sleep, and my ability to get to sleep quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  ASMR is a little strange though. When I typed it into DuckDuckGo to double check
  what it stood for, one of the top results is a porn site, where ASMR is actually
  listed as a category. I've not watched ASMR porn (yet?) but I can understand the
  appeal - ASMR is very intimate in nature, and can have a very personal feel.
  After all, someone is essentially whispering in your ear.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am also slightly ashamed of my newfound love, because I think part of the reason
  I enjoy it so much is precisely because of the intimacy it offers. I mostly listen
  to videos of women whispering, and it's... pretty embarrassing to admit, when I
  phrase it like that. A lot more so than if I talked about the kind of thing I
  watch women do in porn, which seems kinda backwards.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Aside from the actual 'tingles', which are amazing, ASMR aficionados proclaim
  some of its greatest benefits are on those suffering with mental health problems,
  and in my personal experience I would have to agree. When you are feeling anxious,
  stressed or low, someone whispering comforting things (or even total nonsense)
  in your ear is a welcome and calming distraction.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Next time you are struggling to sleep, I would definitely recommend trying to be
  open minded and trying an ASMR video.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Over the last couple of months I have discovered the wondrousness of ASMR - more specifically, watching and listening to videos which are designed to promote Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response. I listen to an 'intentional' ASMR video every night in bed, and I can honestly say I think they have massively improved my quality of sleep, and my ability to get to sleep quickly. ASMR is a little strange though. When I typed it into DuckDuckGo to double check what it stood for, one of the top results is a porn site, where ASMR is actually listed as a category. I've not watched ASMR porn (yet?) but I can understand the appeal - ASMR is very intimate in nature, and can have a very personal feel. After all, someone is essentially whispering in your ear. I am also slightly ashamed of my newfound love, because I think part of the reason I enjoy it so much is precisely because of the intimacy it offers. I mostly listen to videos of women whispering, and it's... pretty embarrassing to admit, when I phrase it like that. A lot more so than if I talked about the kind of thing I watch women do in porn, which seems kinda backwards. Aside from the actual 'tingles', which are amazing, ASMR aficionados proclaim some of its greatest benefits are on those suffering with mental health problems, and in my personal experience I would have to agree. When you are feeling anxious, stressed or low, someone whispering comforting things (or even total nonsense) in your ear is a welcome and calming distraction. Next time you are struggling to sleep, I would definitely recommend trying to be open minded and trying an ASMR video.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Schedule</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/08/schedule" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Schedule" /><published>2018-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/08/schedule</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/08/schedule">&lt;p&gt;
  Having a strict schedule, where I get up and go to bed at the same time very day,
  and can plan my time around my routines, has helped me a lot recently. Last night
  and today my schedule has been knocked off and it has thrown me for quite the loop -
  so today just a short post and an early night. Sweet dreams, friends.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Having a strict schedule, where I get up and go to bed at the same time very day, and can plan my time around my routines, has helped me a lot recently. Last night and today my schedule has been knocked off and it has thrown me for quite the loop - so today just a short post and an early night. Sweet dreams, friends.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Top Ten Albums of 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/07/top-ten-albums-of-2018" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top Ten Albums of 2018" /><published>2018-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/07/top-ten-albums-of-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/07/top-ten-albums-of-2018">&lt;p&gt;
  Nobody asked for it, so here it is - my top 10 albums of 2018.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol reversed&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Denzel Curry - TA13OO.&lt;/strong&gt; One of my favourite hip hop albums of
    the year, Curry mostly delivered with his promise of a dark and twisted
    concept album. Overall very solid and worth a listen, especially if you are
    bored of the current generation of mumble rappers.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Death Grips - Year of the Snitch.&lt;/strong&gt; I love everything Death Grips
    has produced, and in my opinion the weirder the better. While I wish their
    brand of experimental hip hop had been pushed further on this album, it still
    gives me that feeling of unease that I'm looking for in a Death Grips record.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Kanye West - Ye.&lt;/strong&gt; After not being a fan of TLOP, or most of
    Kanye's later work in general, I thought Ye was a step back in the right direction,
    and showed that the hip hop juggernaut has still got it. The production
    is incredible, the lyrics are confessional, powerful and different from anything we've heard
    from Kanye before - my only qualm is that the album is far too short.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Starcrawler - Starcrawler.&lt;/strong&gt; A throwback to a bygone era of rock
    and roll, but with an updated sound and slightly deranged appearance, Starcrawler's
    eponymous debut full length project really blew me away. Hopefully the band
    grows in popularity and there's more to come soon, as this album has some bangers on it.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Mom Jeans. - Puppy Love.&lt;/strong&gt; This album could very easily be a
    contender for top spot on the list, if it weren't for the fact that Mom Jeans
    set the bar so insanely high with their 2016 debut, Best Buds. Listening to that
    album is like hugging your best friend, and while Puppy Love is still an instant
    emo classic, the fact I have usually gone back to their earlier work when in the mood for
    some Mom Jeans meant their 2018 record fell a few places.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Anderson .Paak - Oxnard.&lt;/strong&gt; Comfortably my favourite hip hop album
    of the year, Oxnard has it all - from a Mac Miller tribute, to the almost-mandatory
    'Fuck Trump' track, to... a song about getting road head. Paak is hilarious and
    honest in equal measure, and immensely talented at all times, not to mention
    the neat features on the record.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Graduating Life - Grad Life.&lt;/strong&gt; This relatively underground
    emo/alt/punk slice of goodness gets to be #4 mostly because of how it made me
    feel when I listened to it, something I have mentioned in previous posts. A
    poignant blend of righteous anger and determined perseverance, this album
    is as inspirational as it is catchy.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Mitski - Be The Cowboy.&lt;/strong&gt; The top three of this list could be
    in any order to be honest, or simply all be joint first. I adore Mitski's
    music, and Be The Cowboy is no different. Her arrangements are gorgeous, her
    melancholy lyrics painful yet relatable, and her voice the perfect vehicle for
    delivering them.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;IDLES - Joy As An Act Of Resistance.&lt;/strong&gt; I would consider myself
    someone with a cetain amount of punk sensibility, and this album proved that
    the genre isn't dead. An outspoken retaliation against right-wing politics,
    toxic masculinity and racism, the band's aggressive sound carries with it a
    message of peace and love. This record was a welcome reminder that the world
    has not completely gone to shit.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Twin Fantasy.&lt;/strong&gt; I feel like it's a bit of
    a cop-out to put this album as my #1 seeing as it is a rework of an album
    already released, but if I could only listen to one album on this list ever
    again, it would definitely be this one. Will Toledo continues to be one of my
    heroes, and his 2018 re-imagining of 2011 fan favourite Twin Fantasy is a significant
    enough departure from and improvement upon the original to merit its inclusion here.
    Toledo's deeply personal, poetic lyrics detail his struggle with love, sexuality,
    relationships and life in general in a way that endears me greatly to him, and
    the instrumentation on the rework allows the lyrics to shine through more than on
    the original - something that is not surprising, given that he has said on his
    early albums he intentionally tried to drown out his voice out of embarrassment.
    The updated version also features a number of nods to die-hard fans of the original
    record, adding to the sense of self-awareness which is one of the reasons I love
    CSH's music. If I am ever going to give an album 10/10, this is going to be the one.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Nobody asked for it, so here it is - my top 10 albums of 2018. Denzel Curry - TA13OO. One of my favourite hip hop albums of the year, Curry mostly delivered with his promise of a dark and twisted concept album. Overall very solid and worth a listen, especially if you are bored of the current generation of mumble rappers. Death Grips - Year of the Snitch. I love everything Death Grips has produced, and in my opinion the weirder the better. While I wish their brand of experimental hip hop had been pushed further on this album, it still gives me that feeling of unease that I'm looking for in a Death Grips record. Kanye West - Ye. After not being a fan of TLOP, or most of Kanye's later work in general, I thought Ye was a step back in the right direction, and showed that the hip hop juggernaut has still got it. The production is incredible, the lyrics are confessional, powerful and different from anything we've heard from Kanye before - my only qualm is that the album is far too short. Starcrawler - Starcrawler. A throwback to a bygone era of rock and roll, but with an updated sound and slightly deranged appearance, Starcrawler's eponymous debut full length project really blew me away. Hopefully the band grows in popularity and there's more to come soon, as this album has some bangers on it. Mom Jeans. - Puppy Love. This album could very easily be a contender for top spot on the list, if it weren't for the fact that Mom Jeans set the bar so insanely high with their 2016 debut, Best Buds. Listening to that album is like hugging your best friend, and while Puppy Love is still an instant emo classic, the fact I have usually gone back to their earlier work when in the mood for some Mom Jeans meant their 2018 record fell a few places. Anderson .Paak - Oxnard. Comfortably my favourite hip hop album of the year, Oxnard has it all - from a Mac Miller tribute, to the almost-mandatory 'Fuck Trump' track, to... a song about getting road head. Paak is hilarious and honest in equal measure, and immensely talented at all times, not to mention the neat features on the record. Graduating Life - Grad Life. This relatively underground emo/alt/punk slice of goodness gets to be #4 mostly because of how it made me feel when I listened to it, something I have mentioned in previous posts. A poignant blend of righteous anger and determined perseverance, this album is as inspirational as it is catchy. Mitski - Be The Cowboy. The top three of this list could be in any order to be honest, or simply all be joint first. I adore Mitski's music, and Be The Cowboy is no different. Her arrangements are gorgeous, her melancholy lyrics painful yet relatable, and her voice the perfect vehicle for delivering them. IDLES - Joy As An Act Of Resistance. I would consider myself someone with a cetain amount of punk sensibility, and this album proved that the genre isn't dead. An outspoken retaliation against right-wing politics, toxic masculinity and racism, the band's aggressive sound carries with it a message of peace and love. This record was a welcome reminder that the world has not completely gone to shit. Car Seat Headrest - Twin Fantasy. I feel like it's a bit of a cop-out to put this album as my #1 seeing as it is a rework of an album already released, but if I could only listen to one album on this list ever again, it would definitely be this one. Will Toledo continues to be one of my heroes, and his 2018 re-imagining of 2011 fan favourite Twin Fantasy is a significant enough departure from and improvement upon the original to merit its inclusion here. Toledo's deeply personal, poetic lyrics detail his struggle with love, sexuality, relationships and life in general in a way that endears me greatly to him, and the instrumentation on the rework allows the lyrics to shine through more than on the original - something that is not surprising, given that he has said on his early albums he intentionally tried to drown out his voice out of embarrassment. The updated version also features a number of nods to die-hard fans of the original record, adding to the sense of self-awareness which is one of the reasons I love CSH's music. If I am ever going to give an album 10/10, this is going to be the one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spotify 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/06/spotify-2018" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spotify 2018" /><published>2018-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/06/spotify-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/06/spotify-2018">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I saw my 'Your Top Songs 2018' playlist in my Discover for the first time,
  which (I assume) is a curation of the 100 songs I have listened to most this year.
  I am going to try and feed them all into a Python script and see if I can do
  some fun analysis on them at the weekend, but today I don't have even close to
  enough time. Instead, here are my 100 most listened to songs of 2018 in artist - song
  format:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mom Jeans. - Shred Cruz (Audiotree Live Version)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The New Law - Sang Noir and the Nightbringer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;King Gizzard &amp; The Lizard Wizard - Crumbling Castle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epica - Crimson Bow and Arrow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moe Shop, MYLK - Magic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blue Sky Black Death - Our Hearts Of Ruin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Dead-bird&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduating Life - An Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Seat Headrest - My Boy (Twin Fantasy)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joji - Yeah Right&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Totorro - Brocolissimo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexisonfire - 44. Caliber Love Letter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The New Law - Death Another Day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mom Jeans. - Poor Boxer Shorts (Audiotree Live Version)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tricot - Pool Side&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stromae - tous les mêmes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metronomy - Nights Out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moe Shop, Puniden - Virtual&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mitski - Geyser&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Trailer Trash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduating Life - Cold Raviolis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Totorro - Yaaaago&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring Me The Horizon - Pray For Plagues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;King Gizzard &amp; The Lizard Wizard - Polygondwanaland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mom Jeans. - Edward 40hands (Audiotree Live Version)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epica - Edge of the Blade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Cute Thing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prince Daddy &amp; the Hyena - I thought You Didn't Even Like Leaving&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Death Grips - Get Got&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blue Sky Black Death - And Stars, Ringed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Becky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;REOL - 宵々古今&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bent Knee - Terror Bird&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Julien Baker - Blacktop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joji - Will He&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Totorro - Saveur Cheveux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epica - Universal Death Squad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Nervous Young Humans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduating Life - There's Only One Way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alice Merton - No Roots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tricot - Tobe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Real Adult&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sorority Noise - No Halo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexisonfire - Accidents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modern Baseball - The Waterboy Returns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metronomy - Radio Ladio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Biffy Clyro - Glitter And Trauma&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epica - Wings of Freedom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Death Grips - I Break Mirrors With My Face&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduating Life - Kill Me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The New Law - End World&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;88rising, Joji, Rich Brian, Higher Brothers, AUGUST 08 - Midsummer Madness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mom Jeans. - near death fail comp (must watch til end)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fall Out Boy - Saturday&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hobo Johnson - Sex in the City&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prince Daddy &amp; the Hyena - Clever Girl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mitski - Why Didn't You Stop Me?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Veil Of Maya - Lull&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexisonfire - A Dagger Through The Heart of St Angeles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cap'n Jazz - Basil's Kite&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elephant Gym - 中途&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mouse on the keys - leviathan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;REOL - コノヨ Loading...&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mom Jeans. - sponsor me tape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tricot - Pool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moe Shop, YUC'e - Baby Pink&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blue Sky Black Death - Sleeping Children Are Still Flying&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;King Gizzard &amp; The Lizard Wizard - The Castle in the Air&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prince Daddy &amp; the Hyena - Thrashville 1/3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Beachboy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mitski - Old Friend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elijah Who - crush on you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save Us from the Archon - All I Want Is Sleep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;REOL - ギミアブレスタッナウ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowing - I Think We're in Minsk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring Me The Horizon - (I Used To Make Out With) Medusa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Seat Headrest - We Can't Afford (Your Depression Anymore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mouse on the keys - i shut my eyes in order to see&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kanye West - I Thought About Killing You&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glocca Morra - Ya'll Boots Hats? (Die Angry)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Skeleton Bones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epica - A Phantasmic Parade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Totorro - Chevalier Bulltoe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infected Mushroom - Flamingo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modern Baseball - ...And Beyond&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Julien Baker - Sprained Ankle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mom Jeans., Graduating Life - Shred Cruz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starcrawler - I Love LA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Veil Of Maya - Doublespeak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pictures of Vernon - The Sunshine Bus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Death Grips - The Fever (Aye Aye)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Bottles and Cans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bent Knee - Hole&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Totorro - Home Alone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tricot - On the boom (Audiotree Live Version)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexisonfire - Counterparts And Number Them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Fill in the Blank&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;88rising, Joji, BlocBoy JB - Peach Jam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microwave - Homebody&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taking Back Sunday - Cute Without The 'E' (Cut From The Team)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Shoutout to Mom Jeans./Graduating Life for making Shred Cruz, a song that got
  on the list twice!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Today I saw my 'Your Top Songs 2018' playlist in my Discover for the first time, which (I assume) is a curation of the 100 songs I have listened to most this year. I am going to try and feed them all into a Python script and see if I can do some fun analysis on them at the weekend, but today I don't have even close to enough time. Instead, here are my 100 most listened to songs of 2018 in artist - song format: Mom Jeans. - Shred Cruz (Audiotree Live Version) The New Law - Sang Noir and the Nightbringer King Gizzard &amp; The Lizard Wizard - Crumbling Castle Epica - Crimson Bow and Arrow Moe Shop, MYLK - Magic Blue Sky Black Death - Our Hearts Of Ruin McCafferty - Dead-bird Graduating Life - An Introduction Car Seat Headrest - My Boy (Twin Fantasy) Joji - Yeah Right Totorro - Brocolissimo Alexisonfire - 44. Caliber Love Letter The New Law - Death Another Day Mom Jeans. - Poor Boxer Shorts (Audiotree Live Version) tricot - Pool Side Stromae - tous les mêmes Metronomy - Nights Out Moe Shop, Puniden - Virtual Mitski - Geyser McCafferty - Trailer Trash Graduating Life - Cold Raviolis Totorro - Yaaaago Bring Me The Horizon - Pray For Plagues King Gizzard &amp; The Lizard Wizard - Polygondwanaland Mom Jeans. - Edward 40hands (Audiotree Live Version) Epica - Edge of the Blade Car Seat Headrest - Cute Thing Prince Daddy &amp; the Hyena - I thought You Didn't Even Like Leaving Death Grips - Get Got Blue Sky Black Death - And Stars, Ringed McCafferty - Becky REOL - 宵々古今 Bent Knee - Terror Bird Julien Baker - Blacktop Joji - Will He Totorro - Saveur Cheveux Epica - Universal Death Squad Car Seat Headrest - Nervous Young Humans Graduating Life - There's Only One Way Alice Merton - No Roots tricot - Tobe McCafferty - Real Adult Sorority Noise - No Halo Alexisonfire - Accidents Modern Baseball - The Waterboy Returns Metronomy - Radio Ladio Biffy Clyro - Glitter And Trauma Epica - Wings of Freedom Death Grips - I Break Mirrors With My Face Graduating Life - Kill Me The New Law - End World 88rising, Joji, Rich Brian, Higher Brothers, AUGUST 08 - Midsummer Madness Mom Jeans. - near death fail comp (must watch til end) Fall Out Boy - Saturday Hobo Johnson - Sex in the City Prince Daddy &amp; the Hyena - Clever Girl Mitski - Why Didn't You Stop Me? Veil Of Maya - Lull Alexisonfire - A Dagger Through The Heart of St Angeles Cap'n Jazz - Basil's Kite Elephant Gym - 中途 mouse on the keys - leviathan REOL - コノヨ Loading... Mom Jeans. - sponsor me tape tricot - Pool Moe Shop, YUC'e - Baby Pink Blue Sky Black Death - Sleeping Children Are Still Flying King Gizzard &amp; The Lizard Wizard - The Castle in the Air Prince Daddy &amp; the Hyena - Thrashville 1/3 McCafferty - Beachboy Mitski - Old Friend Elijah Who - crush on you Save Us from the Archon - All I Want Is Sleep REOL - ギミアブレスタッナウ Snowing - I Think We're in Minsk Bring Me The Horizon - (I Used To Make Out With) Medusa Car Seat Headrest - We Can't Afford (Your Depression Anymore) mouse on the keys - i shut my eyes in order to see Kanye West - I Thought About Killing You Glocca Morra - Ya'll Boots Hats? (Die Angry) McCafferty - Skeleton Bones Epica - A Phantasmic Parade Totorro - Chevalier Bulltoe Infected Mushroom - Flamingo Modern Baseball - ...And Beyond Julien Baker - Sprained Ankle Mom Jeans., Graduating Life - Shred Cruz Starcrawler - I Love LA Veil Of Maya - Doublespeak Pictures of Vernon - The Sunshine Bus Death Grips - The Fever (Aye Aye) McCafferty - Bottles and Cans Bent Knee - Hole Totorro - Home Alone tricot - On the boom (Audiotree Live Version) Alexisonfire - Counterparts And Number Them Car Seat Headrest - Fill in the Blank 88rising, Joji, BlocBoy JB - Peach Jam Microwave - Homebody Taking Back Sunday - Cute Without The 'E' (Cut From The Team) Shoutout to Mom Jeans./Graduating Life for making Shred Cruz, a song that got on the list twice!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build All The Things II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/05/build-all-the-things-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build All The Things II" /><published>2018-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/05/build-all-the-things-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/05/build-all-the-things-ii">&lt;p&gt;
  First small Python programme written! It is pretty easy to output just 'hello
  world', so I did it three different ways. I learned about:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Importing modules;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Tuples, lists and sets;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How to sort and remove duplicates from a list;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Using sys.stdout.write vs print().
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Personally I think this is a good start, especially for half an hour's work.
  Here's the code, check it works!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;
    &lt;code&gt;
      import sys

      print('hello world')

      characters = [ 'h', 'e', 'l', 'l', 'o', ' ', 'w', 'o', 'r', 'l', 'd']
      for x in characters:
          sys.stdout.write(x)

      sorted_characters = list(set(characters))
      sorted_characters.sort()
      print(&quot;&quot;)
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[3])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[2])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[4])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[4])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[5])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[0])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[7])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[5])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[6])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[4])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[1])
    &lt;/code&gt;
  &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Software Engineering" /><summary type="html">First small Python programme written! It is pretty easy to output just 'hello world', so I did it three different ways. I learned about: Importing modules; Tuples, lists and sets; How to sort and remove duplicates from a list; Using sys.stdout.write vs print(). Personally I think this is a good start, especially for half an hour's work. Here's the code, check it works! import sys</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build All The Things</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/04/build-all-the-things" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build All The Things" /><published>2018-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/04/build-all-the-things</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/04/build-all-the-things">&lt;p&gt;
  I want to learn Python. I am bored of putting it off and saying to myself that
  I will learn it at some unspecified point in the future. So, I want to learn Python
  now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are two problems with this. Firstly, my attention span and concentration
  are both awful at the moment. Watching video tutorials and learning anything from them
  is going to be nearly impossible. Secondly, I have no time. I used to say that
  as a kind of excuse, really I had plenty of time, I just chose to spend it playing
  video games (which I still think is a perfectly valid way of spending one's time,
  if you make the active choice to prioritise it over other things). Now, I really
  do have no time - my entire week is divided into sleeping, the gym, working,
  and enough self-care time to stop me losing my mind. There's virtually no wiggle
  room. So, again, even if I could make myself absorb videos - I don't have the time
  to sit and watch them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So... the solution I'm going to attempt to use to solve the problem is 'just in time
  learning'. I am going to try and build as many things as possible in Python, each
  one hopefully adding more complexity or exploring a new aspect of the language.
  Rather than learn any of it beforehand, I am going to try to learn exactly
  as much as I need to solve each problem as it arises, meaning I get to immediately
  apply anything and everything I learn to a practical coding scenario. Naturally
  I will have to try to reduce every problem down to its smallest possible constituent
  parts, a skill that will have a meaningful crossover to other languages.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Honestly, this might be a terrible way to learn a language, it's something
  that I don't feel gets advocated for very much. But maybe it'll be fun, and
  maybe it'll be better than the traditional way. Tomorrow I'll post my &lt;code&gt;hello_world&lt;/code&gt;
  programme.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Software Engineering" /><summary type="html">I want to learn Python. I am bored of putting it off and saying to myself that I will learn it at some unspecified point in the future. So, I want to learn Python now. There are two problems with this. Firstly, my attention span and concentration are both awful at the moment. Watching video tutorials and learning anything from them is going to be nearly impossible. Secondly, I have no time. I used to say that as a kind of excuse, really I had plenty of time, I just chose to spend it playing video games (which I still think is a perfectly valid way of spending one's time, if you make the active choice to prioritise it over other things). Now, I really do have no time - my entire week is divided into sleeping, the gym, working, and enough self-care time to stop me losing my mind. There's virtually no wiggle room. So, again, even if I could make myself absorb videos - I don't have the time to sit and watch them. So... the solution I'm going to attempt to use to solve the problem is 'just in time learning'. I am going to try and build as many things as possible in Python, each one hopefully adding more complexity or exploring a new aspect of the language. Rather than learn any of it beforehand, I am going to try to learn exactly as much as I need to solve each problem as it arises, meaning I get to immediately apply anything and everything I learn to a practical coding scenario. Naturally I will have to try to reduce every problem down to its smallest possible constituent parts, a skill that will have a meaningful crossover to other languages. Honestly, this might be a terrible way to learn a language, it's something that I don't feel gets advocated for very much. But maybe it'll be fun, and maybe it'll be better than the traditional way. Tomorrow I'll post my hello_world programme.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">David Goggins</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/03/david-goggins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="David Goggins" /><published>2018-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/03/david-goggins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/03/david-goggins">&lt;p&gt;
  This weekend I decided I should try and catch up on some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  JRE episodes,&lt;/a&gt; and I wound up watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/5tSTk1083VY&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  this one,&lt;/a&gt; with David Goggins.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  His story is obviously incredible - a complete 'nobody' who turned his life wholly
  around to become an accomplished ultramarathon runner, one of the military's elite,
  and the world record holder for most pull-ups in 24 hours. He claims he isn't
  a genetic freak, he is simply someone who worked incredibly hard and was able
  to mentally push himself far past his perceived limit - in fact he coined the now-famous
  '40% rule', the idea that you believe you're 'done' when you're actually at about
  40% of your maximum. He is certainly motivational, and anyone who watches the
  podcast will inevitably be inspired to go for a run immediately afterwards.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But... is there anything meaningful I can actually glean from this? If we assume
  our common goal is maximumising our own happiness (using that word in a fairly
  broad context, to include content, fulfillment, self-worth etc), what can I apply
  from his story to mine? I don't think becoming an ultra runner is going to provide
  a good payoff in terms of effort to reward for me. Everyone around him had no
  expectations of him, and he was determined to prove them wrong, however I feel
  like people around me have high expectations of me, and I am terrified of not
  meeting them. Would achieving or even surpassing those expectations be that
  satisfying? I don't want to dedicate my time to someone else's goals.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Should I throw myself into working, pushing through the mental anguish of burnout
  and stress the same way he pushed through the pain of broken bones and internal
  bleeding? If I ascend to becoming a god-tier programmer one day, on Linus Torvalds'
  speed dial, would I look back and be proud of what I had accomplished in the
  same way that he is? Knowing that I did it, purely to prove to myself that I could?
  I'm not sure. Would I sacrifice other things in my life for this, that could potentially
  make me happy? How am I meant to prioritise? Can I still live a noble, worthy life
  by pursuing balance?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  That's only really the start of the questions I have been asking myself in the wake
  of the podcast. Is his story nothing but inspiration porn? Is he perpetuating
  toxic masculinity? Because if so, then he is very convincing, and I am compelled
  to pursue mental and physical fortitude, to outdo my peers, to fight my demons
  alone and win.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I don't really know. I think if there is one thing I am going to take away from
  it, it's this: fuck my comfort zone. I need to leave it more often, and wander
  as far off into the horizon as I can.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">This weekend I decided I should try and catch up on some JRE episodes, and I wound up watching this one, with David Goggins. His story is obviously incredible - a complete 'nobody' who turned his life wholly around to become an accomplished ultramarathon runner, one of the military's elite, and the world record holder for most pull-ups in 24 hours. He claims he isn't a genetic freak, he is simply someone who worked incredibly hard and was able to mentally push himself far past his perceived limit - in fact he coined the now-famous '40% rule', the idea that you believe you're 'done' when you're actually at about 40% of your maximum. He is certainly motivational, and anyone who watches the podcast will inevitably be inspired to go for a run immediately afterwards. But... is there anything meaningful I can actually glean from this? If we assume our common goal is maximumising our own happiness (using that word in a fairly broad context, to include content, fulfillment, self-worth etc), what can I apply from his story to mine? I don't think becoming an ultra runner is going to provide a good payoff in terms of effort to reward for me. Everyone around him had no expectations of him, and he was determined to prove them wrong, however I feel like people around me have high expectations of me, and I am terrified of not meeting them. Would achieving or even surpassing those expectations be that satisfying? I don't want to dedicate my time to someone else's goals. Should I throw myself into working, pushing through the mental anguish of burnout and stress the same way he pushed through the pain of broken bones and internal bleeding? If I ascend to becoming a god-tier programmer one day, on Linus Torvalds' speed dial, would I look back and be proud of what I had accomplished in the same way that he is? Knowing that I did it, purely to prove to myself that I could? I'm not sure. Would I sacrifice other things in my life for this, that could potentially make me happy? How am I meant to prioritise? Can I still live a noble, worthy life by pursuing balance? That's only really the start of the questions I have been asking myself in the wake of the podcast. Is his story nothing but inspiration porn? Is he perpetuating toxic masculinity? Because if so, then he is very convincing, and I am compelled to pursue mental and physical fortitude, to outdo my peers, to fight my demons alone and win. I don't really know. I think if there is one thing I am going to take away from it, it's this: fuck my comfort zone. I need to leave it more often, and wander as far off into the horizon as I can.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Upgrade and Compromise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/02/upgrade-and-compromise" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Upgrade and Compromise" /><published>2018-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/02/upgrade-and-compromise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/02/upgrade-and-compromise">&lt;p&gt;
  As I'm sure you have noticed, today the site has an exciting new feature - colour!
  There is actually a slightly less obvious, but equally exciting, new feature that
  I have added today as well, which is a JavaScript file. I'd like to talk
  a bit about why I decided to add these two things to my site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Both new additions actually have a common objective, that of improving accessibility.
  In my opinion, accessibility is overlooked by a very large number of web devs,
  and there isn't really a good excuse for it. All that is required to make a site
  accessible is some education and a tiny amount of time, and if a site is built
  with accessibility in mind, the extra effort is negligible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The problem with my lovely CSS-only hamburger menus and accordions was that they
  were completely un-navigable with only a keyboard. Their current JavaScript-enhanced
  iterations aren't much better, but when I next have some time to work on the site,
  the improvements will allow full, and hopefully easy, keyboard navigation of
  the site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My monochrome design choices may have fit my minimalist &lt;span style=&quot;white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;【﻿ａｅｓｔｈｅｔｉｃ】&lt;/span&gt; but
  a lot of the greys had poor colour-contrast, and my link styles were confusing and
  inconsistent. Now, with only a primary and alternate colour,
  every link on the site should look the same &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they are suitably
  different from regular text.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There is an element of compromise here - any JavaScript added will slow the
  performance of my site (although I have only added 15 or so lines so far, so
  the degradation will be infinitesimal), and I can no longer say the site is a
  no-JS-zone. With regards to the colours, I am not entirely sold on the actual
  hues I picked, at least not yet. It was a pretty tough decision, I wanted to pick ones
  that had solid contrast and were complementary, and avoid blue because everything
  on the internet is blue... Perhaps they will grow on me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The next wave of upgrades for this site will be to make it compliant with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  WCAG 2.0 AA&lt;/a&gt; standard. I am hopefully most of the way there already, but I
  am quite excited for the additional challenge, and I think I will learn a lot
  on the way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have made these changes to the site because I believe the web should be for
  everyone, and developers have a responsibility to cater for anyone who wants
  or needs to use their site.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">As I'm sure you have noticed, today the site has an exciting new feature - colour! There is actually a slightly less obvious, but equally exciting, new feature that I have added today as well, which is a JavaScript file. I'd like to talk a bit about why I decided to add these two things to my site. Both new additions actually have a common objective, that of improving accessibility. In my opinion, accessibility is overlooked by a very large number of web devs, and there isn't really a good excuse for it. All that is required to make a site accessible is some education and a tiny amount of time, and if a site is built with accessibility in mind, the extra effort is negligible. The problem with my lovely CSS-only hamburger menus and accordions was that they were completely un-navigable with only a keyboard. Their current JavaScript-enhanced iterations aren't much better, but when I next have some time to work on the site, the improvements will allow full, and hopefully easy, keyboard navigation of the site. My monochrome design choices may have fit my minimalist 【﻿ａｅｓｔｈｅｔｉｃ】 but a lot of the greys had poor colour-contrast, and my link styles were confusing and inconsistent. Now, with only a primary and alternate colour, every link on the site should look the same and they are suitably different from regular text. There is an element of compromise here - any JavaScript added will slow the performance of my site (although I have only added 15 or so lines so far, so the degradation will be infinitesimal), and I can no longer say the site is a no-JS-zone. With regards to the colours, I am not entirely sold on the actual hues I picked, at least not yet. It was a pretty tough decision, I wanted to pick ones that had solid contrast and were complementary, and avoid blue because everything on the internet is blue... Perhaps they will grow on me. The next wave of upgrades for this site will be to make it compliant with the WCAG 2.0 AA standard. I am hopefully most of the way there already, but I am quite excited for the additional challenge, and I think I will learn a lot on the way. I have made these changes to the site because I believe the web should be for everyone, and developers have a responsibility to cater for anyone who wants or needs to use their site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Too Fast</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/01/too-fast" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Too Fast" /><published>2018-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/01/too-fast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/01/too-fast">&lt;p&gt;
  Today has gone by too fast... I had so much I wanted to do. And I haven't spent
  any time frivously I don't think, no games, no Youtube videos, just productivity, the gym
  and socialising out with a friend, something that seems important for my health.
  But I am exhausted (again) and feel like I haven't made a dent in my to-do list
  for the weekend. If only there were more hours in the day... Time to try again
  tomorrow.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today has gone by too fast... I had so much I wanted to do. And I haven't spent any time frivously I don't think, no games, no Youtube videos, just productivity, the gym and socialising out with a friend, something that seems important for my health. But I am exhausted (again) and feel like I haven't made a dent in my to-do list for the weekend. If only there were more hours in the day... Time to try again tomorrow.</summary></entry></feed>