<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-20T18:23:01+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Treasured Memories</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/20/treasured-memories" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Treasured Memories" /><published>2019-08-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/20/treasured-memories</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/20/treasured-memories">&lt;p&gt;While in the pub on Friday, I took it upon myself to try and stimulate some more interesting conversation amongst my male friends, instead of the usual soporific chat about work or cars or boats or some shit. In an effort to coax something vaguely resembling vulnerability out of them, I turned to my favourite source of disarming queries, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://36questionsinlove.com/&quot;&gt;36 questions for love&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to have a crack at number 18 - “what is your most treasured memory?” - but was met with no substantive answer from any of the parties present. I find it hard to believe that it’s possible for somebody to have &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; treasured memories, so decided that they were perhaps merely reluctant to be forthcoming about them, and maybe if I offered some experiences of my own, they might be more willing to reciprocate. So, here are 10 of my most treasured memories, in  vaguely chronological order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;skiing-in-wengenjungfrau-region-with-fleur&quot;&gt;Skiing in Wengen/Jungfrau Region with Fleur&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went skiing with my family every Christmas for 15 years or so in Wengen, Switzerland, and did most of it with the English speaking Downhill Only club, where I was lucky enough to meet Fleur. Both our families would spend the same weeks there for a few years, and so I got to know her pretty well, and I have some very fond memories of skiing and chatting with her. Her cynicism and dry wit, combined with painful intelligence, were all things I sought to emulate and I think she likely had a significant effect on how my personality developed as I grew up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-kiss-with-rozelle&quot;&gt;First kiss with Rozelle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has that one person they fall hopelessly in love with when they first go through puberty, and it’s all a bit of a mess. Rozelle was absolutely that person for me, and I was as besotted as only a teenager can be, and I still remember the first time she kissed me, up against the sadly-now-removed swing set outside the Peninsula Hotel, at goodness knows what time in the morning. I’ve been chasing the butterflies I felt then ever since, having success on only a handful of rare occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beating-toby-at-chess-10th-march-2009&quot;&gt;Beating Toby at chess, 10th March 2009&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think of all the games of chess I have played in my life, this is fairly comfortably my favourite. At 14, playing in the top division of Guernsey’s chess league, beating Toby was the first time I’d beaten a titled player (admittedly he’s ‘only’ a candidate master, but that counts in my book). My chess trajectory was at its highest after that game, and I still remember the feeling of anticipation when I won a pawn, then a second, then liquidated into an endgame with such a big advantage I knew there was no way I was going to mess it up. I was shaking, it was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beating-fareed-and-ben-in-the-debating-cup&quot;&gt;Beating Fareed and Ben in the Debating Cup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My school-long rivalry with Fareed was pretty disgusting when I think about it, and something I am gently ashamed of, although I don’t think either of us could really be blamed for it. We were of course products of environment, and that environment very much encouraged competition and egoism, so we went to war, determined to show our teachers and peers that we were the quickest thinking, most silver tongued pretentious twats in the entire school. One of the greatest victories I ever scored against him was beating him in the semi final of the senior debating cup, having lost to him the year before. Sadly I can’t remember what the motion was, but I do remember shouting ‘come on!’ in celebration when our names were announced winners, as a true testament to my lack of composure in that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seeing-foo-fighters-with-jack&quot;&gt;Seeing Foo Fighters with Jack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the last night of Reading Festival 2012, I was lucky enough to watch the Foo Fighters headline the main stage with Jack. A few beers in, totally exhausted but determined to enjoy the dying hours of our weekend, things suddenly became very emotional when the rest of the band paused momentarily took a backseat as Dave Grohl strummed an acoustic guitar while recounting stories of being in Nirvana and knowing Kurt Cobain. As someone moved by Cobain’s story, that night felt like something special, as if we were all part of something much bigger, all connected through Grohl’s reminiscence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beating-york-including-higgs-at-roses&quot;&gt;Beating York (including Higgs) at Roses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I fenced for the uni, I was always the weakest member on the strongest team, which meant I felt a lot of pressure to perform. The sabreurs always had to carry the weaker foilists and epeeists if we were to have any chance of winning, and our annual varsity match against York, dubbed Roses after the war over 550 years prior, was no different. Lancaster won the toss and so got to decide the match order, and as usual the sabre match would be last, and would decide the outcome of the entire day. When it came down to us, we needed to beat the York sabreurs by 45 to 8 or more in order to win, with 45-9 being a draw. On home soil, with a Lancaster crowd cheering us on, I managed to fight through my nerves and helped the team win 45-6, the biggest margin of victory I’d ever been part of in a team match. For the day, we were heroes, and the party afterwards was electric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;driving-from-edinburgh-to-st-andrews-with-nick&quot;&gt;Driving from Edinburgh to St Andrews with Nick&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having not had much experience with driving anywhere other than Guernsey, on our second Poole-to-Scotland road trip I really fell in love with cruising through the countryside, very much so while navigating the B roads between Edinburgh and St Andrews in the snow. The Scottish scenery is unbelievably beautiful, there was nobody else on the roads, and we were strictly adhering to the speed limit. Probably. It was a wonderful experience with one of my best friends, and I won’t forget it in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meditating-at-cheesters-with-ted-and-mica&quot;&gt;Meditating at Cheesters with Ted and Mica&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While living in Mexico in 2017 with Ted and Mica, we all at various points were engaged in some form of meditation challenge with one another. As a trio we were all determined to do at least 30 minutes a day, and so when an evening downpour trapped us beneath an umbrella in Cheesters restaurant, we elected to simply meditate there and then, until the storm had passed. The feeling of closing one’s eyes and remaining completely still for 30 minutes in the middle of a public space was exhilarating, I could feel my cheeks burning bright red and my heart pound. I had never been more aware of my place in relation to my surroundings, arguably the point of meditation. It was a unique experience which I would highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seeing-car-seat-headrest-with-fi&quot;&gt;Seeing Car Seat Headrest with Fi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the chance to see Car Seat Headrest live in Kentish Town on my birthday last year, with one of my oldest and dearest friends Fiona. CSH are a band that have meant a lot to me for several years, the music and lyrics of frontman Will Toledo are ones that I empathise strongly with, and have brought me a lot of comfort and hope during my time listening to them. To see Will and the boys in the flesh, with 1000 like minded fans screaming all the words alongside me, alongside someone I love and care about deeply, was the perfect birthday present for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-brass-monkeysome-random-sports-bar-in-manhattanthe-subway-and-walk-back-to-astoria-with-polly&quot;&gt;The Brass Monkey/some random sports bar in Manhattan/the subway and walk back to Astoria with Polly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My trip to New York earlier this year was a life changing experience, and picking just one moment from it for this list was very difficult, as I treasure the entire duration of the trip. Our
last full day there was the pièce de résistance of our journey in my mind. Having spent 10 whole days together at this point, Polly and I had grown to know each other unusually well in such a short space of time, and already felt like best friends as we headed into Manhattan to sample more of its watering holes. The drinks flowed, radically honest conversations were had, we drunkenly held hands in the Brass Monkey, and she sung to me in the middle of the subway on the way home. It was the perfect end to the perfect trip.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">While in the pub on Friday, I took it upon myself to try and stimulate some more interesting conversation amongst my male friends, instead of the usual soporific chat about work or cars or boats or some shit. In an effort to coax something vaguely resembling vulnerability out of them, I turned to my favourite source of disarming queries, the 36 questions for love. I decided to have a crack at number 18 - “what is your most treasured memory?” - but was met with no substantive answer from any of the parties present. I find it hard to believe that it’s possible for somebody to have no treasured memories, so decided that they were perhaps merely reluctant to be forthcoming about them, and maybe if I offered some experiences of my own, they might be more willing to reciprocate. So, here are 10 of my most treasured memories, in vaguely chronological order:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alcohol IV</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/18/alcohol-iv" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alcohol IV" /><published>2019-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/18/alcohol-iv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/18/alcohol-iv">&lt;p&gt;When I have finished the (admittedly rather large) glass of wine on my desk, I will
have drunk my supply of alcohol at home clean, and subsequently plan on giving up alcohol
for the foreseeable future, although unlikely forever. Despite enjoying greatly the conversations and experiences it enables me to have, I am hopeful that it’s mere removal
from my weekly routine will aid weight loss efforts, and there will surely be other health
benefits too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is going to make socialising different, and more effort, but perhaps this is not a bad thing. If I have inhibitions about expressing something, I am going to have to overcome
them while stone cold sober. Vulnerability and radical honesty are the orders of the day,
and now it’s time to get better at making them a habit, rather than just something after a 
few drinks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Health and Fitness" /><summary type="html">When I have finished the (admittedly rather large) glass of wine on my desk, I will have drunk my supply of alcohol at home clean, and subsequently plan on giving up alcohol for the foreseeable future, although unlikely forever. Despite enjoying greatly the conversations and experiences it enables me to have, I am hopeful that it’s mere removal from my weekly routine will aid weight loss efforts, and there will surely be other health benefits too.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Reviews&amp;amp;colon; We Should All Be Feminists by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/17/book-reviews-we-should-all-be-feminists-by-chimamanda-ngozi-adichie" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Reviews&amp;colon; We Should All Be Feminists by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie" /><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/17/book-reviews-we-should-all-be-feminists-by-chimamanda-ngozi-adichie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/17/book-reviews-we-should-all-be-feminists-by-chimamanda-ngozi-adichie">&lt;p&gt;In a bid to not wait 6 months in between actually finishing books, I decided to read something
a lot shorter and less Russian, and was &lt;del&gt;forced&lt;/del&gt; recommended to read We Should All Be Feminists
by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichi. Jokes aside, the book is not one I would normally have elected to read, but reading outside of one’s habitual literary bubble can be a good thing, and I think
in this instance it certainly was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the book’s brevity, it makes some excellent points, in a very succint way, and invited
me to consider some of the issues involved in ways that I had not done so before. Firstly,
gender inequality is far deeper ingrained in our society than I had previously thought, and
often manifests itself in subtle ways that seem completely normal to me, but are in fact
legitimately damaging to women. Many men (and perhaps even some women), myself included, are
conditioned to turn a blind eye to these, but once you start looking for them, they’re everywhere, and permeate the vast majority of interactions and scenarios that one has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second was that feminism serves a purpose for men too. The role men are forced to play in
society sucks, not as much as it does for women, but it still sucks nonetheless. Masculine
expectations of bravado, stoicism and status hurt every man they touch, whether they realise
it or not. I hate many aspects of the norms I feel compelled to conform to as a man. I want
to paint my nails, to sing in falsetto, to wear pink, to wear eyeliner, to talk about my feelings, to be able to cry in public relatively unashamed, to have the option of giving up
my career for my prospective children without being judged for it. Probably a million other things. Men are taught to be tough, impassable, pugnacious, proud creatures, but I am fundamentally brittle and sick of pretending otherwise. Feminism can help rid me of these
things just as much as it can about positive change for women too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is a selfish take on the book, but perhaps I am a selfish kinda guy. In the near
future I’d like to write more about why men should be feminists, because I think I finally
feel comfortable calling myself one. 9/10 book, and you can blitz through it in half an hour,
absolutely recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books read this year: 4/52&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next book (not that I ever stick to these): Women &amp;amp; Power, A Manifesto by Mary Beard&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Feminism" /><category term="Book Reviews" /><summary type="html">In a bid to not wait 6 months in between actually finishing books, I decided to read something a lot shorter and less Russian, and was forced recommended to read We Should All Be Feminists by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichi. Jokes aside, the book is not one I would normally have elected to read, but reading outside of one’s habitual literary bubble can be a good thing, and I think in this instance it certainly was.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seeing Yourself II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/16/seeing-yourself-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seeing Yourself II" /><published>2019-08-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/16/seeing-yourself-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/16/seeing-yourself-ii">&lt;p&gt;I feel a similar urge to Polly to disregard other’s opinions of myself - as acknowledged, it is widely touted as ‘good advice’, and 
it’s even something I’ve written about before, for example when reviewing &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson&quot;&gt;Models&lt;/a&gt; or talking about &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/10/i-miss-painting-my-nails&quot;&gt;painting my nails&lt;/a&gt;. It seems
a noble, admirable goal - to have one’s self worth defined purely internally, to be unswayable in one’s resolve to love oneself, to be… oh no. To be stoic. My least favourite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we learn to tune out criticism, it’s similarly easy to learn to tune out positive feedback about ourselves too. Whenever one of
my friends offers me something kind and loving about myself, I simply think “they have an obligation to be nice to me, they’re my
friend, they don’t really mean it” or “they obviously don’t know me that well or they wouldn’t say that about me” or one of a myriad of other rationalisations. With those thoughts, I pay their words no further heed. The only problem is that every so often, someone close to me will say something so genuine and pure to me that I am not able to dismiss it in this manner, and instead I burst into tears. I suspect this is rarely the reaction the other party was seeking or expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every scenario we’re faced with, we present some version of ourselves, which to a greater or lesser extent represents our ‘true’
selves. At work, or with strangers, we are very guarded, with a partner we are hopefully much more open. Some people put up more of 
a facade with their friends and family than other people, largely unconsciously keeping their walls raised, myself included for the
longest time. As these defences start to come down though, the feedback I get from people around me is a much more accurate reflection of who I am as a person - because I am more authentic in my relationships with those people who I’m vulnerable with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to practise telling the people that I love, that I love them, and why. If someone who I’m open and honest with says
something nice about me, I’m going to practice listening to and believing that as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I feel a similar urge to Polly to disregard other’s opinions of myself - as acknowledged, it is widely touted as ‘good advice’, and it’s even something I’ve written about before, for example when reviewing Models or talking about painting my nails. It seems a noble, admirable goal - to have one’s self worth defined purely internally, to be unswayable in one’s resolve to love oneself, to be… oh no. To be stoic. My least favourite.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seeing Yourself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/15/seeing-yourself" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seeing Yourself" /><published>2019-08-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/15/seeing-yourself</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/15/seeing-yourself">&lt;p&gt;In a first for the blog, today we have a guest writer. She is someone who continually inspires me and who I look up to immensely, and so I am beyond excited I managed to pester her into typing something up for me. On a topic that feels equally as relevant and important to me as it
seems to be to her, it is of course the fabled Polly Thompson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that we’re told a lot is that we should care less about what other people think about us. On one level I am totally onboard with this. Since leaving school I have spent a lot of time trying to build up my own identity and self-confidence in a way that relies less on other people’s validation. I think it has successfully made me more self-assured and maybe even happier. But I also find myself fearing compliments and the inevitable shallow ego boost they bring, reminding me how much progress I have to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been thinking about lots of things I once thought of in black and white and realising that possibly nothing is actually so clear-cut. I have thought a lot about the impact of other people on how we see and define ourselves. Being self-aware is hugely important, but other people play such a big role in informing you of how you come across, how your actions impact others, and revealing those sides of you you’re desperately trying to ignore. I’ve always thought of this in terms of constructive criticism. Recently I’ve realised it’s true for compliments and affection too. Someone close to you won’t say something nice unless they really mean it. They’ve just handed you something to love about yourself on a plate (easier said than done). I wish I was better at articulating what I love about the people I care about. I wish they all loved themselves as much as I love them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Guest Blogs" /><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">In a first for the blog, today we have a guest writer. She is someone who continually inspires me and who I look up to immensely, and so I am beyond excited I managed to pester her into typing something up for me. On a topic that feels equally as relevant and important to me as it seems to be to her, it is of course the fabled Polly Thompson.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I love you iii</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/14/i-love-you-iii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I love you iii" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/14/i-love-you-iii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/14/i-love-you-iii">&lt;p&gt;It’s nice to be right about things, and &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/05/03/i-love-you-ii&quot;&gt;back in May&lt;/a&gt; I was indeed right about how I would feel
this week. It’s important that some things are said, and all that’s important is that you say them, not what they might be met with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But equally, hearing it back is a pretty special feeling too. I hope Mica finally got what she wanted.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">It’s nice to be right about things, and back in May I was indeed right about how I would feel this week. It’s important that some things are said, and all that’s important is that you say them, not what they might be met with.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beware of Dog IV</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/13/beware-of-dog-iv" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beware of Dog IV" /><published>2019-08-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/13/beware-of-dog-iv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/13/beware-of-dog-iv">&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/02/beware-of-dog-iii&quot;&gt;the dog&lt;/a&gt; again today, for the first time
since January. No panic attack, no raised heartrate, no sweaty palms, nothing. A lot of progress has been made, and I’m glad I was reminded of that today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">I saw the dog again today, for the first time since January. No panic attack, no raised heartrate, no sweaty palms, nothing. A lot of progress has been made, and I’m glad I was reminded of that today.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Things I Wish I Knew When I Was Younger</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/12/things-i-wish-i-knew-when-i-was-younger" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Things I Wish I Knew When I Was Younger" /><published>2019-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/12/things-i-wish-i-knew-when-i-was-younger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/12/things-i-wish-i-knew-when-i-was-younger">&lt;p&gt;This post is in part written for my younger brother, and in part for my younger self. It contains some things I wish I’d known, or
perhaps believed, when I was a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;perspective-is-everything&quot;&gt;Perspective is everything&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an awful cliché, but I think most such clichés are imbued with a drop of the truth, this one especially so. A sense of perspective is important for a happy life, and in order to achieve that, it’s necessary to constantly re-evaluate and be mindful
of your current position. When faced with a seemingly impassable obstacle, it is easy to forget the previous occasions upon which
you did in fact overcome such an obstacle, and instead become mired in doubt and self pity over whether or not the problem before
you can be solved. The vast majority of your difficulties can and will be resolved - you just need to learn to take a step back and
realise that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-as-honest-as-you-possibly-can&quot;&gt;Be as honest as you possibly can&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not taught to be honest, especially about our feelings. We are taught from a young age that stoicism is the order of the day,
and displays of emotion are displays of weakness. Things are slowly changing, but we need to change faster, to quick on the uptake and ahead of the curve. The prospect of honesty is often terrifying, and I know all too well the feeling of fear that accompanies the
notion of being rejected by the people you care about once you reveal whatever it is that’s on your mind. Start small, but then get
big. Go first - be vulnerable with the people around you, and the ones worth being close to will reciprocate. Don’t worry about the 
other ones. Honesty will change your life immeasurably for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feel-your-feelings&quot;&gt;Feel your feelings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negative emotions are scary, but they serve a purpose, and another thing that we’re not taught is to embrace them. Not only is it OK
to feel sad or angry or lonely or anxious, it’s important, a necessary part of being a human. Those feelings will keep you from harm
when you listen to them, but if you try to run from them, they’ll eventually catch up with you in unpleasant and uncouth ways. It really is OK to cry, just let it all out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-outside&quot;&gt;Go outside&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going outside is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; underrated, especially in Guernsey. It’s so beautiful here, the fresh air will do you good, and if you go
walking on the cliffs early in the morning, you won’t even come across any people who so peskily cause you anxiety. The vitamin D will stop you getting so tired. Maybe you’ll even get a tan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;itll-be-ok---really&quot;&gt;It’ll be ok - really&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It often feels like the world is feeling down on us - but it really isn’t. Our safety net is comically large, and more of a safety
trampoline than anything. No matter how grim things may seem, there’s always a way out, and things will always get better. I promise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">This post is in part written for my younger brother, and in part for my younger self. It contains some things I wish I’d known, or perhaps believed, when I was a teenager.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Many Sheep Crossed The Bridge?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/11/how-many-sheep-crossed-the-bridge" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Many Sheep Crossed The Bridge?" /><published>2019-08-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/11/how-many-sheep-crossed-the-bridge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/11/how-many-sheep-crossed-the-bridge">&lt;p&gt;After dinner this evening, we played a game involving two fields, a bridge, several sheep and a lot of clapping. On every turn, one player tells a short story about why
the sheep are crossing the bridge to the other field this time, followed by pattern of claps (which can be of varying rhthyms and number), before asking the poor person
who does not understand the game how many sheep have crossed the bridge. If you have not played the game before, it is fairly inevitable that you will not be able to
grok the pattern without at least several tries, and the other players can choose to aid or hinder your ability to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was immensely frustrating, and I was fortunate not to be the primary target of the chiding involved. After a progressively bigger series of clues (and one pretty
big red herring), I finally figured it out, to no small amount of relief, and now I cannot wait to similarly taunt my own friends with the dumb sheep game.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Misc" /><summary type="html">After dinner this evening, we played a game involving two fields, a bridge, several sheep and a lot of clapping. On every turn, one player tells a short story about why the sheep are crossing the bridge to the other field this time, followed by pattern of claps (which can be of varying rhthyms and number), before asking the poor person who does not understand the game how many sheep have crossed the bridge. If you have not played the game before, it is fairly inevitable that you will not be able to grok the pattern without at least several tries, and the other players can choose to aid or hinder your ability to solve the problem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Super Meat Boy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/10/super-meat-boy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Super Meat Boy" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/10/super-meat-boy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/10/super-meat-boy">&lt;p&gt;Edmund McMillen’s 2010 indie platformer gem “Super Meat Boy” is almost certainly my favourite
indie title ever, at the very least it is the one that I have sunk the most hours into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s everything an indie game ought to be - relatively simple but exceptionally polished mechanics, great level design and a killer soundtrack. The minimal storyline doesn’t get in
the way of the fact that SMB is all about the gameplay, and trying to conquer it’s often
excruciatingly difficult selection of levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started it up again today, I was a little worried I’m going to get sucked in and sink another 100 hours into trying to 100% the Cotton Alley. If I start writing about how I haven’t been outside for days and can’t remember what any food other than ramen tastes like, send help…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><summary type="html">Edmund McMillen’s 2010 indie platformer gem “Super Meat Boy” is almost certainly my favourite indie title ever, at the very least it is the one that I have sunk the most hours into.</summary></entry></feed>