<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-04T19:33:54+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Slightly More Planned Year (So Far)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2019/08/04/the-slightly-more-planned-year-so-far" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Slightly More Planned Year (So Far)" /><published>2019-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2019/08/04/the-slightly-more-planned-year-so-far</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2019/08/04/the-slightly-more-planned-year-so-far">&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been a very long time since I wrote anything in this blog, and I think an update long overdue at this point. In December &lt;a href=&quot;/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year&quot;&gt;things were bleak&lt;/a&gt;, I was in a very dark place and had struggled for months with feeling like I couldn’t really talk to anyone about it. I was frustrated at the lack of progress with therapy, putting a huge amount of pressure on myself at work, and felt undateable and unloveable in my social life. I was scared, lonely, and desperately trying to find a way out that didn’t involve hurting everyone around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s obvious given that I am writing this now but fortunately I did find said escape route, and subsequently a lot has changed in a short space of time. It all started with a website (which I’m not going to link) devoted to the topic of suicide, discussing its many facets with as little judgment either way as possible. There were studies and statistics, discussion of different methods, ways to get help - the tone was meant to be impartial even though the subject is one of extreme taboo. After perusing through the areas of the site dedicated more to practicality than sentimentality, I decided to read the ‘my story’ section, written by the site’s creator. In it, he described his own unsuccessful attempt to take his life, and his long road to (relative) happiness. On paper, he had it all - a respected, well paying job, he was a handsome guy and in good shape so he got plenty of romantic interest, he had a great network of close friends around him. Or at least, so he thought. Some time after regaining consciousness following an overdose which was intended to be fatal, the individual in question eventually realised that the reason he was unable to contentment was because he was not himself with any of the people around him - he hid away his true feelings, his personality, the things which could have brought him a genuine connection with the people around him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh shit, I thought as I read it. It’s me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gauntlet had been laid down - to be authentic with the people around me. Not to pretend everything was fine; to express my emotions no matter how terrifying a prospect that may be. So slowly, painfully, I gave it a go with a couple of people, and lo and behold, they were both amazing about it. They listened to me, withheld any judgment, and helped pull me out of the hole I was mired in. Spurred on by this initial success, I became increasingly vulnerable with a larger number of people, and the result has been incredible - where I once felt totally isolated, now I have so many relationships that matter to me and that bring me happiness, it’s sometimes difficult to make enough time for all of them. I took the risk by telling the truth, and it has paid off a hundredfold, now I cannot espouse it’s value enough. Honesty has made me so happy in the past few months, and brought me closer to people now than I had previously thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, this year has gone significantly more to plan than last year. I’ve yet to get kicked out of the new flat which I moved into with Sam in January, and actually I’d like to think we’re rather good tenants. I was a little more realistic with my nest-flying plans this time around, so admittedly I am still living quite close to my folks, but the sense of freedom and autonomy that comes from living on my own once more has brought a certain peace and purpose to my life. I’ve got a new job, which I started in May, still following the developer path, but this time doing more software-based work and less on the web. The people there are lovely, the stack is powerful, a lot of the problems we’re solving are ones that interest me, and overall I’m very happy there - the stress levels are markedly lower, and it really feels like I have the rest of my life back. I’m sleeping better, eating better, and finding it easier to make time to see friends or go to the gym after work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job switch is one of two big, perhaps even life-changing events that have happened in the past 7 months, the other being my somewhat well documented trip to New York. That experience was one that I hope will never forget, and the connections that I strengthened and made while I was there were so strong and brought me so much joy, that they really solidified for me what I suspected when I read that story of recovering from a failed suicide all those months ago - that what will make me happy in life, is other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confidence in myself gained on that transatlantic voyage translated into my once-barren dating life becoming rather spicier, and any notion of myself as unloveable has been swept back under the carpet. Furthermore, recent events have meant that my long-held belief (read: excuse) that if I want to attract the kind of people that I’d like to be in a relationship with then I’m going to have to lose weight/look different has similarly evaporated and I’m left with the slightly concerning byproduct that actually, there’s nothing wrong with me and maybe I could have a healthy relationship one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lifestyle has changed a lot too - it’s astounding how much of a difference not being miserable all the time will make when considering whether or not to go for a run, or see friends at the beach. For the past couple of months I have been out of the house with friends more evenings than not, and while the introvert in me is writhing in agony, he now occupies a far less significant portion of my consciousness than he needs in order to have a meaningful effect on my wellbeing. Guernsey is beautiful - the sun, the sea, the beaches - and I have taken them far too granted for the majority of my life. My friends are all beautiful too, even though they all have their fair share of flaws (not least having poor taste in company); now I am in a better place, connecting with them has been easier and more rewarding than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes, things are going well, and I hope it does not come across as some kind of brag, because I really don’t want to be that kind of person. The aim is very much more that it serves as an example of how things can get a lot better in a very short space of time, even when the present situation may be dire, and that there’s great importance in not giving up hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still work to be done though. While it’s important to acknowledge that progress has been made, and to revel in that, it would be naive to think that that is the end of the story, that I am now destined to ride off into the sunset on my horse made of pure serotonin. I’m acutely aware that my current state of relative wellbeing may be precariously balanced atop a run of fortunate life events, and while I have the motivation to do so, I ought to put preventative measures into place to avoid any future backsliding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been plenty of moments where I have felt the spindly fingers of anxiety wrapping themselves around my brain, or I’ve been unsure of how to handle a problem and the ever-present solution of yeeting myself off a cliff has re-emerged in my otherwise serene thought processes. The latter is no longer a valid option though, and while I am going to allow myself to feel anxiety when it’s appropriate, I’m not going to let it control me like it used to. My relationships, both with other people and myself, will always need active and frequent work, and I still want to try every day to push to be a better person lest I stagnate in my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I am feeling better in myself, I want to devote more of my time and effort to standing up for the causes I believe in, and to finding a hill to die on. Wanting to be accepted by everyone around you is fine when you hate yourself and need the validation, but once you love yourself, if you don’t fight for what you think is right then you’re failing at the very thing I said was what made me happy: being honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know what form all this is going to take yet. Maybe I’ll write a tonne of preachy blog posts about social equality, maybe I’ll become a vegan, maybe I’ll start a punk band and write lyrics about The Man. All I know is that it’s not enough to do nothing anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Well, it’s been a very long time since I wrote anything in this blog, and I think an update long overdue at this point. In December things were bleak, I was in a very dark place and had struggled for months with feeling like I couldn’t really talk to anyone about it. I was frustrated at the lack of progress with therapy, putting a huge amount of pressure on myself at work, and felt undateable and unloveable in my social life. I was scared, lonely, and desperately trying to find a way out that didn’t involve hurting everyone around me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Honesty II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/03/radical-honesty-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Honesty II" /><published>2019-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/03/radical-honesty-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/03/radical-honesty-ii">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2017/10/17/radical-honesty&quot;&gt;Radical Honesty&lt;/a&gt; has been both on my mind and my lips a lot recently. After having conversations about it with some of my favourite people in the world I think I am onboard with it than ever - perhaps
still not fullblown, yes-you-do-look-fat-in-that-dress honesty, but certainly &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/05/03/i-love-you-ii&quot;&gt;I-love-you&lt;/a&gt; honesty. The kind where you have difficult conversations when they’re important,
even if you’re nervous, the kind where you’re unashamed to tell someone how you feel about them, the kind where you have no secrets, you own everything you say, do and feel. The expected value is off the charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now the blog is back, I’d like to recommit myself to writing uncomfortably, painfully honestly here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Radical Honesty has been both on my mind and my lips a lot recently. After having conversations about it with some of my favourite people in the world I think I am onboard with it than ever - perhaps still not fullblown, yes-you-do-look-fat-in-that-dress honesty, but certainly I-love-you honesty. The kind where you have difficult conversations when they’re important, even if you’re nervous, the kind where you’re unashamed to tell someone how you feel about them, the kind where you have no secrets, you own everything you say, do and feel. The expected value is off the charts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">50 Ways To Show Someone You Love Them Without Having Sex</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/02/50-ways-to-show-someone-you-love-them-without-having-sex" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="50 Ways To Show Someone You Love Them Without Having Sex" /><published>2019-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/02/50-ways-to-show-someone-you-love-them-without-having-sex</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/02/50-ways-to-show-someone-you-love-them-without-having-sex">&lt;p&gt;I’ve never spoken especially highly of the sex education I received at school, as frankly I feel like it left me wholly unprepared for the complex, emotional realities of sex itself. At the fairly young age of 13 or so, I distinctly remember the inhabitants of our
all male form being handed out purple leaflets, emblazoned with the religion-reminiscent heading ‘50 ways to show someone you love them without having sex’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now here’s the thing. I can’t remember 49 of the things on the list - I’m sure I could hazard a guess and probably get some obvious ones, hold hands, cook them dinner etc etc. But there is one I very explicitly do remember, as something I thought of as bizarre and uncouth over 10 years ago, and my opinion is little changed since - cut their toenails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite not knowing what any of them are, I am confident in saying that I would do any of the remaining 49 displays of affection before I would cut someone else’s toenails. And I would definitely, definitely have sex with them first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is the new bar I should set for trying to find a life partner - somebody I love so much, I’d happily cut their toenails?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Relationships" /><summary type="html">I’ve never spoken especially highly of the sex education I received at school, as frankly I feel like it left me wholly unprepared for the complex, emotional realities of sex itself. At the fairly young age of 13 or so, I distinctly remember the inhabitants of our all male form being handed out purple leaflets, emblazoned with the religion-reminiscent heading ‘50 ways to show someone you love them without having sex’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What’re You Feeling?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/01/whatre-you-feeling" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What're You Feeling?" /><published>2019-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/01/whatre-you-feeling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/08/01/whatre-you-feeling">&lt;p&gt;Every so often when I’m chatting to slvrsluger, he’ll ask me what I’ve been thinking about recently. It’s a question I usually welcome, as it precedes many interesting conversations - I frequently have indeed had something on my mind recently, but it’s not always easy to steer a conversation towards a certain topic, especially if it has been a personal matter to me. Between men, we don’t
talk about our feelings you know, so this particular line of questioning can be a little disarming, undoubtedly a good thing in this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was recently suggested to me that the question ‘what are you feeling?’ could be a meaningful upgrade on the ‘what are you thinking?’ question, and I am inclined to agree. It serves a similar purpose, to surprise the questionee into displaying some vulnerability, but it is far more effective, and gives a lot less room to manouevre around the machismo-stoic response of ‘nothing’. 
Us men have a remarkable capacity to think nothing, but (at least in my experience) a greatly diminished ability to &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s going to be my new go-to. I feel… sleeeeeepy. But happy. What’re you feeling?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Every so often when I’m chatting to slvrsluger, he’ll ask me what I’ve been thinking about recently. It’s a question I usually welcome, as it precedes many interesting conversations - I frequently have indeed had something on my mind recently, but it’s not always easy to steer a conversation towards a certain topic, especially if it has been a personal matter to me. Between men, we don’t talk about our feelings you know, so this particular line of questioning can be a little disarming, undoubtedly a good thing in this scenario.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Hedonic Treadmill III</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/31/the-hedonic-treadmill-iii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Hedonic Treadmill III" /><published>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/31/the-hedonic-treadmill-iii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/31/the-hedonic-treadmill-iii">&lt;p&gt;Yet more thoughts on the HedTread, as I’ve decided I’m going to start calling it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it exists, would it really matter so much? My own fear of it comes from the idea that I mignt never completely shake off
my melancholic affliction, that any periods of happiness will inevitably be short-lived and that I’ll invariably slide backwards into
greyness. This is assuming that the HedTread refers to every human having an emotional baseline, with meaningful deviation thereof being impossible, and furthermore that my baseline is significantly below ‘contented’, but perhaps this is a flawed assumption. If
everybody has a default emotional state, perhaps it is simple contentment, neutrality, 0 on the y axis of the graph in my mind.
It seems possible that I’ve spent most of my life on some kind of reverse HedTread - perhaps attempting to run down an ascending
escalator of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If neutrality is indeed the norm, maybe striving to be happier without ever making much progress would not be such a bad thing.
As (I think) &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/20/book-reviews-notes-from-underground-by-fyodor-dostoevsky&quot;&gt;Dostoyevsky was getting at&lt;/a&gt;, working
towards a goal seems more fundamental to the human condition than actually achieving it. Chasing true happiness, no matter how unattainable, might give purpose to one’s life, and can there be anything more important in life than purpose? Happiness seems very much akin to enlightenment in this way - maybe there is a compelling argument to be made that they are in fact synonymous - and I’m sure many who are chasing nirvana understand that the journey is far more important than their impossible goal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Yet more thoughts on the HedTread, as I’ve decided I’m going to start calling it…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Hedonic Treadmill II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/30/the-hedonic-treadmill-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Hedonic Treadmill II" /><published>2019-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/30/the-hedonic-treadmill-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/30/the-hedonic-treadmill-ii">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing some more &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/06/28/the-hedonic-treadmill&quot;&gt;worrying about the hedonic treadmill&lt;/a&gt; recently, but I think I am slowly getting my head round it. I wrote
a while ago now about &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2017/11/01/problems&quot;&gt;struggles with relating to other people’s problems&lt;/a&gt;, but the key to hopping off the hedonic hamster wheel could lie in how I
relate to my own problems, and how I use them to inform my perspective on my current situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past this was very difficult - as I progressed through my teen years into adulthood, my problems seemed to get progressively more serious than their predecessors. I was no longer
worried about whether or not a girl thought I was cute, or if I was going to get in trouble for not doing my homework - suddenly I was facing the prospect of trying to attain a degree,
then find a job, then achieve and maintain financial independence and generally approximate being a functional adult human as best I could. It wasn’t exactly possible to look back
and think to myself that I had had it much worse in the past and survived, and should be grateful for what I had now, because I had more responsibility and more at stake than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not true anymore though. Even very recently &lt;a href=&quot;/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year&quot;&gt;I really wasn’t doing so good&lt;/a&gt;, but now a lot has changed for the better. I still have problems,
and negative feelings that arise as a result of them - the difference being that this time, my own recent past might offer an important lens through which to view the present. My struggles
now are undoubtedly not as great as they were even 9 months ago. So much has gone right for me in that time, and I have so many things to feel happy about, but as the treadmill notion suggests,
it’s not necessarily that easy. The goal for the near future is to focus as much as possible on what’s changed, and how I no longer feel like I did. Back then, I thought I would be over the
moon to be where I am today, and so it’s time to allow myself to feel like that and not worry too much about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I’ve been doing some more worrying about the hedonic treadmill recently, but I think I am slowly getting my head round it. I wrote a while ago now about struggles with relating to other people’s problems, but the key to hopping off the hedonic hamster wheel could lie in how I relate to my own problems, and how I use them to inform my perspective on my current situation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Climbing Progress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/29/climbing-progress" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Climbing Progress" /><published>2019-07-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/29/climbing-progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/29/climbing-progress">&lt;p&gt;At the expense of being preachy about my new active lifestyle as someone who both goes running &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; climbing, today I wanted to briefly mention
how great the latter is. I’ve been doing it for less than a month now, and during that time have already made some very satisfying beginner progress -
newbie gains for the win, and when you’re as bad as I am, the only way to go is up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I had the particularly rewarding experience of topping a route that I had worked on for the last 3 or 4 sessions, managing (eventually) do each move
but not quite being able to put them all together until this evening, admittedly with a little help from a more experienced climber. In any discipline
feeling that your efforts are being reward with a sense of improvement is intensely enjoyable, and it’s pretty neat how climbing provides you with a very
measurable way of seeing said improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to send the next route I’m working on, with a strong chance I brag about topping that when it happens as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Climbing" /><summary type="html">At the expense of being preachy about my new active lifestyle as someone who both goes running and climbing, today I wanted to briefly mention how great the latter is. I’ve been doing it for less than a month now, and during that time have already made some very satisfying beginner progress - newbie gains for the win, and when you’re as bad as I am, the only way to go is up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Reviews&amp;amp;colon; The Master and Margarita by Mikhail Bulgakov</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/28/book-reviews-the-master-and-margarita-by-mikhail-bulgakov" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Reviews&amp;colon; The Master and Margarita by Mikhail Bulgakov" /><published>2019-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/28/book-reviews-the-master-and-margarita-by-mikhail-bulgakov</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/28/book-reviews-the-master-and-margarita-by-mikhail-bulgakov">&lt;p&gt;Well, the whole 52 books in 52 weeks thing is looking admittedly unlikely to pan out, but I have nonetheless made some progress by finally finishing ‘The Master and Margarita’
by Mikhail Bulgakov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact it essentially took me 6 months to read, I thoroughly enjoyed Bulgakov’s magnum opus. Not published until 17 years after his death, and even then heavily censored, the novel can only really be described as absurd. Satan and a handful of his aides travel to Soviet Moscow and wreak havoc on its inhabitants, primarily its literary elite, through the use of transforming banknotes and disappearing dresses,
prophecies of imminent death and Behemoth, the black cat who frequently clutches a gun in his paw. All the while, Bulgakov also gives his own version of events surrounding the execution of Jesus, or Yeshua as he is
in the book, retold with Pontius Pilate seemingly the protagonist and Yeshua having only a lone disciple in Levi Matthew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very hard to ‘review’ this book, because it is truely so bizarre, and I have never read anything like it. It was a phenomenal read, perhaps because of its oddities rather than in spite of them. Trying to
extract some kind of allegory or overarching message from the story is a job for a far greater intellect than me, but I cannot recommend it strongly enough purely as a romp through the ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9/10, a sensational read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books read this year: 3/52&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next book: Moscow to the End of the Line by Benedict Erofeev&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">Well, the whole 52 books in 52 weeks thing is looking admittedly unlikely to pan out, but I have nonetheless made some progress by finally finishing ‘The Master and Margarita’ by Mikhail Bulgakov.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iNcontroL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/27/incontrol" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iNcontroL" /><published>2019-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/27/incontrol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/27/incontrol">&lt;p&gt;Geoff Robinson, better known by his screenname, ‘iNcontroL’ passed away on July 20th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I’d never really understood why people get upset when a celebrity they’ve never met dies. But now, I think I sort of get it. Waking up to read the news that iNcontroL had died was a total shock to me, so much so that I didn’t initially think it could be real, like many others in the Starcraft community of which Geoff was a part for almost 20 years. He was only 33 years old when he suffered a pulmonary embolism which took his life with virtually no warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoff was a big part of why I got hooked on esports years ago, and why I continue to be so enamoured with Starcraft to this day, and so despite never having met or talked to him, I wanted to write a little about why he was so great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my earliest infatuations with the scene came in the form of the GD show, a news and opinions programme that was streamed live every Tuesday night at 8pm GMT from the GD Studio in Sweden. Geoff was one of the
regulars on the show, along with Adebisi, Semmler, Apollo, Hellspawn, wEppas, Statsman Bruno, Trance, Draskyl and of course 2GD himself. I had chess club at 7:30pm, but I would frequently try to finish my games quickly and then hurry home in the hopes of catching the tail end of the live broadcast. Geoff’s character was indomitable, a juggernaut of both intellect and humour, and Starcraft was blessed that a man of such
obvious talents chose to lend them to that game in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoff was also a regular on State of the Game and produced arguably the two best moments in the entire series - first by laying down the law on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9iSb5-X_2do&amp;amp;t=1s&quot;&gt;horses&lt;/a&gt; and then second by making &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fEcsmUx8CzU&quot;&gt;Day9 fall off his chair&lt;/a&gt;. His demeanour and love of life was evident to all, and he was an inspiration to many in the community through his dedication to the game and relentless optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years he has been the shining light on commentary panels, bringing unmatched humour and passion to each cast, uniting diehard fans and newcomers alike with his ability to analyse and simplify the intricacies of an exceptionally complex game. Future events simply won’t be the same without him.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="esports" /><summary type="html">Geoff Robinson, better known by his screenname, ‘iNcontroL’ passed away on July 20th.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Honesty Problem II&amp;amp;colon; The Honesty Solution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/26/the-honesty-problem-ii-the-honesty-solution" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Honesty Problem II&amp;colon; The Honesty Solution" /><published>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/26/the-honesty-problem-ii-the-honesty-solution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/07/26/the-honesty-problem-ii-the-honesty-solution">&lt;p&gt;It appears the break is over - in fact it lasted a lot less time than I’d anticipated. But, the fans have spoken, and who am I to
deny my loyal followers the quality content that they so crave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more serious note, the biggest reason I decided to write again today, and probably again tomorrow, and the day after, is that
I spent some time reading through a handful of my old posts. It was a thoroughly enjoyable experience - not because I am an even vaguely competent writer, but because they capture a snapshot of myself from the past. Revisiting all those moments in time was a surprisingly pleasant journey, and ellicited a string of wry smiles. There are many posts I have written here that I love and am proud of, and not continuing to write more seems like something I might regret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such post that I returned to was &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/28/the-honesty-problem&quot;&gt;The Honesty Problem&lt;/a&gt;, which I wrote while very
much struggling at the end of last year. It talks plainly about how I am scared to admit to the people around me how low I was feeling, at a time when I felt isolated and alone, and in retrospect is pretty obviously a cry for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, it somewhat worked. In the days that followed that post, I did tell my friends how bad things had gotten, how trapped I felt, and how afraid I was about the future. Funnily enough, none of them abandoned me or gave me any indication that I was
being a burden - in fact, it strengthened my relationships with them. In the time since, I have slowly been more honest with more people,
and the overwhelming sense of loneliness I felt barely 6 months ago has transformed into a feeling that I am surrounded at all times by people who love and care about me. While I once labelled the idea of being honest about how I feel as a “problem”, it has since
allowed me to feel a stronger connection to someone than I have in years, that I didn’t even think I had the capacity to feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was wrong on the 28th December 2018, and I’m immensely grateful I was. I like being wrong - sometimes at least. I’ve still got
further progress to make with honesty, but I am happy to rebrand it as a solution and not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you tomorrow, friends.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">It appears the break is over - in fact it lasted a lot less time than I’d anticipated. But, the fans have spoken, and who am I to deny my loyal followers the quality content that they so crave?</summary></entry></feed>