<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Infinite Jest&amp;#58; I've Written a Novel</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/24/infinite-jest-ive-written-a-novel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/24/infinite-jest-ive-written-a-novel</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buho</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight I’m going to a fancy Mexican restaurant. Only, the thing is, as someone who can now pretentiously claimed that they lived in Mexico briefly, I know there’s no such thing as an
&lt;em&gt;authentic&lt;/em&gt; fancy Mexican restaurant. If it isn’t fried in 3 pigs worth of pork fat and served
to you by a 400lb, 5’2 Mexican lady who clearly hates you because you’re white and your Spanish
sucks, then it simply isn’t legitimate Mexican cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, fake-ass fancy Mexican is still &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; tasty and the tequila tastes the same either
which way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/21/buho</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/21/buho</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Staff Car Parks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The parking situation at the local hospital is, frankly, a fucking nightmare. It’s always so full that not only are there no spaces, but cars are scattered all over the shop, protruding onto the
roads and paths and just making the whole experience unnecessarily cumbersome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however, a staff car park. The forbidden fruit - an oasis of gravel and opportunity amidst
the frozen tundra of why-are-there-never-any-fucking-spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I parked there, because life is too short not to. Fuck the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/20/staff-car-parks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/20/staff-car-parks</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Violent Video Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time violent video games got a bad rap, and I think by and large people are pretty over it, but I actually think they can (potentially) be a powerful &lt;em&gt;positive&lt;/em&gt;
tool for catharsis and emotional regulation. My evidence is purely anecdotal of course, but after a long, stressful, angry day today, I sat down this evening to murder hordes
of zombies in Killing Floor 2, its tech-death soundtrack blaring through my headphones. Having played through a few levels, my body count now in the thousands, I already feel a
lot calmer, and have processed some of rage and frustation
today has inflicted upon me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/19/violent-video-games</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/19/violent-video-games</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things That Are More Therapeutic Than Therapy IV&amp;#58; Swimming in the Sea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My GP spent a good portion of our January appointments trying to persuade me that I should join the local sea swimming group, and that it would be good for my mental health. I
would’ve been infinitely more open to the idea in any other month, but January just seemed a little too optimistic. Now we’re knee deep in &lt;del&gt;clu&lt;/del&gt; February though, I
decided to take the plunge, both figuratively and literally, and joined them bright and early at 7am this morning. The air temperature was an invigorating 8 degrees celsius,
and I don’t want to even think about what the water temperature was. It was bracing, invigorating, and life-affirming, but really the best bit was what came after. Once I’d
managed an entire length of the pool (!!) we got out and peered east, across the water to Herm and Sark, silhouetted by the dawn. And then, to warm up, one of my newfound
swimming companions showed us some kind of dance/chant/thing to warm up as we faced the sun. Sharing that, with complete strangers, was how I think life should be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/18/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-iv58-swimming-in-the-sea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/18/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-iv58-swimming-in-the-sea</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adjusting For Your Own Biases</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I am wholly indebted to the poker lifestyle for is an awareness of my own biases. A lot of the discussion surrounding
poker’s mental game revolves around how to identify and correct for biases in your decision making, in order to improve said decisions,
and now I do my best to question my own biases in other aspects of life. Arrogantly, I think I do so reasonably well - at the very
least better than I did pre-poker - but this is only half the battle, and I worry I am very much losing the second half. If you
know you’re biased towards one option when making a decision, how do you actually go about correcting for it? Over-correcting
is just as unhelpful as being biased in the first place… How can you quantify bias, without ending up in some levelling-war
death-spiral? Hang on, I think my nose is bleeding…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/17/adjusting-for-your-own-biases</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/17/adjusting-for-your-own-biases</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things That Are More Therapeutic Than Therapy III&amp;#58; Bumpy Flights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having had to brave Storm Dennis from inside his bowels at approximately 24000ft in the air,
today was a jarring reminder of the deepset fear brought on by in-flight turbulence. The acute anxiety experienced as an aircraft rolls, pitches and yaws its perrilous way toward the ground
is an excellent opportunity to practice how to deal with things outside of our own control. Rationally, I knew that I was essentially completely safe, and this situation was far less dangerous than
basically every time I drive a car. I knew there was nothing I could do about it; my catastrophisizing was not going to change the weather, for regrettably I am not Zeus himself. All I could do was
close me eyes, breath, and accept my current reality, and as it turns out, I did live to fight another day. I think the practicee in these kinds of scenarios is invaluable, as they are very intense
but also very simple, and so any skills learned can easily be transplanted into social situations - or at least I hope so. Still, I’m glad I’m not flying again anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/16/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-bumpy-flights</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/16/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-bumpy-flights</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trying to Teach an Idiot Poker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For starters, “idiot” was his choice of word and not mine, I think he is plainly very intelligent.
Really, attempting to teach Josh some of the basics of poker made me feel like the idiot, as I was
reminded how difficult it can be to distill internalised and subconscious knowledge into something
accessible and with as few prerequisites for understanding as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a welcome reminder that the now-slightly-clichéd “if you can’t explain it simply then you
don’t understand it well enough” (which is something I think there is almost no way Einstein actually said and has been habitually misattributed) does have a good deal of truth to it. I still
need to work further on the very basics, the fundamental principles of the game, before I try
to lay any further masonry atop that foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is definitely better than all his friends thanks to my tuition now though.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/15/trying-to-teach-an-idiot-poker</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/15/trying-to-teach-an-idiot-poker</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things That Are More Therapeutic Than Therapy II&amp;#58; Live Music</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Christmas Eve, my friend Josh posited that one of the most worthwhile reasons not to yeet myself off this mortal coil was that it would no longer mean that I’d be able to go to gigs. At
first glance I distinctly thought to myself that this was an altogether unacceptably shallow, 
fleeting reason to prolong the drudgery of existence. Upon further inspection however, I think it’s
a pretty good point, and so it felt fitting that last night we sojourned to a grungy venue, deep inside Birmingham’s bowels, to watch instrumental prog virtuosos Polyphia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, they were &lt;em&gt;incredible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as a result, the feeling I had at the gig was one of unbridled and uncaveated joy - which indeed made me thankful that I’m still here to have those experiences, and that I might be able
to continue to have similar ones in the near future. I have always found live music to be an
exceptionally conscious, present experience - nothing outside of the time and space of the gig
really matters, and I feel deeply connected with everyone around me. It was a well needed
moment of life affirmation, and undeniably more therapeutic than therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/14/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-ii58-live-music</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/14/things-that-are-more-therapeutic-than-therapy-ii58-live-music</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Infinite Jest for the Wrong Reasons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I began &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2020/01/26/can-jonny-actually-read-challenge-20&quot;&gt;my new year’s reading resolution&lt;/a&gt; and cracked open Infinite Jest on my kindle. The edition I’m reading, rather hilariously, begins with a foreword which attempts to allay any fears the reader might have about
the levels of complexity and subsequent inpenetrability of the novel - which ironically only served to heighten my own. Nonetheless, it added to the sense that I am setting off on a spiritual
and emotionally journey, one from which I will return a changed man, hopefully for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, I suspect I am not reading the book for the right reasons. I am one of those
problematic people who cannot help but romanticise the tortured artist cliché, perhaps narcissistically feeling some kind of kinship with those sorts, and in my naive attempts to be self aware about this, posed the question to myself whether or not I would be reading the book had its author, David Foster Wallace, not taken his own life in 2008? The answer, unfortunately, is that I probably would not be. Similarly, I worry I am not reading Infinite Jest in order to read Infinite Jest, and that I am in fact reading Infinite Jest to &lt;em&gt;have read&lt;/em&gt; Infinite, a goal that while on the face of may seem noble, I expect has a very high chance to bring disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this, perhaps it is irrelevant whether or not intentions are noble, if the outcome of the
actions they inspire is positive. Even if I am not choosing to begin reading the book for the
right reasons, I suspect that they will be the only things that keep me reading it, as I navigate its 1079 pages of footnotes, satire and post-post-modernism. Perhaps, as they say, the end will justify the means.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/13/infinite-jest-for-the-wrong-reasons</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/13/infinite-jest-for-the-wrong-reasons</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>