<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-26T20:31:01+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Failure II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/26/failure-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Failure II" /><published>2019-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/26/failure-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/26/failure-ii">&lt;p&gt;(A quick aside - the first time I wrote a blog post entitled failure, the result was &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/03/30/failure&quot;&gt;pitiful and hilarious&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is pretty great, and I would strongly recommend it to each and every one of you. In what has been described by critics as my first meaningful 
foray into this particular emotion, I feel like I have found my stride pretty quickly, whistling down the street and smiling at strangers as if I’d 
been doing this shit my whole life. Despite my desire to maintain my mood’s upwards trajectory, I can already feel myself veering dangerously towards 
the dreaded comfort zone, and I am acutely aware now is the brief moment of time in which I am able to swerve the car and avoid going in the ditch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is imperative to jam pack as much failure into my imminent future as possible, and not to self-regulate back towards my median emotional state;
because failure is vital to me having any of the successes I crave, and now is the time when I can actually cope with multiple setbacks in quick succession. 
I have a unique opportunity to fail this time as well - I can fail alone. Previously I always defer to my friends, get their advice on what course of action 
would be best, ask my parents what career moves I should make, my buddies with girlfriends what words in what order to say to the cute girl I know. That’s all 
very well and good, but it limits my capacity to spectacularly fuck up significantly, which can only be a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So from now, I’m not even going to ask your advice. I’m just going to do it, even though I know there’s a strong chance that it’s a no good, bad bad bad, exceptionally, 
painfully terrible idea. Because that way, I think I’ll actually learn something from my mistakes, and maybe there’ll be a fun story or two to come out of it as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">(A quick aside - the first time I wrote a blog post entitled failure, the result was pitiful and hilarious).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m having a baby!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/25/im-having-a-baby" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I'm having a baby!" /><published>2019-04-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/25/im-having-a-baby</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/25/im-having-a-baby">&lt;p&gt;By which I mean, I’m inheriting a website and I’m pretty excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the &lt;a href=&quot;guernseychessclub.org.gg&quot;&gt;Guernsey Chess Club Website&lt;/a&gt; and yes, it
is old AF. The URL was registered in 1997 and I think it’s reasonable to assume
that the site has undergone minimal work since, which in a way I actually love -
it is a relic of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently been inspired by a certain cathédrale, and relics can be burned,
so sadly I’m not sure how long the site will last in its current iteration under
my stewardship. I have grand designs on a rebuild, but porting some of the features
(that are all pure custom build with no framework, I believe in Classic ASP) into
a modern CMS is probably going to be a not insignificant challenge. I’m hoping
that it will be an enjoyable one though, and the chess club has given me a lot
over the past 12 or so years that I have been attending, so I am excited at the
prospect of being able to give something back.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">By which I mean, I’m inheriting a website and I’m pretty excited.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On The Subject of Emasculating Oneself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/24/on-the-subject-of-emasculating-oneself" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On The Subject of Emasculating Oneself" /><published>2019-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/24/on-the-subject-of-emasculating-oneself</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/24/on-the-subject-of-emasculating-oneself">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I talked about a fragile and likely naive spark of hope with regards
to the immediate future of my dating life, so today it only seems fair to reflect
on the barren wasteland from which that flame may hopefully grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a really long time since I’ve been in a serious relationship - about 4 years.
And given that that relationship started when I was a teenager, I’m reluctant to even
place it into the ‘serious relationship’ category in the first place. Equally,
it’s been a long time since anything even remotely exciting happened in any intimate context;
at the expense of eliciting undesired pity, I haven’t got laid in 18 months.
While I can see the argument for complaining about that, it is obviously somewhat
my fault, and porn scratches that itch enough to where it doesn’t really get me
down. But there are &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; parts of the whole romantic experience that I have
not partaken in the last 18 months either, it’s just they’re unmanly and I’m
a little ashamed to admit them - they make me feel somewhat pathetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s similarly been 18 months since I made out with someone, or cuddled on the couch and
watched Netflix with someone, or just since I felt really &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; by someone.
It’s those feelings that I ultimately miss and crave, but equally those experiences
are the most difficult to ask for and hardest to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ultimately, it’s not having those things in my life that get me down and
lower my esteem and confidence. I suspect it’s the same for other men too, but
it is beaten into us not to talk about. On holiday I was briefly accused of
not doing enough to combat ‘incels’ because I am allegedly part of their community
and do not stick up for women, after I said that I can understand why some men
end up having those beliefs. I think that for many incels, they feel the same
way that I do, except rather than admit it to anyone (or themselves), they simply
take the red pill and choose to blame women rather than understand the problem
lies within. But, at the expense of being an apologist, these people feel a very
real pain, and to some degree I can identify with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think I am a little more grounded in reality than most incels, so I choose not
to persecute and objectify women in quite the same way, and am far more comfortable
instead turning my malice on myself, hence at least one joke I made on holiday
about cutting my own dick off. As with all my self-deprecating comments, there is
of course some truth in it; it’s a thinly-veiled cry for help. I’m not really
going to cut my own genitals off, but it’s far easier to joke about that than to say
“I’m really lonely and it’s causing me a lot of pain, please help”, but to the
keen observer they broadly amount to the same thing. Even the most bitter and callous
human being wants to be loved, as observed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.litcharts.com/lit/the-hitchhiker-s-guide-to-the-galaxy/chapter-7&quot;&gt;Douglas Adams&lt;/a&gt;,
in that regard the incels and I are one and the same. It’s going to take some
time to go from not talking about these feelings at all, to making them a joke,
to articulately expressing them, but hey, one day I’ll get there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">Yesterday I talked about a fragile and likely naive spark of hope with regards to the immediate future of my dating life, so today it only seems fair to reflect on the barren wasteland from which that flame may hopefully grow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adventures in Online Dating</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/23/adventures-in-online-dating" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adventures in Online Dating" /><published>2019-04-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/23/adventures-in-online-dating</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/23/adventures-in-online-dating">&lt;p&gt;While in New York, I was persuaded to give Tinder another try, by which I mean
I handed over my phone and got to play on my travelling companion’s in return
while she set up my profile and employed an exceptionally liberal right-swipe
policy. I thought hey, it’s a bit of a laugh in the city, but when I come home
I’ll exorcise the app from my phone and go back to perusing erotic literature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for whatever reason, I didn’t. I dicovered swiping is actually pretty fun,
it taps into my inner asshole’s desire to judge people and even gamifies it -
an equally genius and morally despicable move on Tinder’s behalf. When I kept
using it in Guernsey, my expectations were less than zero, they were in fact negative,
I assumed the app would damage my self esteem, and treated it as indulging my
self destructive side a little. As it turned out… I was kinda wrong. I’m borderline
enjoying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, my match rate is very low, I’d guess something around 10%. When I had
the app at uni it was definitely lower, maybe something like 1-2%, and I never
really had a meaningful conversation with anyone on there. This time, I messaged
everyone I matched with - and given my low expectations, I didn’t expect responses.
Everything I said was pretty dumb, I didn’t try to be especially impressive, or
overthink things. Most of what I said was purely to make me laugh, to satiate
my own awful sense of humour. My overarching objective, repeated inside my brain
as my materialistic mantra, was not to take it seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as it happens, it worked, and I’ve had a few genuine conversations with people.
Sure, it’s only been a few days, things haven’t exactly gone far, but it’s
enjoyable just to have that easy human connection, and try and get to know
someone, and for them to reciprocate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for part II after I’ve found my wife.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">While in New York, I was persuaded to give Tinder another try, by which I mean I handed over my phone and got to play on my travelling companion’s in return while she set up my profile and employed an exceptionally liberal right-swipe policy. I thought hey, it’s a bit of a laugh in the city, but when I come home I’ll exorcise the app from my phone and go back to perusing erotic literature.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advice II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/22/advice-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advice II" /><published>2019-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/22/advice-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/22/advice-ii">&lt;p&gt;I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/03/30/advice&quot;&gt;already talks about how dumb and arrogant unsolicited advice is&lt;/a&gt;,
but today I am wondering exactly where the line should be. On one hand, if you
genuinely &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; you could make someone happier, don’t you have some kind of
obligation to do it? Especially if they are your friend, and it would be relatively
little effort on your part. Of course, you can never know 100% that whatever
you say or do will make another person feel better, so how confident do you
need to be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think in these scenarios it’s exceptionally difficult to have a high confidence
interval - I’m reminded &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/02/13/gods-children&quot;&gt;of the Mormons&lt;/a&gt; who
I’m sure genuinely believe that they can make other people happier, and that
it is their duty. Conversely, I genuinely believe that they are delusional, and
while I guess it is possible that we are both right, it seems unlikely in the
majority of instances. Am I right to be put off offering any kind of unsolicited
advice out of a sense of altruism for fear of becoming like them? Sometimes I
want to help my close friends, but I obviously don’t know what’s best for them -
should I stay in my lane? Get better at communicating my feelings? It seems obvious
when put in those terms, but in reality I think the problem is far more nuanced
and difficult to make decisions about.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I’ve already talks about how dumb and arrogant unsolicited advice is, but today I am wondering exactly where the line should be. On one hand, if you genuinely knew you could make someone happier, don’t you have some kind of obligation to do it? Especially if they are your friend, and it would be relatively little effort on your part. Of course, you can never know 100% that whatever you say or do will make another person feel better, so how confident do you need to be?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Just Enjoy It, You Fucking Idiot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/21/just-enjoy-it-you-fucking-idiot" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just Enjoy It, You Fucking Idiot" /><published>2019-04-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/21/just-enjoy-it-you-fucking-idiot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/21/just-enjoy-it-you-fucking-idiot">&lt;p&gt;Not to brag, but things are going great for me right now. My career is on the up,
my social life is improving, I have a tan (by my standards at least) and my
self-esteem is slowly climbing out of the dumpster. Honestly, I’m borderline
running out of things to complain about on this blog, so much so I’m worried I
wouldn’t be able to maintain my daily posting routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean there’s quite &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to complain about though. Amidst all
this happiness, part of me is trying very hard not to be happy - to overthink
thanks, to catastrophise and self-sabotage. The more things in my life improve,
the stronger the urge to resist happiness becomes, but I refuse to give in to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonny, just enjoy it, you fucking idiot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Not to brag, but things are going great for me right now. My career is on the up, my social life is improving, I have a tan (by my standards at least) and my self-esteem is slowly climbing out of the dumpster. Honestly, I’m borderline running out of things to complain about on this blog, so much so I’m worried I wouldn’t be able to maintain my daily posting routine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pete Davidson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/20/pete-davidson" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pete Davidson" /><published>2019-04-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/20/pete-davidson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/20/pete-davidson">&lt;p&gt;If I had to pick a hero, I think Pete Davidson might well be the one. Both hilariously
funny and an ambassador for still living your best life despite battling mental
health issues. Being more like Pete is definitely being added to my list of goals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><summary type="html">If I had to pick a hero, I think Pete Davidson might well be the one. Both hilariously funny and an ambassador for still living your best life despite battling mental health issues. Being more like Pete is definitely being added to my list of goals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Falling in Love With Where I Live</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/19/falling-in-love-with-where-i-live" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Falling in Love With Where I Live" /><published>2019-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/19/falling-in-love-with-where-i-live</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/19/falling-in-love-with-where-i-live">&lt;p&gt;Upon my return to Guernsey, I was struck by an awful realisation - I actually
don’t really hate it here anymore. This is a problem because I get off to loudly
talking about how much I hate things, in particular living here, and I worry if
that changes then part of my identity will be lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is one blow to my ego that I will have to grin and bear though,
as I will now freely admit that Guernsey is a great place to live in many
respects. It’s incredibly safe, surrounded by natural beauty, I can walk everywhere
I need to, and my friends and family are by and large on my doorstep. Sure,
I have some pretty major unanswered questions about our political system,
economic drivers and collective social consciousness, and those are all things
worth being concerned about - but perhaps they do not have to outweigh the positives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems the next step may be to try and take action towards improving the things
I don’t like, rather than simply whining the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Upon my return to Guernsey, I was struck by an awful realisation - I actually don’t really hate it here anymore. This is a problem because I get off to loudly talking about how much I hate things, in particular living here, and I worry if that changes then part of my identity will be lost.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aeroplane Film Reviews</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/18/aeroplane-film-reviews" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aeroplane Film Reviews" /><published>2019-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/18/aeroplane-film-reviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/18/aeroplane-film-reviews">&lt;p&gt;As I am currently stuck in Gatwick Airport unable to even check in for another three
hours, I thought it would be a good time to review some of the films that I watched
on the plane to and from the Big Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-green-book&quot;&gt;The Green Book&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up was the somewhat controversial The Green Book, starring Viggo Mortensen
and Marshala Ali. I can understand somewhat why some people felt this film was
problematic - given that it deals directly with racial issues in the American south,
it is a very ‘white’ film, and Mortensen’s character is very much the protagonist,
whereas perhaps the film would’ve been better served by making Ali’s character
the central one. Despite these reservations, I still found the film powerful and
uplifting, a testament to the fact that human experience transcends race as well
as a reminder that we must all be compassionate to one another if we are going to
find solutions to society’s problems. Imperfect, but in my opinion still worthy of
the acclaim it received - well worth a watch if you need a little faith in humanity
restoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-darjeeling-limited&quot;&gt;The Darjeeling Limited&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thoroughly enjoying Moonrise Kingdom recently, I was more than happy to dive
into another Wes Andersen film when the opportunity presented itself. As with all
his films it would seem, The Darjeeling Limited is stunningly shot and a wonderful
piece of artistic cinema, although if I remember correctly at no point does Owen
Wilson say the word ‘wow’ which is, frankly, unforgivable. The main appeal is
the aesthetics rather than the plot, but I enjoy stories that need a lot of
interpretation anyway, so in turn I enjoyed the film. Good if you want to watch
something gorgeous, bad if you want to be on the edge of your seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-billboards-outside-ebbing-missouri&quot;&gt;Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was comfortably my favourite plane film from this trip. It hits like a truck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be prepared to feel emotions in a far more complicated way than you have before.
Poignant, brutal and agonizing, every time you think things can’t get any worse,
they do. Compelling from start to finish with an incredible storyline and amazing
acting performances, the film still has an uplifting side even in the face of the
starkest possible situations. It encapsulates the full range of human emotions,
from unthinkable anger and unspeakable violence, to tear-jerking love and compassion.
A must-watch, but not when you’re feeling fragile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-revenant&quot;&gt;The Revenant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie that finaly netted my boy Leo the Oscar, but in all honestly, I don’t
entirely see why. The plot can essentially be summed up as “Leonardo Di Caprio
crawls through the forest for three hours, groaning and writhing in pain, and eats
large quantities of raw meat. Also sleeps inside a horse.” Aaaand that’s basically
it - he barely even has any dialogue. The film was fine, but I can’t say it did
it for me, I think it was a little overrated. Sorry Leo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Films" /><summary type="html">As I am currently stuck in Gatwick Airport unable to even check in for another three hours, I thought it would be a good time to review some of the films that I watched on the plane to and from the Big Apple.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Long Road Home</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/17/the-long-road-home" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Long Road Home" /><published>2019-04-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/17/the-long-road-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/17/the-long-road-home">&lt;p&gt;I’m about to begin the 6000km journey home, and I won’t get there for 30 or so hours.
I’m probably not going to sleep in the interim, I certainly won’t find a bed,
I’m a bit hungover and likely to be exceptionally tired for most of the trip. It’s
definitely going to suck, but it was also without a doubt, 100%, categorically worth
any kind of pain for the amazing two weeks that I’ve just had.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">I’m about to begin the 6000km journey home, and I won’t get there for 30 or so hours. I’m probably not going to sleep in the interim, I certainly won’t find a bed, I’m a bit hungover and likely to be exceptionally tired for most of the trip. It’s definitely going to suck, but it was also without a doubt, 100%, categorically worth any kind of pain for the amazing two weeks that I’ve just had.</summary></entry></feed>