<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-14T07:51:10+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Egos at the Door</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/13/egos-at-the-door.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Egos at the Door" /><published>2018-10-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/13/egos-at-the-door</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/13/egos-at-the-door.html">&lt;p&gt;
  Today was another perfect example of why having an ego and being
  a programmer seem completely incompatible. This site is built
  only really using HTML and CSS - admittedly there is some templating
  and preprocessing done with Sass/Liquid etc - but it should still
  be easy enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I spent maybe two hours today staring at the mobile styling
  for this page. I had a regular desktop browser set to 375px
  wide, but everything was too small, and the DOM elements
  were telling me that there were bigger than they demonstrably were.
  &lt;code&gt;console.log(screen.width);&lt;/code&gt; returned 375px - what we'd
  expect. &lt;code&gt;console.log(document.querySelector('body').screenWidth);&lt;/code&gt;
  however, returned 980px, despite it clearly being visually
  less than the width of the device. I even hooked up an old
  android phone to my PC and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/dev-options&quot;&gt;
  installed developer options by tapping the build number 7 times.&lt;/a&gt; I had no joy whatsoever.
  What. The. Fuck.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Except not really what the fuck, because anyone who would so
  brazenly call themselves a web developer, as I have, would
  know that the first thing to check would be whether or not
  a meta value had been set for the viewport. I'm a clown.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  At least I am a clown who learned something, and I suspect
  this is the last time I make this mistake again - at the very
  least I hope it is the last time I waste nearly 2 hours trying
  to correct it. The relief when I could finally get media queries
  working correctly was palpable.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Responsive Web Design" /><category term="Imposter Syndrome" /><summary type="html">Today was another perfect example of why having an ego and being a programmer seem completely incompatible. This site is built only really using HTML and CSS - admittedly there is some templating and preprocessing done with Sass/Liquid etc - but it should still be easy enough. I spent maybe two hours today staring at the mobile styling for this page. I had a regular desktop browser set to 375px wide, but everything was too small, and the DOM elements were telling me that there were bigger than they demonstrably were. console.log(screen.width); returned 375px - what we'd expect. console.log(document.querySelector('body').screenWidth); however, returned 980px, despite it clearly being visually less than the width of the device. I even hooked up an old android phone to my PC and installed developer options by tapping the build number 7 times. I had no joy whatsoever. What. The. Fuck. Except not really what the fuck, because anyone who would so brazenly call themselves a web developer, as I have, would know that the first thing to check would be whether or not a meta value had been set for the viewport. I'm a clown. At least I am a clown who learned something, and I suspect this is the last time I make this mistake again - at the very least I hope it is the last time I waste nearly 2 hours trying to correct it. The relief when I could finally get media queries working correctly was palpable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beautility</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/12/beautility.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beautility" /><published>2018-10-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/12/beautility</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/12/beautility.html">&lt;p&gt;
  I have had a pretty ambivalent relationship with my phone for quite
  a while now. On one hand, all of us would struggle to forgo
  one altogether, given it is now a primary driver in almost all of
  our social and professional lives. Having the seemingly infinite
  wealth of human knowledge at my fingertips seems invaluable a lot of
  the time, especially when I'm trying to impress at dinner parties.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  That was a joke. Obviously I don't get invited to parties, dinner
  or otherwise.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The point remains though - it is not exactly a hot take to suggest
  we are &quot;enslaved&quot; to our phones, or some other suitably sensational
  choice of phrase. I spend a decent amount of time on my phone, and
  quite a lot of that time I suspect does not really benefit me, often
  making me experience things negatively, eg the increasing-less-mild sense
  of nihilism I have whenever I read the news. So overall is my phone
  +EV for me, I should I, ever the contrarian-wannabe-hipster-douchebag,
  stop using me phone (and then immediately proceed to brag about it to everyone
  who'll listen)?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  No. I am trying not to be &quot;that guy&quot;, and just admitting that I am
  millenial trash and that my iPhone dictates my life at this point.
  In the unending and naive quest to improve my life though, I discovered
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://betterhumans.coach.me/beautility-my-ultimate-iphone-setup-1b3dd0c588a0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  this&lt;/a&gt;, a simple post with a few relatively straightforward ideas to
  change one's iOS habits, with big promises about how it would impact
  my use of the device. I set everything up tonight and it was about as
  easy as advertised - only 15 minutes or so in total. So far I am
  enjoying the new layout a lot more than the old one, although of course
  it is early days yet. Unlocking my phone to see basically nothing is
  a pretty good reminder that I should probably just lock my phone
  again and get on with something.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'll report back next weekend with how I feel after a week in this
  new bleak, minimalistic mobile landscape.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="iOS" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">I have had a pretty ambivalent relationship with my phone for quite a while now. On one hand, all of us would struggle to forgo one altogether, given it is now a primary driver in almost all of our social and professional lives. Having the seemingly infinite wealth of human knowledge at my fingertips seems invaluable a lot of the time, especially when I'm trying to impress at dinner parties. That was a joke. Obviously I don't get invited to parties, dinner or otherwise. The point remains though - it is not exactly a hot take to suggest we are &quot;enslaved&quot; to our phones, or some other suitably sensational choice of phrase. I spend a decent amount of time on my phone, and quite a lot of that time I suspect does not really benefit me, often making me experience things negatively, eg the increasing-less-mild sense of nihilism I have whenever I read the news. So overall is my phone +EV for me, I should I, ever the contrarian-wannabe-hipster-douchebag, stop using me phone (and then immediately proceed to brag about it to everyone who'll listen)? No. I am trying not to be &quot;that guy&quot;, and just admitting that I am millenial trash and that my iPhone dictates my life at this point. In the unending and naive quest to improve my life though, I discovered this, a simple post with a few relatively straightforward ideas to change one's iOS habits, with big promises about how it would impact my use of the device. I set everything up tonight and it was about as easy as advertised - only 15 minutes or so in total. So far I am enjoying the new layout a lot more than the old one, although of course it is early days yet. Unlocking my phone to see basically nothing is a pretty good reminder that I should probably just lock my phone again and get on with something. I'll report back next weekend with how I feel after a week in this new bleak, minimalistic mobile landscape.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Source</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/11/open-source.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Source" /><published>2018-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/11/open-source</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/11/open-source.html">&lt;p&gt;
  I was inspired today by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/how-i-went-from-newbie-to-software-engineer-in-9-months-while-working-full-time-460bd8485847&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  this&lt;/a&gt; Medium article. I know inspiration will fade quickly, but
  I am hoping I can hold onto at least one thing from this article -
  it is never to late to start contributing to open source.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One of the reasons I am a web developer is because I care a lot
  about the internet - I want it to be fast, accessible, to connect
  people and to improve our lives. Contributing to open source
  technology might seem sinful to some people, particularly in
  other professions. Giving up my time and expertise, for free?
  Volunteering, but not for those in need, for other developers?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Well, in my infinite ignorance, I think it's a noble cause. To have
  the opportunity to contribute to a large, growing, evolving codebase
  would feel amazing, and I am hoping I will have that opportunity soon.
  Imagine when I get my first patch in a big project... It's going to feel
  like a huge achievement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The article linked above says it's never to early to start contributing,
  and I suspect this is true, especially given I don't actually have to
  contribute code, nor do I have to contribute to a major library.
  There are some pretty massive projects out there with terrible documentation -
  Drupal, I am looking at you - so something like that seems like a natural
  place to start. Obviously I am not going to try to write documentation
  for Drupal though, because that would require understanding it, and honestly
  Drupal is nuts to me. My weekend homework (once this site is finished)
  is going to be researching the best way to start my open source journey -
  hopefully it is a long one.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Open Source" /><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">I was inspired today by this Medium article. I know inspiration will fade quickly, but I am hoping I can hold onto at least one thing from this article - it is never to late to start contributing to open source. One of the reasons I am a web developer is because I care a lot about the internet - I want it to be fast, accessible, to connect people and to improve our lives. Contributing to open source technology might seem sinful to some people, particularly in other professions. Giving up my time and expertise, for free? Volunteering, but not for those in need, for other developers? Well, in my infinite ignorance, I think it's a noble cause. To have the opportunity to contribute to a large, growing, evolving codebase would feel amazing, and I am hoping I will have that opportunity soon. Imagine when I get my first patch in a big project... It's going to feel like a huge achievement. The article linked above says it's never to early to start contributing, and I suspect this is true, especially given I don't actually have to contribute code, nor do I have to contribute to a major library. There are some pretty massive projects out there with terrible documentation - Drupal, I am looking at you - so something like that seems like a natural place to start. Obviously I am not going to try to write documentation for Drupal though, because that would require understanding it, and honestly Drupal is nuts to me. My weekend homework (once this site is finished) is going to be researching the best way to start my open source journey - hopefully it is a long one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We are Live - ish</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/10/we-are-live-ish.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We are Live - ish" /><published>2018-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/10/we-are-live-ish</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/10/we-are-live-ish.html">&lt;p&gt;
  This is the first daily post which is going to be uploaded to this new
  Jekyll site on the same day it was published! The URL is currently
  jonnyspicer.github.io but assuming I get everything finished by the
  end of the weekend, I'll swap the domain over to jonnyspicer.com -
  an exciting time. It has taken a long time for me to even start this project
  and in the end, it didn't even require that many hours, &amp;lt;20 so far,
  including having to learn Jekyll.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Overall I am pretty happy, I like the minimal look, Jekyll has not been
  painless but it hasn't been excruciating either. There is a bit more
  effort involed in actually generating a blog post then there would be
  with a CMS, as evidenced by the fact I am writing this in my text editor
  - there's no wysiwyg to catch any embarrassing spelling mistakes. I also
  have to manually generate the post file with a specific date/name convention
  but after the site is complete I'll write a script to do that for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Left to do as of 10th Oct 2018:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Set up home page with excerpts of last post in each blog;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Change blog pages to just show last 5-10 posts for each blog,
      with dates;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Add full archive pages, grouped by date;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Review mobile/tablet styling (should just be changing font size...);
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Add CNAME file to repo;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Change DNS for jonnyspicer.com to point to this site.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">This is the first daily post which is going to be uploaded to this new Jekyll site on the same day it was published! The URL is currently jonnyspicer.github.io but assuming I get everything finished by the end of the weekend, I'll swap the domain over to jonnyspicer.com - an exciting time. It has taken a long time for me to even start this project and in the end, it didn't even require that many hours, &amp;lt;20 so far, including having to learn Jekyll. Overall I am pretty happy, I like the minimal look, Jekyll has not been painless but it hasn't been excruciating either. There is a bit more effort involed in actually generating a blog post then there would be with a CMS, as evidenced by the fact I am writing this in my text editor - there's no wysiwyg to catch any embarrassing spelling mistakes. I also have to manually generate the post file with a specific date/name convention but after the site is complete I'll write a script to do that for me. Left to do as of 10th Oct 2018: Set up home page with excerpts of last post in each blog; Change blog pages to just show last 5-10 posts for each blog, with dates; Add full archive pages, grouped by date; Review mobile/tablet styling (should just be changing font size...); Add CNAME file to repo; Change DNS for jonnyspicer.com to point to this site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Codecoaster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/09/the-codecoaster.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Codecoaster" /><published>2018-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/09/the-codecoaster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/09/the-codecoaster.html">&lt;p&gt;
  Programming is such a bizarre series of ups and downs. One moment I
  have crippling imposter syndrome - I feel like I don't deserve the job
  I have at all, and feel like I should quit to save my boss the trouble
  of realising how awful I am and firing me. But the next, I have written
  a function which has a little complexity, is decently efficient, and I
  worked hard on - I'm proud of it, and proud of myself by proxy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Like everything else in life, this process is pretty exhausting. I am
  naïvely hoping that it will get better as I get better at programming -
  but I know it won't. Oh well.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Programming" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Programming is such a bizarre series of ups and downs. One moment I have crippling imposter syndrome - I feel like I don't deserve the job I have at all, and feel like I should quit to save my boss the trouble of realising how awful I am and firing me. But the next, I have written a function which has a little complexity, is decently efficient, and I worked hard on - I'm proud of it, and proud of myself by proxy. Like everything else in life, this process is pretty exhausting. I am naïvely hoping that it will get better as I get better at programming - but I know it won't. Oh well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">elijah who</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/08/elijah-who.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="elijah who" /><published>2018-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/08/elijah-who</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/08/elijah-who.html">&lt;p&gt;
  Today has been a really rough day, but I whine enough in this blog,
  so I wanna talk about something positive instead. After listening to
  some lofi hip-hop while trying to work, I remembered &lt;a href=&quot;https://elijahwho.bandcamp.com/&quot;
  target=&quot;blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;elijah who.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  His(?) music is super relaxing, and made it easier to get through the
  day relatively meltdown-free. Cheers, elijah.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Today has been a really rough day, but I whine enough in this blog, so I wanna talk about something positive instead. After listening to some lofi hip-hop while trying to work, I remembered elijah who. His(?) music is super relaxing, and made it easier to get through the day relatively meltdown-free. Cheers, elijah.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/07/jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll" /><published>2018-10-07T19:35:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-07T19:35:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/07/jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/07/jekyll.html">&lt;span &gt;Today I finally got round to rebuilding my main site, where this blog will be hosted in the (near) future. It has been a long time-coming, and I am glad I finally made a start - hopefully I can smash it out in a couple of weeks, although this is probably naive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;I decided to move the site from Wordpress to Github Pages, and in doing so decided I was gonna give Jekyll a go instead of using a CMS. Installing Jekyll meant installing Ruby on my Windows machine, which I was not excited about. To start with, it was relatively easy, until I tried to install some Jekyll plugins, at which point it seems like the rubygems.org servers had a mare and timed out repeatedly. After trying ~10x, I finally managed to install the gems I was after, but it seems like I am definitely not gonna be updating them anytime soon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;The skeleton of the site is vaguely set up - the git repo is initialised, I've got the sass structure sorted, I've got a config file working, the main pages and includes are all there, waiting to be populated with that sweet, juicy content. I'm still not 100% sure what I think about Jekyll overall and whether or not it's preferable to a CMS, but I am super excited to try and build a very stripped back blog, potentially with no JS, and a very minimal design.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html">Today I finally got round to rebuilding my main site, where this blog will be hosted in the (near) future. It has been a long time-coming, and I am glad I finally made a start - hopefully I can smash it out in a couple of weeks, although this is probably naive.I decided to move the site from Wordpress to Github Pages, and in doing so decided I was gonna give Jekyll a go instead of using a CMS. Installing Jekyll meant installing Ruby on my Windows machine, which I was not excited about. To start with, it was relatively easy, until I tried to install some Jekyll plugins, at which point it seems like the rubygems.org servers had a mare and timed out repeatedly. After trying ~10x, I finally managed to install the gems I was after, but it seems like I am definitely not gonna be updating them anytime soon.&amp;nbsp;The skeleton of the site is vaguely set up - the git repo is initialised, I've got the sass structure sorted, I've got a config file working, the main pages and includes are all there, waiting to be populated with that sweet, juicy content. I'm still not 100% sure what I think about Jekyll overall and whether or not it's preferable to a CMS, but I am super excited to try and build a very stripped back blog, potentially with no JS, and a very minimal design.&amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Always Tired</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/06/always-tired.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Always Tired" /><published>2018-10-06T20:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T20:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/06/always-tired</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/06/always-tired.html">&lt;span &gt;Much like Post Malone, I am also &lt;strike&gt;a hyper-rich international hip-hop sensation&lt;/strike&gt; always tired. Perhaps it's a lack of vitamin-D, or due to my less than ideal diet, because I'm depressed, or down to the incessant wailing of my newborn child during the night. Either which way, it sucks, and I need to do something about it.&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Much like Post Malone, I am also a hyper-rich international hip-hop sensation always tired. Perhaps it's a lack of vitamin-D, or due to my less than ideal diet, because I'm depressed, or down to the incessant wailing of my newborn child during the night. Either which way, it sucks, and I need to do something about it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Optimism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/05/optimism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optimism" /><published>2018-10-05T18:52:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T18:52:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/05/optimism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/05/optimism.html">&lt;p&gt;
  I'm not very good at noticing the good things in life, especially given the way I fixate on the bad. I still think there is an objective argument that society is trash, and that is a good reason to feel depressed, but it seems my main strategy for dealing with that right now is just to, uh, try not to think about it. Just like I'm not thinking about a big pink elephant right now. Fuck.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'm trying to think of things to be optimistic about. The main thing I can think of right now is that tech is getting more advanced, and there is some non-zero amount of people out there trying to use its new capabilities to do good. &lt;a href=&quot;https://solid.inrupt.com/&quot;&gt;Solid &lt;/a&gt;is a pretty good example. I plan on setting up an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; gateway this weekend. Pen testers are still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.martinvigo.com/googlemeetroulette/&quot;&gt;creative, thorough geniuses&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe life isn't so bad.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I'm not very good at noticing the good things in life, especially given the way I fixate on the bad. I still think there is an objective argument that society is trash, and that is a good reason to feel depressed, but it seems my main strategy for dealing with that right now is just to, uh, try not to think about it. Just like I'm not thinking about a big pink elephant right now. Fuck.I'm trying to think of things to be optimistic about. The main thing I can think of right now is that tech is getting more advanced, and there is some non-zero amount of people out there trying to use its new capabilities to do good. Solid is a pretty good example. I plan on setting up an IPFS gateway this weekend. Pen testers are still creative, thorough geniuses. Maybe life isn't so bad.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/04/stress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stress" /><published>2018-10-04T21:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-04T21:04:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/04/stress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/04/stress.html">&lt;span &gt;This week at work has been one of the most stressful I have faced so far. I am very excited for the weekend, and the pub tomorrow. I'm still trying to figure out if this is what life is meant to just be like for the next 40 years, or if I'm missing something.&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">This week at work has been one of the most stressful I have faced so far. I am very excited for the weekend, and the pub tomorrow. I'm still trying to figure out if this is what life is meant to just be like for the next 40 years, or if I'm missing something.</summary></entry></feed>