<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-12T19:23:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Open Source</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/11/open-source.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Source" /><published>2018-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/11/open-source</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/11/open-source.html">&lt;p&gt;
  I was inspired today by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/how-i-went-from-newbie-to-software-engineer-in-9-months-while-working-full-time-460bd8485847&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  this&lt;/a&gt; Medium article. I know inspiration will fade quickly, but
  I am hoping I can hold onto at least one thing from this article -
  it is never to late to start contributing to open source.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One of the reasons I am a web developer is because I care a lot
  about the internet - I want it to be fast, accessible, to connect
  people and to improve our lives. Contributing to open source
  technology might seem sinful to some people, particularly in
  other professions. Giving up my time and expertise, for free?
  Volunteering, but not for those in need, for other developers?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Well, in my infinite ignorance, I think it's a noble cause. To have
  the opportunity to contribute to a large, growing, evolving codebase
  would feel amazing, and I am hoping I will have that opportunity soon.
  Imagine when I get my first patch in a big project... It's going to feel
  like a huge achievement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The article linked above says it's never to early to start contributing,
  and I suspect this is true, especially given I don't actually have to
  contribute code, nor do I have to contribute to a major library.
  There are some pretty massive projects out there with terrible documentation -
  Drupal, I am looking at you - so something like that seems like a natural
  place to start. Obviously I am not going to try to write documentation
  for Drupal though, because that would require understanding it, and honestly
  Drupal is nuts to me. My weekend homework (once this site is finished)
  is going to be researching the best way to start my open source journey -
  hopefully it is a long one.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Open Source" /><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">I was inspired today by this Medium article. I know inspiration will fade quickly, but I am hoping I can hold onto at least one thing from this article - it is never to late to start contributing to open source. One of the reasons I am a web developer is because I care a lot about the internet - I want it to be fast, accessible, to connect people and to improve our lives. Contributing to open source technology might seem sinful to some people, particularly in other professions. Giving up my time and expertise, for free? Volunteering, but not for those in need, for other developers? Well, in my infinite ignorance, I think it's a noble cause. To have the opportunity to contribute to a large, growing, evolving codebase would feel amazing, and I am hoping I will have that opportunity soon. Imagine when I get my first patch in a big project... It's going to feel like a huge achievement. The article linked above says it's never to early to start contributing, and I suspect this is true, especially given I don't actually have to contribute code, nor do I have to contribute to a major library. There are some pretty massive projects out there with terrible documentation - Drupal, I am looking at you - so something like that seems like a natural place to start. Obviously I am not going to try to write documentation for Drupal though, because that would require understanding it, and honestly Drupal is nuts to me. My weekend homework (once this site is finished) is going to be researching the best way to start my open source journey - hopefully it is a long one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We are Live - ish</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/10/we-are-live-ish.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We are Live - ish" /><published>2018-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/10/we-are-live-ish</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/10/we-are-live-ish.html">&lt;p&gt;
  This is the first daily post which is going to be uploaded to this new
  Jekyll site on the same day it was published! The URL is currently
  jonnyspicer.github.io but assuming I get everything finished by the
  end of the weekend, I'll swap the domain over to jonnyspicer.com -
  an exciting time. It has taken a long time for me to even start this project
  and in the end, it didn't even require that many hours, &amp;lt;20 so far,
  including having to learn Jekyll.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Overall I am pretty happy, I like the minimal look, Jekyll has not been
  painless but it hasn't been excruciating either. There is a bit more
  effort involed in actually generating a blog post then there would be
  with a CMS, as evidenced by the fact I am writing this in my text editor
  - there's no wysiwyg to catch any embarrassing spelling mistakes. I also
  have to manually generate the post file with a specific date/name convention
  but after the site is complete I'll write a script to do that for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Left to do as of 10th Oct 2018:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Set up home page with excerpts of last post in each blog;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Change blog pages to just show last 5-10 posts for each blog,
      with dates;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Add full archive pages, grouped by date;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Review mobile/tablet styling (should just be changing font size...);
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Add CNAME file to repo;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Change DNS for jonnyspicer.com to point to this site.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">This is the first daily post which is going to be uploaded to this new Jekyll site on the same day it was published! The URL is currently jonnyspicer.github.io but assuming I get everything finished by the end of the weekend, I'll swap the domain over to jonnyspicer.com - an exciting time. It has taken a long time for me to even start this project and in the end, it didn't even require that many hours, &amp;lt;20 so far, including having to learn Jekyll. Overall I am pretty happy, I like the minimal look, Jekyll has not been painless but it hasn't been excruciating either. There is a bit more effort involed in actually generating a blog post then there would be with a CMS, as evidenced by the fact I am writing this in my text editor - there's no wysiwyg to catch any embarrassing spelling mistakes. I also have to manually generate the post file with a specific date/name convention but after the site is complete I'll write a script to do that for me. Left to do as of 10th Oct 2018: Set up home page with excerpts of last post in each blog; Change blog pages to just show last 5-10 posts for each blog, with dates; Add full archive pages, grouped by date; Review mobile/tablet styling (should just be changing font size...); Add CNAME file to repo; Change DNS for jonnyspicer.com to point to this site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Codecoaster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/09/the-codecoaster.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Codecoaster" /><published>2018-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/09/the-codecoaster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/09/the-codecoaster.html">&lt;p&gt;
  Programming is such a bizarre series of ups and downs. One moment I
  have crippling imposter syndrome - I feel like I don't deserve the job
  I have at all, and feel like I should quit to save my boss the trouble
  of realising how awful I am and firing me. But the next, I have written
  a function which has a little complexity, is decently efficient, and I
  worked hard on - I'm proud of it, and proud of myself by proxy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Like everything else in life, this process is pretty exhausting. I am
  naïvely hoping that it will get better as I get better at programming -
  but I know it won't. Oh well.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Programming" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Programming is such a bizarre series of ups and downs. One moment I have crippling imposter syndrome - I feel like I don't deserve the job I have at all, and feel like I should quit to save my boss the trouble of realising how awful I am and firing me. But the next, I have written a function which has a little complexity, is decently efficient, and I worked hard on - I'm proud of it, and proud of myself by proxy. Like everything else in life, this process is pretty exhausting. I am naïvely hoping that it will get better as I get better at programming - but I know it won't. Oh well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">elijah who</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/08/elijah-who.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="elijah who" /><published>2018-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/08/elijah-who</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/08/elijah-who.html">&lt;p&gt;
  Today has been a really rough day, but I whine enough in this blog,
  so I wanna talk about something positive instead. After listening to
  some lofi hip-hop while trying to work, I remembered &lt;a href=&quot;https://elijahwho.bandcamp.com/&quot;
  target=&quot;blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;elijah who.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  His(?) music is super relaxing, and made it easier to get through the
  day relatively meltdown-free. Cheers, elijah.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Today has been a really rough day, but I whine enough in this blog, so I wanna talk about something positive instead. After listening to some lofi hip-hop while trying to work, I remembered elijah who. His(?) music is super relaxing, and made it easier to get through the day relatively meltdown-free. Cheers, elijah.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/07/jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll" /><published>2018-10-07T19:35:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-07T19:35:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/07/jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/07/jekyll.html">&lt;span &gt;Today I finally got round to rebuilding my main site, where this blog will be hosted in the (near) future. It has been a long time-coming, and I am glad I finally made a start - hopefully I can smash it out in a couple of weeks, although this is probably naive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;I decided to move the site from Wordpress to Github Pages, and in doing so decided I was gonna give Jekyll a go instead of using a CMS. Installing Jekyll meant installing Ruby on my Windows machine, which I was not excited about. To start with, it was relatively easy, until I tried to install some Jekyll plugins, at which point it seems like the rubygems.org servers had a mare and timed out repeatedly. After trying ~10x, I finally managed to install the gems I was after, but it seems like I am definitely not gonna be updating them anytime soon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;The skeleton of the site is vaguely set up - the git repo is initialised, I've got the sass structure sorted, I've got a config file working, the main pages and includes are all there, waiting to be populated with that sweet, juicy content. I'm still not 100% sure what I think about Jekyll overall and whether or not it's preferable to a CMS, but I am super excited to try and build a very stripped back blog, potentially with no JS, and a very minimal design.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html">Today I finally got round to rebuilding my main site, where this blog will be hosted in the (near) future. It has been a long time-coming, and I am glad I finally made a start - hopefully I can smash it out in a couple of weeks, although this is probably naive.I decided to move the site from Wordpress to Github Pages, and in doing so decided I was gonna give Jekyll a go instead of using a CMS. Installing Jekyll meant installing Ruby on my Windows machine, which I was not excited about. To start with, it was relatively easy, until I tried to install some Jekyll plugins, at which point it seems like the rubygems.org servers had a mare and timed out repeatedly. After trying ~10x, I finally managed to install the gems I was after, but it seems like I am definitely not gonna be updating them anytime soon.&amp;nbsp;The skeleton of the site is vaguely set up - the git repo is initialised, I've got the sass structure sorted, I've got a config file working, the main pages and includes are all there, waiting to be populated with that sweet, juicy content. I'm still not 100% sure what I think about Jekyll overall and whether or not it's preferable to a CMS, but I am super excited to try and build a very stripped back blog, potentially with no JS, and a very minimal design.&amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Always Tired</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/06/always-tired.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Always Tired" /><published>2018-10-06T20:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T20:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/06/always-tired</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/06/always-tired.html">&lt;span &gt;Much like Post Malone, I am also &lt;strike&gt;a hyper-rich international hip-hop sensation&lt;/strike&gt; always tired. Perhaps it's a lack of vitamin-D, or due to my less than ideal diet, because I'm depressed, or down to the incessant wailing of my newborn child during the night. Either which way, it sucks, and I need to do something about it.&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Much like Post Malone, I am also a hyper-rich international hip-hop sensation always tired. Perhaps it's a lack of vitamin-D, or due to my less than ideal diet, because I'm depressed, or down to the incessant wailing of my newborn child during the night. Either which way, it sucks, and I need to do something about it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Optimism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/05/optimism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optimism" /><published>2018-10-05T18:52:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-05T18:52:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/05/optimism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/05/optimism.html">&lt;p&gt;
  I'm not very good at noticing the good things in life, especially given the way I fixate on the bad. I still think there is an objective argument that society is trash, and that is a good reason to feel depressed, but it seems my main strategy for dealing with that right now is just to, uh, try not to think about it. Just like I'm not thinking about a big pink elephant right now. Fuck.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'm trying to think of things to be optimistic about. The main thing I can think of right now is that tech is getting more advanced, and there is some non-zero amount of people out there trying to use its new capabilities to do good. &lt;a href=&quot;https://solid.inrupt.com/&quot;&gt;Solid &lt;/a&gt;is a pretty good example. I plan on setting up an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; gateway this weekend. Pen testers are still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.martinvigo.com/googlemeetroulette/&quot;&gt;creative, thorough geniuses&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe life isn't so bad.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I'm not very good at noticing the good things in life, especially given the way I fixate on the bad. I still think there is an objective argument that society is trash, and that is a good reason to feel depressed, but it seems my main strategy for dealing with that right now is just to, uh, try not to think about it. Just like I'm not thinking about a big pink elephant right now. Fuck.I'm trying to think of things to be optimistic about. The main thing I can think of right now is that tech is getting more advanced, and there is some non-zero amount of people out there trying to use its new capabilities to do good. Solid is a pretty good example. I plan on setting up an IPFS gateway this weekend. Pen testers are still creative, thorough geniuses. Maybe life isn't so bad.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/04/stress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stress" /><published>2018-10-04T21:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-04T21:04:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/04/stress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/04/stress.html">&lt;span &gt;This week at work has been one of the most stressful I have faced so far. I am very excited for the weekend, and the pub tomorrow. I'm still trying to figure out if this is what life is meant to just be like for the next 40 years, or if I'm missing something.&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">This week at work has been one of the most stressful I have faced so far. I am very excited for the weekend, and the pub tomorrow. I'm still trying to figure out if this is what life is meant to just be like for the next 40 years, or if I'm missing something.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s too late for me - save yourself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/03/its-too-late-for-me-save-yourself.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It's too late for me - save yourself" /><published>2018-10-03T23:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T23:24:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/03/its-too-late-for-me-save-yourself</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/03/its-too-late-for-me-save-yourself.html">&lt;span &gt;In the last few months I have become more and more disillusioned with our corporate overlords, the Big Five - Apple, Alphabet (Google's parent company), Microsoft, Facebook and Amazon. I am scared about what they have already done to our society and what they continue to do, that they are eroding not only the foundations of the internet but also our basic human right to privacy, and tearing at our social fabric.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;Sure, my tinfoil hat is pretty screwed on at this point, but I'm not sure I need to explain in too much detail why I think these companies are bad, it just seems as a society we have collectively accepted our fate. But, in an effort to make myself feel better about life, a couple of weeks ago, I decided to see how much of these five companies I could remove from my life. The answer is - not very much. But here is what I found.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Microsoft&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Microsoft is probably the company out of the five that I have the least qualms with, however this could be due to lack of sensationalist articles on Hacker News about them more than any kind of higher level of business ethics. The fact they don't run their own ad network helps a lot, as does the fact they sell proprietary products, and ironically the fact I don't use any Bing services probably means I like them more as I am have no idea what their ad or tracking policies are like.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;At the moment my home PC and all my laptops (and a VM) are running various versions of Windows. As of this weekend, my PC now dual-boots Windows 10 and Kali Linux, but I can't see myself ever making the switch full time to Linux, due to the lack of software support on the latter. I'm excited to get to grips with Unix and try to learn some pentesting on Kali though, I think it will improve my computing knowledge a lot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Facebook&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Ah, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-DN1TIDZPH4&quot;&gt;Zark Fuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;, get your hands out of my data. I would put money on Facebook being the first test case for GDPR in EU court, after another massive breach this past week. The old &quot;if you're not paying, you're the product&quot; isn't quite as poetic and universally true as some might think, but in Facebook's case I absolutely believe it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;Sadly... I am struggling to carve Facebook out of my life. Despite having deactivated my Facebook account proper, I have retained use of its Messenger app, as it's the way I communicate with most of my friends, and I fear ditching that too would leave me something of a social leper. You win this time, Fuckerberg.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Oh Google... how far you have fallen in my estimation. Once a company I trusted, now I am in the process of migrating away from as many of its services as possible, during which I have discovered quite how many Google services I previously used. Chrome 69 was really the last straw from me, despite being a Chrome user since sometime around version 1, they have shown their true colours in that all they want is your juicy, juicy data. Well, no more! Below are the services I use and what I have been replacing them with. Big shout-out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nomoregoogle.com/&quot;&gt;https://nomoregoogle.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Browser: Google Chrome to Brave at home, Firefox at work. Considering trying Vivaldi out too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Search engine: Google to Duck Duck Go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Email: Haven't actually ditched Gmail yet, looking into FastMail and ProtonMail as alternatives.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Docs/Sheets: Docs will probably get replaced by Evernote, Sheets undecided. I haven't needed to use either service recently.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Youtube: Sadly there is no real alternative to Youtube. Its biggest competitor for video content is Facebook, withVimeo and Dailymotion quite some ways behind, both lacking content. Peertube is interesting conceptually but my experience with the federated model a la Mastodon hasn't been great so far.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Maps: Gmaps to OpenStreetMap which is my new favourite thing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Authenticator: In the process of migrating to Authy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Blogging: I swear to god at some point I will finally get a Jekyll site running on Github pages which will host this blog. If not I owe somebody a beer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;DNS: Swapped to Cloudflare last week, works like a dream.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;File storage: Drive to Dropbox, will look at MEGA too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span &gt;Domain: currently looking for a domain registrar that is both not in the Fortune 500 and also provides service that isn't 100% awful.... suggestions appreciated.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Apple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Do you have any idea how tedious it is to switch away from an iPhone once you already have an iPhone? All your apps, contacts, data etc is stored in Apple's corner of the ever-mysterious &quot;cloud&quot;, and the prospect of having to manually generate it all again is one that doesn't bear thinking about. Also, most of the viable alternatives are made by some other giant megacorp tech company so it wouldn't even make me feel that much better.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;As with Microsoft, at least I am actually paying for a product here, so perhaps that means that Apple don't have any incentive to harvest my data. After all, it's pretty widely thought that they make an insane markup on each phone, I suspect due to cheap labour and poor conditions in their manufacturing plants in China. Having said that, you don't become the world's first trillion dollar company by not squeezing every penny you can out of your poor, unsuspecting consumers... so Tim Cook, if you're reading this, fuck off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Amazon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span &gt;Ya boy Bezos has been in the news a lot recently, and rightly so - it seems he is the poster boy for everything wrong with capitalism. After reading accounts of appalling working conditions in Amazon factories across the world, I am going to see how practical it is to stop ordering anything from Amazon over the next few months - I don't think it should be too bad, and I'm happy to pay more in shipping for the peace of mind that comes with knowing the company who I am supporting doesn't make its workers &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/16/17243026/amazon-warehouse-jobs-worker-conditions-bathroom-breaks&quot;&gt;terrified of peeing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;There is a problem with Amazon and I though... Like Messenger and Youtube, Amazon provides a service which I cannot see myself moving away from and there are no good alternatives - Twitch. Twitch hosts the vast majority of the content for esports, my biggest passion in life, it's biggest competitors in that regard being... Youtube and Facebook. For fuck's sake. Perhaps this will be my legacy - an open-source, peer to peer esports streaming platform... I'll add it to the list of projects to start &quot;when I have the time&quot;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span &gt;Overall, writing this out has made me kinda bummed I still rely on the Big Five so much. I'll report back in a couple of weeks to see if I've made any progress.&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Internet of Things" /><category term="Ethics" /><summary type="html">In the last few months I have become more and more disillusioned with our corporate overlords, the Big Five - Apple, Alphabet (Google's parent company), Microsoft, Facebook and Amazon. I am scared about what they have already done to our society and what they continue to do, that they are eroding not only the foundations of the internet but also our basic human right to privacy, and tearing at our social fabric.Sure, my tinfoil hat is pretty screwed on at this point, but I'm not sure I need to explain in too much detail why I think these companies are bad, it just seems as a society we have collectively accepted our fate. But, in an effort to make myself feel better about life, a couple of weeks ago, I decided to see how much of these five companies I could remove from my life. The answer is - not very much. But here is what I found.MicrosoftMicrosoft is probably the company out of the five that I have the least qualms with, however this could be due to lack of sensationalist articles on Hacker News about them more than any kind of higher level of business ethics. The fact they don't run their own ad network helps a lot, as does the fact they sell proprietary products, and ironically the fact I don't use any Bing services probably means I like them more as I am have no idea what their ad or tracking policies are like.&amp;nbsp;At the moment my home PC and all my laptops (and a VM) are running various versions of Windows. As of this weekend, my PC now dual-boots Windows 10 and Kali Linux, but I can't see myself ever making the switch full time to Linux, due to the lack of software support on the latter. I'm excited to get to grips with Unix and try to learn some pentesting on Kali though, I think it will improve my computing knowledge a lot.FacebookAh, Zark Fuckerberg, get your hands out of my data. I would put money on Facebook being the first test case for GDPR in EU court, after another massive breach this past week. The old &quot;if you're not paying, you're the product&quot; isn't quite as poetic and universally true as some might think, but in Facebook's case I absolutely believe it.Sadly... I am struggling to carve Facebook out of my life. Despite having deactivated my Facebook account proper, I have retained use of its Messenger app, as it's the way I communicate with most of my friends, and I fear ditching that too would leave me something of a social leper. You win this time, Fuckerberg.AlphabetOh Google... how far you have fallen in my estimation. Once a company I trusted, now I am in the process of migrating away from as many of its services as possible, during which I have discovered quite how many Google services I previously used. Chrome 69 was really the last straw from me, despite being a Chrome user since sometime around version 1, they have shown their true colours in that all they want is your juicy, juicy data. Well, no more! Below are the services I use and what I have been replacing them with. Big shout-out to https://nomoregoogle.comBrowser: Google Chrome to Brave at home, Firefox at work. Considering trying Vivaldi out too.Search engine: Google to Duck Duck Go.Email: Haven't actually ditched Gmail yet, looking into FastMail and ProtonMail as alternatives.Docs/Sheets: Docs will probably get replaced by Evernote, Sheets undecided. I haven't needed to use either service recently.Youtube: Sadly there is no real alternative to Youtube. Its biggest competitor for video content is Facebook, withVimeo and Dailymotion quite some ways behind, both lacking content. Peertube is interesting conceptually but my experience with the federated model a la Mastodon hasn't been great so far.Maps: Gmaps to OpenStreetMap which is my new favourite thing.Authenticator: In the process of migrating to AuthyBlogging: I swear to god at some point I will finally get a Jekyll site running on Github pages which will host this blog. If not I owe somebody a beer.DNS: Swapped to Cloudflare last week, works like a dream.File storage: Drive to Dropbox, will look at MEGA too.Domain: currently looking for a domain registrar that is both not in the Fortune 500 and also provides service that isn't 100% awful.... suggestions appreciated.AppleDo you have any idea how tedious it is to switch away from an iPhone once you already have an iPhone? All your apps, contacts, data etc is stored in Apple's corner of the ever-mysterious &quot;cloud&quot;, and the prospect of having to manually generate it all again is one that doesn't bear thinking about. Also, most of the viable alternatives are made by some other giant megacorp tech company so it wouldn't even make me feel that much better.&amp;nbsp;As with Microsoft, at least I am actually paying for a product here, so perhaps that means that Apple don't have any incentive to harvest my data. After all, it's pretty widely thought that they make an insane markup on each phone, I suspect due to cheap labour and poor conditions in their manufacturing plants in China. Having said that, you don't become the world's first trillion dollar company by not squeezing every penny you can out of your poor, unsuspecting consumers... so Tim Cook, if you're reading this, fuck off.AmazonYa boy Bezos has been in the news a lot recently, and rightly so - it seems he is the poster boy for everything wrong with capitalism. After reading accounts of appalling working conditions in Amazon factories across the world, I am going to see how practical it is to stop ordering anything from Amazon over the next few months - I don't think it should be too bad, and I'm happy to pay more in shipping for the peace of mind that comes with knowing the company who I am supporting doesn't make its workers terrified of peeing.There is a problem with Amazon and I though... Like Messenger and Youtube, Amazon provides a service which I cannot see myself moving away from and there are no good alternatives - Twitch. Twitch hosts the vast majority of the content for esports, my biggest passion in life, it's biggest competitors in that regard being... Youtube and Facebook. For fuck's sake. Perhaps this will be my legacy - an open-source, peer to peer esports streaming platform... I'll add it to the list of projects to start &quot;when I have the time&quot;.Overall, writing this out has made me kinda bummed I still rely on the Big Five so much. I'll report back in a couple of weeks to see if I've made any progress.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Relating to People</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/02/relating-to-people.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Relating to People" /><published>2018-10-02T21:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T21:15:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/02/relating-to-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/10/02/relating-to-people.html">&lt;span &gt;I had my first meeting with a new therapist today. My homework for the week is to think about how I relate to people, what I do well or not so well etc. I think the answer is likely to be that I don't do a great job, but I'm trying to be objective about it all. I'm sure I'll write some of my thoughts about it all later in the week.&lt;/span&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">I had my first meeting with a new therapist today. My homework for the week is to think about how I relate to people, what I do well or not so well etc. I think the answer is likely to be that I don't do a great job, but I'm trying to be objective about it all. I'm sure I'll write some of my thoughts about it all later in the week.</summary></entry></feed>