<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-11T10:49:06+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Positive Juice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/11/positive-juice" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positive Juice" /><published>2018-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/11/positive-juice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/11/positive-juice">&lt;p&gt;
  I am typing this from the Wagamama in Gatwick Airport Departures. Beside my laptop
  is an arrogantly green 'positive juice'. I ordered it in the hope that it will
  imbue me with some of its positivity, and I might be able to shake off my usual
  drab cynicism, at least for the time I am sat here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm trying really hard to let it do its thing. London has already somewhat brightened
  my disposition - I love coming here, at least in small doses. It feels like
  stuff is happening, ideas are being shared, people are struggling for something.
  If I lived here I think my anxiety would get the better of me pretty quickly,
  but still. It gives me some hope - there is a big wide world out there, away
  from the weird bubble on Guernsey that I live in. In London I could do anything,
  and I could be anyone - I like that feeling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This trip is the happiest I have been... since my last trip to London. So I guess
  I should book another one soon - I am already considering coming back to see
  Mom Jeans in January. The real question is, how can I carry this feeling back
  over the Channel with me? I don't want to go back home and be sad immediately.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think I've felt a lot less guilt this trip than I would at home. I woke up
  at 8am instead of 6am, and played on my phone in bed for an hour - and felt
  fine about it. I spent a couple of hours in the evenings watching Youtube
  videos on my laptop, and wasn't overwhelmed by the feeling that I should be
  doing something 'productive' instead. Maybe that is what I need to take home
  with me - relaxation. Being able to just absorb fairly mindless media instead
  of trying to learn or build something. Even scheduling in time when I force myself
  to play games or catch up on Youtube.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Maybe I'll ask them for the recipe for this juice, and get a juicer, and every
  day in the morning I'll wake up and the first thing I'll do will be to make
  myself a positive juice. We'll have to see.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I am typing this from the Wagamama in Gatwick Airport Departures. Beside my laptop is an arrogantly green 'positive juice'. I ordered it in the hope that it will imbue me with some of its positivity, and I might be able to shake off my usual drab cynicism, at least for the time I am sat here. I'm trying really hard to let it do its thing. London has already somewhat brightened my disposition - I love coming here, at least in small doses. It feels like stuff is happening, ideas are being shared, people are struggling for something. If I lived here I think my anxiety would get the better of me pretty quickly, but still. It gives me some hope - there is a big wide world out there, away from the weird bubble on Guernsey that I live in. In London I could do anything, and I could be anyone - I like that feeling. This trip is the happiest I have been... since my last trip to London. So I guess I should book another one soon - I am already considering coming back to see Mom Jeans in January. The real question is, how can I carry this feeling back over the Channel with me? I don't want to go back home and be sad immediately. I think I've felt a lot less guilt this trip than I would at home. I woke up at 8am instead of 6am, and played on my phone in bed for an hour - and felt fine about it. I spent a couple of hours in the evenings watching Youtube videos on my laptop, and wasn't overwhelmed by the feeling that I should be doing something 'productive' instead. Maybe that is what I need to take home with me - relaxation. Being able to just absorb fairly mindless media instead of trying to learn or build something. Even scheduling in time when I force myself to play games or catch up on Youtube. Maybe I'll ask them for the recipe for this juice, and get a juicer, and every day in the morning I'll wake up and the first thing I'll do will be to make myself a positive juice. We'll have to see.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflecting On: an iPhone noted dated 19th November 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/10/reflections-on-iphone-note-dated-19th-november-2017" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflecting On&amp;#58; an iPhone noted dated 19th November 2017" /><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/10/reflections-on-iphone-note-dated-19th-november-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/10/reflections-on-iphone-note-dated-19th-november-2017">&lt;p&gt;
  While I originally started writing this series (it feels so
  arrogant to call a group of these thematically linked posts a series)
  with the idea of looking at old blog posts I've written, there are
  a lot of other things from my past I think may be worth reflecting on
  as well. Some are videos I've made, some are journal entries, email
  or IM correspondence, forum posts... and this one is a note on my iPhone,
  dated almost a year ago, on 19th November 2017.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The note reads thusly:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Goals:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Fall in love again
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I don't explicitly remember writing this. I assume the idea was that I was
  going to add more goals, but that I forgot. It does make sound like I'm a
  bit of a naive loser (and I am), but there is something quite poetic about
  the fact that I left it like that I think. It is a noble goal and one that
  I suspect most people strive for, we are just too proud to admint it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Having it as my sole aim is interesting too. What would I do differently if
  the only thing in life I was searching for was love, with no regard for career,
  fulfillment, health, friends or anything else? I think I would still spend
  time on those things: being healthy and happy, with a good group of friends
  and a fulfilling career is going to make me much more attractive, and likelier
  to find love. Would I try and meet more new people, or connect more strongly
  to those I already know? Would I try different strategies to overcome my
  social anxiety, or only seek out someone who 'loved me for me'?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It is a good only goal to have. I would put it as my only goal presently, if
  I didn't think it had one horrible flaw. It inherently focuses too much on the
  end result, and not the journey. If my only goal was to fall in love, rejections
  would be incomprehensibly painful. Over time, if I wasn't successful then I
  expect my self esteem would decrease even further. I think my 'all or nothing'
  mindset would stop me from forming emotionally fulfilling relationships of any
  kind with people who I had already mentally decided were not the One, with a
  capital 'O'.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So I'm going to stick with working on myself, and hope that somewhere along
  the line, the 'fall' happens purely accidentally - like most literal falls do.
  Falling in love is more of a bucket list thing, than a meaningful, achievable
  goal.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Relationships" /><summary type="html">While I originally started writing this series (it feels so arrogant to call a group of these thematically linked posts a series) with the idea of looking at old blog posts I've written, there are a lot of other things from my past I think may be worth reflecting on as well. Some are videos I've made, some are journal entries, email or IM correspondence, forum posts... and this one is a note on my iPhone, dated almost a year ago, on 19th November 2017. The note reads thusly: Goals: Fall in love again I don't explicitly remember writing this. I assume the idea was that I was going to add more goals, but that I forgot. It does make sound like I'm a bit of a naive loser (and I am), but there is something quite poetic about the fact that I left it like that I think. It is a noble goal and one that I suspect most people strive for, we are just too proud to admint it. Having it as my sole aim is interesting too. What would I do differently if the only thing in life I was searching for was love, with no regard for career, fulfillment, health, friends or anything else? I think I would still spend time on those things: being healthy and happy, with a good group of friends and a fulfilling career is going to make me much more attractive, and likelier to find love. Would I try and meet more new people, or connect more strongly to those I already know? Would I try different strategies to overcome my social anxiety, or only seek out someone who 'loved me for me'? It is a good only goal to have. I would put it as my only goal presently, if I didn't think it had one horrible flaw. It inherently focuses too much on the end result, and not the journey. If my only goal was to fall in love, rejections would be incomprehensibly painful. Over time, if I wasn't successful then I expect my self esteem would decrease even further. I think my 'all or nothing' mindset would stop me from forming emotionally fulfilling relationships of any kind with people who I had already mentally decided were not the One, with a capital 'O'. So I'm going to stick with working on myself, and hope that somewhere along the line, the 'fall' happens purely accidentally - like most literal falls do. Falling in love is more of a bucket list thing, than a meaningful, achievable goal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Belonging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/09/belonging" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Belonging" /><published>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/09/belonging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/09/belonging">&lt;p&gt;
  First of all, yesterday I saw Car Seat Headrest and they were &lt;strong&gt;amazing.&lt;/strong&gt;
  They are a band that I have loved for years, and are probably sneaking into my
  top three favourite bands of all time, so to finally be able to see them play
  live was a great experience, and one which was on my currently rather underwhelming
  bucket list.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The band has gained a significant following over the past couple of years, and so
  it wasn't a proper basement gig, but the venue still had a pretty intimate feeling.
  The official capacity is listed as 2300, and it felt pretty full, but I would've
  guessed that there were fewer than 2300 people there - perhaps I am bad at estimating
  crowds though. The point is - it was by no means huge.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  CSH are, in my opinion, a somewhat polarising band - they are likely to either
  be one of your absolute favourites, or you find their music wholly unpalatable.
  That means that when you go to one of their shows, a lot of the people there are
  fairly hardcore fans who &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; love their music.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The relatively small venue combined with especially zealous fans allows something
  amazing to happen. I know most of the words to most CSH songs. Everyone else
  also appeared to know most of the words to most of the songs. In quiet moments,
  or during the chorus, or just for lines that lent themselves well to singing along...
  you could hear the crowd so loudly. Sometimes they drowned out the singing from
  the band themselves. Two thousand voices in unison, unashamedly belting out
  emotional, introspective lyrics into the rafters. I think a lot of CSH fans, myself
  included, enjoy the band's music largely because of the lyricism of frontman Will
  Toledo, and experience a very human connection through his music. Usually,
  if I am just listening to them through my headphones, I only feel that connection with him,
  with one human being, and even then, he obviously has no idea who I am and it is
  completely unilateral. But when there is a room full of people, the connection
  is with &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt; in the room. It felt like something really special to me.
  It felt like I had found my people, like I was part of something bigger, like
  this was where I belonged.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Which is a long way of getting to the point I wanted to make in this post. I am
  led to believe, through reading things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://80000hours.org&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  80000 Hours,&lt;/a&gt; through conversations with my therapist and through my personal
  experience, that feeling part of something bigger contributes a lot to an
  individual's happiness. Intuitively this seems true to me because I think the
  reverse often makes me unhappy - I feel isolated and disconnected, even if I
  still meet up with my friends and participate in society, I don't feel like I
  belong.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This is the reason I started painting my nails (and wish I could do so again).
  It was a way of saying to the world &quot;if you think this is weird, then I am not
  like you. I am not part of what you are part of.&quot; It's also the reason I enjoyed
  and embraced GTO club so fully - I felt like part of something bigger, I had
  found a group of like-minded people who were all striving to achieve their goals
  and become better people.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But now GTO club is dead. Sure, I could go to more CSH gigs, but that'd be
  insanely expensive, and even then, they only last for a couple of hours at a time.
  Same story with esports LAN events.
  I felt like I belonged when I fenced at university, another option I no longer
  have. I don't feel like part of anything grander at my job - only one person
  meaningfully contributes to our codebase, and it isn't me.
  Most of my friends don't share most of my interests. When I go to the gym, I
  have never made the effort to talk to anyone apart from the select few
  people I know, even if I see them there 5x a week. In the chess league I am
  still the youngest player by about a decade, and the mean age is likely double
  mine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Perhaps I am just whining, as always, painting myself as a victim and looking
  for your pity. That I am somehow better than everyone around me, and that is
  why I don't belong. I hope that is not how I come across, but accept that it probably
  is. Regardless, it would still be nice to be part of something, and be happier.
  Perhaps that is why I have grown more socially conscious, in the hopes that I
  can work towards a common goal with a large group of people, something that we
  all care about. Perhaps I will find what I am looking for in the open source
  community, if I can build up my skills sufficiently and actively participate
  in it. Perhaps I will end up returning to university at some point, and will
  feel at home in academia.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But, as always, I really have no idea. Suggestions appreciated.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">First of all, yesterday I saw Car Seat Headrest and they were amazing. They are a band that I have loved for years, and are probably sneaking into my top three favourite bands of all time, so to finally be able to see them play live was a great experience, and one which was on my currently rather underwhelming bucket list. The band has gained a significant following over the past couple of years, and so it wasn't a proper basement gig, but the venue still had a pretty intimate feeling. The official capacity is listed as 2300, and it felt pretty full, but I would've guessed that there were fewer than 2300 people there - perhaps I am bad at estimating crowds though. The point is - it was by no means huge. CSH are, in my opinion, a somewhat polarising band - they are likely to either be one of your absolute favourites, or you find their music wholly unpalatable. That means that when you go to one of their shows, a lot of the people there are fairly hardcore fans who really love their music. The relatively small venue combined with especially zealous fans allows something amazing to happen. I know most of the words to most CSH songs. Everyone else also appeared to know most of the words to most of the songs. In quiet moments, or during the chorus, or just for lines that lent themselves well to singing along... you could hear the crowd so loudly. Sometimes they drowned out the singing from the band themselves. Two thousand voices in unison, unashamedly belting out emotional, introspective lyrics into the rafters. I think a lot of CSH fans, myself included, enjoy the band's music largely because of the lyricism of frontman Will Toledo, and experience a very human connection through his music. Usually, if I am just listening to them through my headphones, I only feel that connection with him, with one human being, and even then, he obviously has no idea who I am and it is completely unilateral. But when there is a room full of people, the connection is with everyone in the room. It felt like something really special to me. It felt like I had found my people, like I was part of something bigger, like this was where I belonged. Which is a long way of getting to the point I wanted to make in this post. I am led to believe, through reading things like 80000 Hours, through conversations with my therapist and through my personal experience, that feeling part of something bigger contributes a lot to an individual's happiness. Intuitively this seems true to me because I think the reverse often makes me unhappy - I feel isolated and disconnected, even if I still meet up with my friends and participate in society, I don't feel like I belong. This is the reason I started painting my nails (and wish I could do so again). It was a way of saying to the world &quot;if you think this is weird, then I am not like you. I am not part of what you are part of.&quot; It's also the reason I enjoyed and embraced GTO club so fully - I felt like part of something bigger, I had found a group of like-minded people who were all striving to achieve their goals and become better people. But now GTO club is dead. Sure, I could go to more CSH gigs, but that'd be insanely expensive, and even then, they only last for a couple of hours at a time. Same story with esports LAN events. I felt like I belonged when I fenced at university, another option I no longer have. I don't feel like part of anything grander at my job - only one person meaningfully contributes to our codebase, and it isn't me. Most of my friends don't share most of my interests. When I go to the gym, I have never made the effort to talk to anyone apart from the select few people I know, even if I see them there 5x a week. In the chess league I am still the youngest player by about a decade, and the mean age is likely double mine. Perhaps I am just whining, as always, painting myself as a victim and looking for your pity. That I am somehow better than everyone around me, and that is why I don't belong. I hope that is not how I come across, but accept that it probably is. Regardless, it would still be nice to be part of something, and be happier. Perhaps that is why I have grown more socially conscious, in the hopes that I can work towards a common goal with a large group of people, something that we all care about. Perhaps I will find what I am looking for in the open source community, if I can build up my skills sufficiently and actively participate in it. Perhaps I will end up returning to university at some point, and will feel at home in academia. But, as always, I really have no idea. Suggestions appreciated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflecting On: Success</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/08/reflecting-on-success" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflecting On&amp;#58; Success" /><published>2018-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/08/reflecting-on-success</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/08/reflecting-on-success">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/tartarus/2017/11/08/success&quot;&gt;Success&lt;/a&gt; was, ironically, pretty comfortably
  the most successful post on my old
  Wordpress site, in terms of page views. It is also my favourite post
  there, and probably one of my favourite things I've ever written.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I published it a year ago today, so it seemed appropriate to reflect
  upon some of the things on the list, and maybe see if there is anything
  I can add to it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Firstly, there are quite a few about my sexual exploits. This year
  has... not been successful on that front. But there's always next
  year.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are some cool gaming ones - I would definitely add attending
  FACEIT Major London to the list, a LAN much bigger than Dreamhack
  London. Seeing 10000 nerds all packed into an arena cheering
  at some other nerds playing videogames on a stage really validated
  my lifelong commitment to nerdom. I made good on my promise to get
  a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.speedrun.com/Refunct/run/mekevn3m&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  sub 3 minute Refunct run&lt;/a&gt; too!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The handful about poker and career were obviously written from a different
  place. I'm happy that I still view all those things as achievements,
  even if I didn't turn out to be the next cumicon. Would I add anything
  to the list on this topic? Perhaps, I think getting hired for a position
  I am aggressively underqualified for is something of an achievement. I built
  my first two commercial sites, and I actually think they are of a reasonable quality.
  I designed and built this site, although 'designed' is a bit of a stretch. Overall,
  some neat things, and some things I ought to recognise as successes - but
  I am more excited for potential greater career achievements in the next couple of years.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One of the items from the list year really sticks out for me in the context of
  the last 365 days - #65 'kicked depression in the dick'. It turns out, that
  injuring something's genitals is actually only exceptionally rarely fatal.
  Considering depression well and truly beaten is one success that I am going
  to have to put on ice for the foreseeable future, although I think there
  are some successes this year that have come out of it - namely, surviving
  and even being a relatively functional member of society. I got and have kept
  a new job, still maintain a good group of friends, and just signed the
  lease for a new flat, despite having really struggled with my mental health
  in the last 12 months. Good job, me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I touched on it in my post yesterday, but one of the biggest changes (and,
  I think, successes) that I see in myself in the last year is that I care about
  stuff a lot more. I have become more socially conscious, I no longer actively
  avoid learning about politics, I closely follow tech news, I want to change my own lifestyle to combat
  climate change, I want to contribute to effective altruism etc. This time last year,
  I was very much more focused on myself, and my own success, viewing those other
  things as distractions that would cause me stress and sadness. Now, I think
  these things can help me feel like part of something bigger, which I am led
  to believe could make me happier.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's been a difficult year, and in some ways there aren't many new successes
  of the ilk that I wrote about last year. But I think there are plenty of more
  subtle, nuanced ones, that make me excited about the next year.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And, it is my birthday, which means I am listening to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YTFAXK-f4N4&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;
  this song&lt;/a&gt; all day.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Success was, ironically, pretty comfortably the most successful post on my old Wordpress site, in terms of page views. It is also my favourite post there, and probably one of my favourite things I've ever written. I published it a year ago today, so it seemed appropriate to reflect upon some of the things on the list, and maybe see if there is anything I can add to it. Firstly, there are quite a few about my sexual exploits. This year has... not been successful on that front. But there's always next year. There are some cool gaming ones - I would definitely add attending FACEIT Major London to the list, a LAN much bigger than Dreamhack London. Seeing 10000 nerds all packed into an arena cheering at some other nerds playing videogames on a stage really validated my lifelong commitment to nerdom. I made good on my promise to get a sub 3 minute Refunct run too! The handful about poker and career were obviously written from a different place. I'm happy that I still view all those things as achievements, even if I didn't turn out to be the next cumicon. Would I add anything to the list on this topic? Perhaps, I think getting hired for a position I am aggressively underqualified for is something of an achievement. I built my first two commercial sites, and I actually think they are of a reasonable quality. I designed and built this site, although 'designed' is a bit of a stretch. Overall, some neat things, and some things I ought to recognise as successes - but I am more excited for potential greater career achievements in the next couple of years. One of the items from the list year really sticks out for me in the context of the last 365 days - #65 'kicked depression in the dick'. It turns out, that injuring something's genitals is actually only exceptionally rarely fatal. Considering depression well and truly beaten is one success that I am going to have to put on ice for the foreseeable future, although I think there are some successes this year that have come out of it - namely, surviving and even being a relatively functional member of society. I got and have kept a new job, still maintain a good group of friends, and just signed the lease for a new flat, despite having really struggled with my mental health in the last 12 months. Good job, me. I touched on it in my post yesterday, but one of the biggest changes (and, I think, successes) that I see in myself in the last year is that I care about stuff a lot more. I have become more socially conscious, I no longer actively avoid learning about politics, I closely follow tech news, I want to change my own lifestyle to combat climate change, I want to contribute to effective altruism etc. This time last year, I was very much more focused on myself, and my own success, viewing those other things as distractions that would cause me stress and sadness. Now, I think these things can help me feel like part of something bigger, which I am led to believe could make me happier. It's been a difficult year, and in some ways there aren't many new successes of the ilk that I wrote about last year. But I think there are plenty of more subtle, nuanced ones, that make me excited about the next year. And, it is my birthday, which means I am listening to this song all day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Red and Blue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/07/red-and-blue" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Red and Blue" /><published>2018-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/07/red-and-blue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/07/red-and-blue">&lt;p&gt;
  It is pretty bizarre to me how big a part of news media aimed at me consists
  of US politics. Even UK politics ought not to effect me that much, given
  that Guernsey is self-governing, but I can forgive people here an interest
  in our mainland counterparts. American politics on the other hand... is
  thousands of miles away. I hope it will never really effect me, and I suspect
  it will certainly never meaningful change my existence unless we enter some
  kind of mutually-assured-destruction scenario.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With that being said, I have in general pretty liberal views, and more and
  more governments across the world seem to be shifting to the right. I think
  this is, uh, bad. Because it's incongruent with my views, and I'm a bit
  worried about what's going to become of humanity as a species if our
  societies shift that way. I don't really know anything about anything
  though, so I probably don't really get to have an opinion on the subject
  of politics.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With all that being said, I read a little about the results of the US
  mid terms today, and in general it seemed positive for us liberal snowflakes.
  So, good job everybody. 
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Politics" /><category term="Social Consciousness" /><summary type="html">It is pretty bizarre to me how big a part of news media aimed at me consists of US politics. Even UK politics ought not to effect me that much, given that Guernsey is self-governing, but I can forgive people here an interest in our mainland counterparts. American politics on the other hand... is thousands of miles away. I hope it will never really effect me, and I suspect it will certainly never meaningful change my existence unless we enter some kind of mutually-assured-destruction scenario. With that being said, I have in general pretty liberal views, and more and more governments across the world seem to be shifting to the right. I think this is, uh, bad. Because it's incongruent with my views, and I'm a bit worried about what's going to become of humanity as a species if our societies shift that way. I don't really know anything about anything though, so I probably don't really get to have an opinion on the subject of politics. With all that being said, I read a little about the results of the US mid terms today, and in general it seemed positive for us liberal snowflakes. So, good job everybody.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Plant Based Diet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/06/plant-based-diet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plant Based Diet" /><published>2018-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/06/plant-based-diet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/06/plant-based-diet">&lt;p&gt;
  Following on from my &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/10/26/lifestyle-changes.html&quot;&gt;
  post on Oct 26th,&lt;/a&gt; I am planning on going a step further than cutting
  out red meat, and am going to at least try a fully plant-based, vegan
  diet. I signed the lease on a new flat yesterday with a friend, and move in
  on January 29th, so I have nearly two full months of research and planning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have made these kinds of statements, especially about diet, many times before,
  and I have failed to follow through on them pretty much without exception.
  What will be different this time? I am hoping a change in living situation,
  combined with a roommate who has a generally pretty healthy lifestyle,
  will be a good start towards possible change. Perhaps the socially
  conscious nature of the change will help too, and maybe if I obnoxiously
  blog about it all the time, that will keep me accountable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Or maybe I'll just book a massive freeroll.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Diet and Fitness" /><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Following on from my post on Oct 26th, I am planning on going a step further than cutting out red meat, and am going to at least try a fully plant-based, vegan diet. I signed the lease on a new flat yesterday with a friend, and move in on January 29th, so I have nearly two full months of research and planning. I have made these kinds of statements, especially about diet, many times before, and I have failed to follow through on them pretty much without exception. What will be different this time? I am hoping a change in living situation, combined with a roommate who has a generally pretty healthy lifestyle, will be a good start towards possible change. Perhaps the socially conscious nature of the change will help too, and maybe if I obnoxiously blog about it all the time, that will keep me accountable. Or maybe I'll just book a massive freeroll.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Just like cooking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/05/just-like-cooking" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just like cooking" /><published>2018-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/05/just-like-cooking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/05/just-like-cooking">&lt;p&gt;
  I caught up with a poker friend that I had not spoken to in a very
  long time over the weekend. He had just got back into playing full time
  after having taken a year away from the game to complete his studies,
  and his reflections on his return to the game were insightful and
  hilarious in equal measure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Paraphrased:
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Poker is so frustrating. In almost everything else in life, you
      get instant feedback... like in cooking. If you burn your food, you
      know you fucked up. In poker, you can play perfectly and still burn
      your food over and over again.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Hearing him say that sentence made me unbelievably glad I no longer
  have to deal with the stress of playing poker full time.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Poker" /><summary type="html">I caught up with a poker friend that I had not spoken to in a very long time over the weekend. He had just got back into playing full time after having taken a year away from the game to complete his studies, and his reflections on his return to the game were insightful and hilarious in equal measure. Paraphrased: Poker is so frustrating. In almost everything else in life, you get instant feedback... like in cooking. If you burn your food, you know you fucked up. In poker, you can play perfectly and still burn your food over and over again. Hearing him say that sentence made me unbelievably glad I no longer have to deal with the stress of playing poker full time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Serral</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/04/serral" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Serral" /><published>2018-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/04/serral</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/04/serral">&lt;p&gt;
  Last night, Joona &quot;Serral&quot; Sotala made esports history. He was the first non-Korean
  player to reach the world championship final in the 20 years the game has had one -
  but not only that, the Finnish Zerg won, becoming the first world champion
  not to carry the Korean flag.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  For some context - in Starcraft, Koreans are so dominant that any player who
  is not Korean is simply referred to as a &quot;foreigner&quot;. It's been a running joke
  in the Starcraft community for years, that even mediocre Koreans will always
  outshine foreign players. When any passionate fans are debating the greatest
  foreigners of all time, it will always come down to the very small handful
  who have been able to compete with Koreans and come out roughly equal. But none of them
  have achieved what Serral has achieved - on top of winning the world championship,
  he won all four major non-Korean tournaments this year, and GSL vs the World,
  the clash of the two regions (GSL is the top Korean league). He was also the first
  foreigner to take the crown in that tournament, and is one of a select few foreigners
  to have won a major tournament on Korean soil.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Before the world championships, there were whispers that the gap was closing.
  Reddit was unusually optimistic. The Korean players, usually dismissive of
  foreigners in interviews, didn't want to get drawn against Serral. They were scared -
  they didn't want to be the ones to lose to a foreigner. But they all did:
  Serral defeated an all-star lineup of the best players Seoul has to offer,
  having faced a Korean player in every single match he played in the tournament.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The first time I watched Serral play Starcraft, it was at Dreamhack Valencia 2013,
  when he was 14. He took a game off Life, who would go on to be the world champion
  next year, and is considered one of the best players of the modern era.
  I remember thinking Serral was promising for his age, but I never
  imagined he would achieve what he has this year. Before, fans would talk about
  which player would be the &quot;foreign hope&quot;. Serral has made our hope a reality,
  in one of the most inspiring and emotional displays of skill I've ever seen on an esports
  stage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Thank you Serral, for making me proud to be a fan of Starcraft, esports and gaming.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Torille.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="esports" /><summary type="html">Last night, Joona &quot;Serral&quot; Sotala made esports history. He was the first non-Korean player to reach the world championship final in the 20 years the game has had one - but not only that, the Finnish Zerg won, becoming the first world champion not to carry the Korean flag. For some context - in Starcraft, Koreans are so dominant that any player who is not Korean is simply referred to as a &quot;foreigner&quot;. It's been a running joke in the Starcraft community for years, that even mediocre Koreans will always outshine foreign players. When any passionate fans are debating the greatest foreigners of all time, it will always come down to the very small handful who have been able to compete with Koreans and come out roughly equal. But none of them have achieved what Serral has achieved - on top of winning the world championship, he won all four major non-Korean tournaments this year, and GSL vs the World, the clash of the two regions (GSL is the top Korean league). He was also the first foreigner to take the crown in that tournament, and is one of a select few foreigners to have won a major tournament on Korean soil. Before the world championships, there were whispers that the gap was closing. Reddit was unusually optimistic. The Korean players, usually dismissive of foreigners in interviews, didn't want to get drawn against Serral. They were scared - they didn't want to be the ones to lose to a foreigner. But they all did: Serral defeated an all-star lineup of the best players Seoul has to offer, having faced a Korean player in every single match he played in the tournament. The first time I watched Serral play Starcraft, it was at Dreamhack Valencia 2013, when he was 14. He took a game off Life, who would go on to be the world champion next year, and is considered one of the best players of the modern era. I remember thinking Serral was promising for his age, but I never imagined he would achieve what he has this year. Before, fans would talk about which player would be the &quot;foreign hope&quot;. Serral has made our hope a reality, in one of the most inspiring and emotional displays of skill I've ever seen on an esports stage. Thank you Serral, for making me proud to be a fan of Starcraft, esports and gaming. Torille.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I expect myself to have more than 24 hours in a day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/03/i-expect-myself-to-have-more-than-24-hours-in-a-day" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I expect myself to have more than 24 hours in a day" /><published>2018-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/03/i-expect-myself-to-have-more-than-24-hours-in-a-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/03/i-expect-myself-to-have-more-than-24-hours-in-a-day">&lt;p&gt;
  For a few years now, I have been a fan of the idea that your happiness is
  your reality minus your expectations. It seems to make a lot of sense to me,
  but I have never been very happy, despite having what I thought were low
  expectations. Having thought about it a little more recently, with some help
  from my therapist... I actually have insane, wholly unrealistic expectations.
  Here are some of them:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to improve my front end web dev skills very rapidly, across multiple
    languages and frameworks;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to improve my back end web dev skills very rapidly, across multiple
    languages and frameworks;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to pick up other software development skills and programming languages,
    including machine learning in python, native app development, c++ development,
    unit testing, scalable database management...;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to improve my computer science knowledge, and pass CS50 as quickly
    as possible;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to improve at basic maths, including linear algebra and algorithms;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to learn about the world, and keep up to date with the latest news
    in technology and science;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to learn about penetration, be able to secure bug bounties, and
    keep up with CVEs for all major platforms and devices;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to be working on multiple coding side-projects, be building useful
    applications and growing my portfolio;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to be completely comfortable using the Linux command line to do anything,
    as well as having an excellent knowledge of Windows and MacOS;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to be able to understand every stage of deployment and scaling for an
    app on an Apache server, and have a thorough understanding of Apache in general;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to go to the gym 5-6 times a week, and see an improvement in my
    cardiovascular fitness and all three main lifts;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to eat less and lose weight;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to get better at chess;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to maintain a group of friends, spend time with them,
    and get closer to some of them;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to be likeable, unawkward, and easily form a rapport with new people
    I meet;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to spend more time with my brother, give him good advice and help him
    be happier and maximise his life experience;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect not to upset, anger or disappoint my friends, family or coworkers;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect myself to have other hobbies and interests outside of tech, chess
    and the gym, and I expect myself to try and be open to trying new things;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to get 8+ hours of sleep every night;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect my career to progress rapidly;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect myself to overcome my anxiety and depression;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I expect to be able to do this, with only 24 hours in a day, without succumbing
    to stress, while being able to balance relaxation that doesn't contribute to
    my personal growth, eg following esports.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Why I expect all this is a story for another day. But, I think I figured out
  why I'm sad all the time.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">For a few years now, I have been a fan of the idea that your happiness is your reality minus your expectations. It seems to make a lot of sense to me, but I have never been very happy, despite having what I thought were low expectations. Having thought about it a little more recently, with some help from my therapist... I actually have insane, wholly unrealistic expectations. Here are some of them: I expect to improve my front end web dev skills very rapidly, across multiple languages and frameworks; I expect to improve my back end web dev skills very rapidly, across multiple languages and frameworks; I expect to pick up other software development skills and programming languages, including machine learning in python, native app development, c++ development, unit testing, scalable database management...; I expect to improve my computer science knowledge, and pass CS50 as quickly as possible; I expect to improve at basic maths, including linear algebra and algorithms; I expect to learn about the world, and keep up to date with the latest news in technology and science; I expect to learn about penetration, be able to secure bug bounties, and keep up with CVEs for all major platforms and devices; I expect to be working on multiple coding side-projects, be building useful applications and growing my portfolio; I expect to be completely comfortable using the Linux command line to do anything, as well as having an excellent knowledge of Windows and MacOS; I expect to be able to understand every stage of deployment and scaling for an app on an Apache server, and have a thorough understanding of Apache in general; I expect to go to the gym 5-6 times a week, and see an improvement in my cardiovascular fitness and all three main lifts; I expect to eat less and lose weight; I expect to get better at chess; I expect to maintain a group of friends, spend time with them, and get closer to some of them; I expect to be likeable, unawkward, and easily form a rapport with new people I meet; I expect to spend more time with my brother, give him good advice and help him be happier and maximise his life experience; I expect not to upset, anger or disappoint my friends, family or coworkers; I expect myself to have other hobbies and interests outside of tech, chess and the gym, and I expect myself to try and be open to trying new things; I expect to get 8+ hours of sleep every night; I expect my career to progress rapidly; I expect myself to overcome my anxiety and depression; I expect to be able to do this, with only 24 hours in a day, without succumbing to stress, while being able to balance relaxation that doesn't contribute to my personal growth, eg following esports. Why I expect all this is a story for another day. But, I think I figured out why I'm sad all the time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Money Makes Me Sad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/02/money-makes-me-sad" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Money Makes Me Sad" /><published>2018-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/02/money-makes-me-sad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/02/money-makes-me-sad">&lt;p&gt;
  In another post I mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://80000hours.org&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  80000 hours,&lt;/a&gt; and today I read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://80000hours.org/career-guide/anyone-make-a-difference/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  third chapter&lt;/a&gt; in their career guide,
  &quot;No matter your job, here's 3 evidence-based ways anyone can have a real impact&quot;.
  The number one way involves effective altruism, ie donating to charities that
  have been shown to have the biggest impact on human life per dollar donated, or
  bang for your buck if you will.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The reasoning employed is approximately as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Past a certain income threshold, any additional income provides you with
    proportionally less additional happiness and life satisfaction;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    By participating in effective altruism and donating to high-impact charities,
    you can make a substantial, tangible difference to the lives of a meaningful
    number of people by donating, for example, 10% of you income;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    The happiness and satisfaction you will get from making these donations will
    significantly outweigh the happiness you would get from keeping this money,
    and this has been quantifiably proven in studies.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think intuitively this makes a lot of sense and is very likely to be true, without delving
  too much into the studies that are referenced. Before I continue, I am admittedly
  below the income/happiness threshold, but it is not inconceivable that I reach it
  in the next few years - I think I am likely to do so by the time I am 30. I also
  don't think it's inconceivable that I would be happier donating 10% of my salary now
  than not doing so. &lt;i&gt;But...&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  When I think about making a commitment to donating a significant portion of my salary,
  I think about the following:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I need to support my parents financially in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I need to support my brother financially in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I get made redundant and am unable to find work in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I want to have kids in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I want to own my own property in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I get seriously ill in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And on a perhaps less critical but still arguably equally valid note:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I want to go travelling in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What if I want to buy x, y or z nice thing in the future?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;Can I use the entirety of my income to maximise my own human experience in my lifetime?&lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And that... made me kinda sad. I would imagine my mindset if very similar to
  a lot of people in Western society - we have a lot of different pressures driving
  us to try to generate as much wealth as possible. It contributes a lot to my anxiety,
  a vague sense of fear of not having accrued enough capital at some arbitrary point
  in the future. I don't think I spend recklessly, but I could definitely be more
  frugal or save more aggressively, and sometimes that leads me to feel guilty
  about a bunch of really small things that I don't need to be feeling guilty
  about at this point in my life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  As always, I don't know what the answer is. Perhaps I'll start small. I'm considering
  giving up alcohol - if I do, maybe I'll donate the money I would've spent on beer
  to an effective cause every month. And then I'll blog about it and tell everyone
  about it all the time, and be a real self-righteous prick about the whole thing,
  and if being that prick feels as good as I suspect it might, then I'll donate
  more and be an even greater prick about it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal Finance" /><category term="Effective Altruism" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">In another post I mentioned 80000 hours, and today I read the third chapter in their career guide, &quot;No matter your job, here's 3 evidence-based ways anyone can have a real impact&quot;. The number one way involves effective altruism, ie donating to charities that have been shown to have the biggest impact on human life per dollar donated, or bang for your buck if you will. The reasoning employed is approximately as follows: Past a certain income threshold, any additional income provides you with proportionally less additional happiness and life satisfaction; By participating in effective altruism and donating to high-impact charities, you can make a substantial, tangible difference to the lives of a meaningful number of people by donating, for example, 10% of you income; The happiness and satisfaction you will get from making these donations will significantly outweigh the happiness you would get from keeping this money, and this has been quantifiably proven in studies. I think intuitively this makes a lot of sense and is very likely to be true, without delving too much into the studies that are referenced. Before I continue, I am admittedly below the income/happiness threshold, but it is not inconceivable that I reach it in the next few years - I think I am likely to do so by the time I am 30. I also don't think it's inconceivable that I would be happier donating 10% of my salary now than not doing so. But... When I think about making a commitment to donating a significant portion of my salary, I think about the following: What if I need to support my parents financially in the future? What if I need to support my brother financially in the future? What if I get made redundant and am unable to find work in the future? What if I want to have kids in the future? What if I want to own my own property in the future? What if I get seriously ill in the future? And on a perhaps less critical but still arguably equally valid note: What if I want to go travelling in the future? What if I want to buy x, y or z nice thing in the future? Can I use the entirety of my income to maximise my own human experience in my lifetime? And that... made me kinda sad. I would imagine my mindset if very similar to a lot of people in Western society - we have a lot of different pressures driving us to try to generate as much wealth as possible. It contributes a lot to my anxiety, a vague sense of fear of not having accrued enough capital at some arbitrary point in the future. I don't think I spend recklessly, but I could definitely be more frugal or save more aggressively, and sometimes that leads me to feel guilty about a bunch of really small things that I don't need to be feeling guilty about at this point in my life. As always, I don't know what the answer is. Perhaps I'll start small. I'm considering giving up alcohol - if I do, maybe I'll donate the money I would've spent on beer to an effective cause every month. And then I'll blog about it and tell everyone about it all the time, and be a real self-righteous prick about the whole thing, and if being that prick feels as good as I suspect it might, then I'll donate more and be an even greater prick about it.</summary></entry></feed>