<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-04T18:38:22+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Lessons From Meal Prep</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/04/lessons-from-meal-prep" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lessons From Meal Prep" /><published>2019-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/04/lessons-from-meal-prep</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/04/lessons-from-meal-prep">&lt;p&gt;
  Yesterday I set out with the plan of making 9 meals worth of nutritious, delicious
  food which I could then enjoy throughout the week without having to cook again
  (I ritualistically eat lunch out on Fridays). It was a precedented disaster,
  but I thought it would be fun to share what specifically went wrong and what
  I learned from the experience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 1 - actually buy the ingredients before you cook the dish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I had been planning all week to make a lentil curry. I had the lentils. I had
  rice. I bought vegetables to with them. However, I did not think to buy
  curry powder (or indeed any other spices) until I came to began cooking at
  7pm on a Sunday, by which time the shops were shut.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 2 - don't just wing it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am not a good cook, but at least understand some of the basics. Make things
  hot and they'll taste better (or indeed, become edible at all). Use salt and
  pepper and garlic, not too little but not too much. You're not Heston Blumenthal,
  so pick traditional, non-experimental flavour combinations. If you are cooking
  one portion of food, I think these principles are enough where one could essential
  wing it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If you are cooking an entire week of food, you clearly cannot rely on your
  self-inflated ambition to get the job done. In fact, my 'curry' turned out to
  be a bland mush that is only palatable with copious amounts of sriracha. Do not
  be like me - follow a recipe, you fucking idiot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My 'curry' turned out to be a bland mush that is only palatable with copious
  amounts of sriracha. Do not be like me - follow a recipe, you fucking idiot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 3 - ensure you have enough containers for the food you are going to make&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  When you are making this quantity of food, weigh it - &lt;i&gt;please.&lt;/i&gt; I made
  too much rice. I had too much lentils. The curry did not fit into the wok I own,
  so I had to fire up an auxiliary overflow pan. Then, when it came time to dish
  everything up, I didn't have enough containers for the food I'd made (as it turned
  out, I only had 8 containers, and I'm an idiot). I had to call my mother and
  ask her to bring me some of her tupperware so none of the food would go to waste.
  It was embarrassing, and I wouldn't recommend it in the slightest.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm going to try it all again this Sunday, and I'll let you know if it goes
  any better.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Diet" /><summary type="html">Yesterday I set out with the plan of making 9 meals worth of nutritious, delicious food which I could then enjoy throughout the week without having to cook again (I ritualistically eat lunch out on Fridays). It was a precedented disaster, but I thought it would be fun to share what specifically went wrong and what I learned from the experience. Lesson 1 - actually buy the ingredients before you cook the dish I had been planning all week to make a lentil curry. I had the lentils. I had rice. I bought vegetables to with them. However, I did not think to buy curry powder (or indeed any other spices) until I came to began cooking at 7pm on a Sunday, by which time the shops were shut. Lesson 2 - don't just wing it! I am not a good cook, but at least understand some of the basics. Make things hot and they'll taste better (or indeed, become edible at all). Use salt and pepper and garlic, not too little but not too much. You're not Heston Blumenthal, so pick traditional, non-experimental flavour combinations. If you are cooking one portion of food, I think these principles are enough where one could essential wing it. If you are cooking an entire week of food, you clearly cannot rely on your self-inflated ambition to get the job done. In fact, my 'curry' turned out to be a bland mush that is only palatable with copious amounts of sriracha. Do not be like me - follow a recipe, you fucking idiot. My 'curry' turned out to be a bland mush that is only palatable with copious amounts of sriracha. Do not be like me - follow a recipe, you fucking idiot. Lesson 3 - ensure you have enough containers for the food you are going to make When you are making this quantity of food, weigh it - please. I made too much rice. I had too much lentils. The curry did not fit into the wok I own, so I had to fire up an auxiliary overflow pan. Then, when it came time to dish everything up, I didn't have enough containers for the food I'd made (as it turned out, I only had 8 containers, and I'm an idiot). I had to call my mother and ask her to bring me some of her tupperware so none of the food would go to waste. It was embarrassing, and I wouldn't recommend it in the slightest. I'm going to try it all again this Sunday, and I'll let you know if it goes any better.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Have Too Much Stuff</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/03/i-have-too-much-stuff" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Have Too Much Stuff" /><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/03/i-have-too-much-stuff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/03/i-have-too-much-stuff">&lt;p&gt;
  In the process of moving this week, I became cutely aware of how many boxes of
  largely superfluous possessions I had to painstakingly lug up and down
  multiple flights of stairs. I then compounded this by buying even more
  unnecessary trash, despite being already cogniscent that I had too much of it
  in the first place - everything I purchased, I had persuaded myself was 'essential'.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Sure, perhaps I am as much a victim of capitalist dogma as the rest of us,
  and have just now become more acutely aware of it. But all these material
  goods weigh heavy on my soul - I can't help but wonder if I would feel
  a great sense of liberation on becoming free of it all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Naturally, I am far too scared to take the plunge and find out.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">In the process of moving this week, I became cutely aware of how many boxes of largely superfluous possessions I had to painstakingly lug up and down multiple flights of stairs. I then compounded this by buying even more unnecessary trash, despite being already cogniscent that I had too much of it in the first place - everything I purchased, I had persuaded myself was 'essential'. Sure, perhaps I am as much a victim of capitalist dogma as the rest of us, and have just now become more acutely aware of it. But all these material goods weigh heavy on my soul - I can't help but wonder if I would feel a great sense of liberation on becoming free of it all. Naturally, I am far too scared to take the plunge and find out.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Satisficing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/02/satisficing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Satisficing" /><published>2019-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/02/satisficing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/02/satisficing">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I learned a new word, courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://apenwarr.ca/log/20190201&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  apenwarr,&lt;/a&gt; and that word is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satisficing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  satisficing.&lt;/a&gt; I think it's my new favourite.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The basic idea is that satisficing (satisfying and sufficing) is when you
  make a choice based on something meeting some lower bound of acceptability,
  rather than prolonging the decision making process in order to find the most
  optimal choice. And I think this idea encapsulates everything I am terrified
  of in my life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am terrified of satisficing on (I have no idea what the right preposition to
  use is) a girlfriend or serious relationship. I am terrified of satisficing
  on a job or a career path. I am terrified of satisficing on a place to live,
  and not trying to leave Guernsey, and regretting it. I am terrified of
  satisficing on myself, and not pushing myself to improve further.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So, from now on: &lt;strong&gt;no satisficing.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Language" /><summary type="html">Today I learned a new word, courtesy of apenwarr, and that word is satisficing. I think it's my new favourite. The basic idea is that satisficing (satisfying and sufficing) is when you make a choice based on something meeting some lower bound of acceptability, rather than prolonging the decision making process in order to find the most optimal choice. And I think this idea encapsulates everything I am terrified of in my life. I am terrified of satisficing on (I have no idea what the right preposition to use is) a girlfriend or serious relationship. I am terrified of satisficing on a job or a career path. I am terrified of satisficing on a place to live, and not trying to leave Guernsey, and regretting it. I am terrified of satisficing on myself, and not pushing myself to improve further. So, from now on: no satisficing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Face</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/01/new-face" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Face" /><published>2019-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/01/new-face</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/01/new-face">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I shaved my face down to the skin for the first time in around
  4 years. My chin has not seen the light of day for the last 1500 of them -
  I wonder what its take on the shift in the global political climate is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I expected to hate it, but I actually kinda don't - although I certainly don't
  love it either. But, given that everything else is changing, this felt like time
  for a facial change as well - time for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/OwjPPaEyqhl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  new face.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I wonder if I'll start getting IDed in bars again now.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today I shaved my face down to the skin for the first time in around 4 years. My chin has not seen the light of day for the last 1500 of them - I wonder what its take on the shift in the global political climate is. I expected to hate it, but I actually kinda don't - although I certainly don't love it either. But, given that everything else is changing, this felt like time for a facial change as well - time for a new face. I wonder if I'll start getting IDed in bars again now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/31/new-site" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Site" /><published>2019-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/31/new-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/31/new-site">&lt;p&gt;
  This week I have started working on a new version of this site,
  one that will be quite different from this one. Inspired heavily
  by &lt;a href=&quot;https://devoncrawford.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  Devon Crawford's site,&lt;/a&gt; it will be a completely different approach
  to building a site - rather than providing the absolute minimum
  functionality for what I want to do with it (this iteration hosts blogs and
  nothing else), instead it will serve as a platform on which I could easily
  deploy any web apps I may develop in the future. It will be completel overkill
  for a personal site - but that's fine. In the process I'll get to learn about
  several new, interesting technologies such as Node, React and Docker, as well
  as how to have multiple servers interacting seemlessly with one another.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The plan at the moment is to produce something very similar to Devon's site -
  a front end server running React, a thin back end server using Node, and a
  database server with MySQL. Everything will be containerised with Docker and
  deployed using Kubernetes, meaning I should be able to add new features relatively
  painlessly. A security/auth server is a cool idea but not something that will be
  crucial until I have an app worth providing auth for, so this will be probably
  be the first 'add-on' once the new site is live, similarly with a CPU bound
  backend server, although mine definitely won't be written in dotnet.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Inspired by Shawn Wang's &lt;a href=&quot;https://swyx.io/writing/learn-in-public/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  &quot;Learn in Public&quot;,&lt;/a&gt; I will be attempting to do just that, as I embarrassingly
  stumble through new frameworks and libraries towards the finished product.
  Hopefully I will be able to show how achievable it is to build the kind of
  platform I envision even with little to no experience or knowledge of much of
  the technology involved.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Stay tuned ^^
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">This week I have started working on a new version of this site, one that will be quite different from this one. Inspired heavily by Devon Crawford's site, it will be a completely different approach to building a site - rather than providing the absolute minimum functionality for what I want to do with it (this iteration hosts blogs and nothing else), instead it will serve as a platform on which I could easily deploy any web apps I may develop in the future. It will be completel overkill for a personal site - but that's fine. In the process I'll get to learn about several new, interesting technologies such as Node, React and Docker, as well as how to have multiple servers interacting seemlessly with one another. The plan at the moment is to produce something very similar to Devon's site - a front end server running React, a thin back end server using Node, and a database server with MySQL. Everything will be containerised with Docker and deployed using Kubernetes, meaning I should be able to add new features relatively painlessly. A security/auth server is a cool idea but not something that will be crucial until I have an app worth providing auth for, so this will be probably be the first 'add-on' once the new site is live, similarly with a CPU bound backend server, although mine definitely won't be written in dotnet. Inspired by Shawn Wang's &quot;Learn in Public&quot;, I will be attempting to do just that, as I embarrassingly stumble through new frameworks and libraries towards the finished product. Hopefully I will be able to show how achievable it is to build the kind of platform I envision even with little to no experience or knowledge of much of the technology involved. Stay tuned ^^</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The End of the Beginning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/30/the-end-of-the-beginning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The End of the Beginning" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/30/the-end-of-the-beginning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/30/the-end-of-the-beginning">&lt;p&gt;
  Today, at my own request, I was discharged from therapy. It marks the end of a
  14 month long stretch of engaging with some kind of professional help for my
  mental health.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It has been an arduous and often painful journey, but in that way it reflects
  life when one is not lying on the therapist's couch (although I have never actually
  got to lie on one of those couches). I felt like I made little to no progress for
  the vast majority of that time, but in a way, that lack of progress ultimately
  spurred me to seek other solutions, and was thus ultimately helpful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  A lot of my sessions were horrible. Being confronted with the bleak reality
  (or lack thereof) of one's consciousness, as condensed and articulated by another,
  is immensely sobering. There is nowhere to hide in that scenario, and given
  most mentally ill people's propensity to avoid tackling their problems head on,
  the only viable alternative is to attempt to will oneself out of existence.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Therein lay my problem, or at least part of it. I hoped, wanted and to some
  extent expected therapy to be a silver bullet for me, but of course it was not.
  When you are sick, you go to the doctor and there is some level of expectation
  that whatever course of action the doctor prescribes will cure all ailments.
  With mental health and psychotherapy, this is not the case, and rather than
  admit this to myself, I instead became frustrated with therapy because it &quot;wasn't
  working&quot;, and engaged less and less, exacerbating the issue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have made a massive improvement to my mental health in the past two months,
  and I think these changes might actually stick. Through some amazing friends,
  whom I too often take for granted, I have learned the value of other people
  in my life, and was abundantly surprised to discover how much my personal
  relationships affect my day-to-day happiness. I have done at least some of the
  work myself though, so I will aportion a non-zero amount of credit to myself as
  well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am truly hopefully today was the last therapy session I will ever have, and
  that this is the end of the beginning. The future is bright.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Today, at my own request, I was discharged from therapy. It marks the end of a 14 month long stretch of engaging with some kind of professional help for my mental health. It has been an arduous and often painful journey, but in that way it reflects life when one is not lying on the therapist's couch (although I have never actually got to lie on one of those couches). I felt like I made little to no progress for the vast majority of that time, but in a way, that lack of progress ultimately spurred me to seek other solutions, and was thus ultimately helpful. A lot of my sessions were horrible. Being confronted with the bleak reality (or lack thereof) of one's consciousness, as condensed and articulated by another, is immensely sobering. There is nowhere to hide in that scenario, and given most mentally ill people's propensity to avoid tackling their problems head on, the only viable alternative is to attempt to will oneself out of existence. Therein lay my problem, or at least part of it. I hoped, wanted and to some extent expected therapy to be a silver bullet for me, but of course it was not. When you are sick, you go to the doctor and there is some level of expectation that whatever course of action the doctor prescribes will cure all ailments. With mental health and psychotherapy, this is not the case, and rather than admit this to myself, I instead became frustrated with therapy because it &quot;wasn't working&quot;, and engaged less and less, exacerbating the issue. I have made a massive improvement to my mental health in the past two months, and I think these changes might actually stick. Through some amazing friends, whom I too often take for granted, I have learned the value of other people in my life, and was abundantly surprised to discover how much my personal relationships affect my day-to-day happiness. I have done at least some of the work myself though, so I will aportion a non-zero amount of credit to myself as well. I am truly hopefully today was the last therapy session I will ever have, and that this is the end of the beginning. The future is bright.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moving Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/29/moving-day" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving Day" /><published>2019-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/29/moving-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/29/moving-day">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I am moving into a new flat, and it is the 4th time that I have moved
  out of my parents' with the intention of not returning. I hope it sticks this
  time, although I am not going to get my hopes up too much. I'm less excited
  than the previous times, now it feels like business as usual.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I also spent about 6 hours trying to get Ubuntu working on a secondary SSD
  yesterday to no avail. The install process runs successfully, but open
  attempting to restart and boot into Ubuntu, my machine hangs when the BIOS
  hands over to grub. Send help :-(
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today I am moving into a new flat, and it is the 4th time that I have moved out of my parents' with the intention of not returning. I hope it sticks this time, although I am not going to get my hopes up too much. I'm less excited than the previous times, now it feels like business as usual. I also spent about 6 hours trying to get Ubuntu working on a secondary SSD yesterday to no avail. The install process runs successfully, but open attempting to restart and boot into Ubuntu, my machine hangs when the BIOS hands over to grub. Send help :-(</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OS Installation Issues</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/28/os-installation-issues" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OS Installation Issues" /><published>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/28/os-installation-issues</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/28/os-installation-issues">&lt;p&gt;
  I'm moving out tomorrow, and in preparation for doing so, I'm attempting to overwrite
  my Kali install with an Ubuntu one on my desktop. It turns out this is not as
  simple as I had hoped, and is in fact quite frustrating - firstly, as I had
  filled the drive with junk data during my Kali install, there was no space
  for Ubuntu, so I had to boot back into Windows and wipe the drive. Now, I have a
  bootloader install failed error, for unknown reasons. I guess I am going to try
  and manually install a bootloader, wish me luck...
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">I'm moving out tomorrow, and in preparation for doing so, I'm attempting to overwrite my Kali install with an Ubuntu one on my desktop. It turns out this is not as simple as I had hoped, and is in fact quite frustrating - firstly, as I had filled the drive with junk data during my Kali install, there was no space for Ubuntu, so I had to boot back into Windows and wipe the drive. Now, I have a bootloader install failed error, for unknown reasons. I guess I am going to try and manually install a bootloader, wish me luck...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Game Jam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/27/game-jam" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Game Jam" /><published>2019-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/27/game-jam</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/27/game-jam">&lt;p&gt;
  This weekend I participated in the Guernsey edition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalgamejam.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  Global Game Jam,&lt;/a&gt; an event where participating teams have just 48 hours to
  create a game from scratch, based on a prompt given at the start of the event.
  This year's theme was 'what home means to you', which is... vague.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It was my first time doing the event, and our team consisted of a telecomms
  engineer, a dotnet devloper, two python developers and myself, a web developer.
  We decided to build our game in Unity, of which only one of us had any
  experience (and it wasn't me!) - in fact, only two people knew any C# at all (and
  again, I was not one of them). Our interpretation of 'what home meant to us'
  mainly revolved around frustrating and arduous driving experiences, and so
  the concept was that the player would drive around a map of Guernsey, attempting
  to reach her destination, while a series of obstacles such as randomly-generated
  road closures would stand in her way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We actually managed to get fairly close to that in the time given. We managed
  to produce a game where the player could navigate round Guernsey, contending
  with suitably janky mechanics, and try to find a specific place having
  been given a tongue-in-cheek flavour text cue. There was a compass for guidance,
  if you veered off the road the car would slow to a crawl, and there were some pretty
  nifty engine sounds (I did those!). It was pretty fun, and I'm proud of what
  we achieved given how little collective experience we had.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I learned a huge amount from this experience. Aside from technical things, like
  learning a little C#, Unity and sound editing, I learned a lot about working
  in a team. We suffered a lot from not having someone in charge - nobody wanted
  to step on anybody else's toes, but that meant nobody stepped up with a grand
  vision for the project. Most importantly, nobody coordinated how we could all
  work individually and then pool our work into one finished product, meaning
  that the resultant game was contributed to significantly more by some team
  members than others. Effective communication was very important in this intense
  environment, and I think I improved as the weekend went by, so I am hopeful
  this will translate into better efficacy in my day to day job.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In retrospect I wish I had been able to contribute more to our game, either
  in the form of code or stepping up to fill the project manager type of role,
  but either way it was a huge amount of fun, I both laughed and learned a lot.
  I'll definitely be doing it next year, but hopefully I will have some Unity
  experience before then!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Programming" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Gaming" /><summary type="html">This weekend I participated in the Guernsey edition of Global Game Jam, an event where participating teams have just 48 hours to create a game from scratch, based on a prompt given at the start of the event. This year's theme was 'what home means to you', which is... vague. It was my first time doing the event, and our team consisted of a telecomms engineer, a dotnet devloper, two python developers and myself, a web developer. We decided to build our game in Unity, of which only one of us had any experience (and it wasn't me!) - in fact, only two people knew any C# at all (and again, I was not one of them). Our interpretation of 'what home meant to us' mainly revolved around frustrating and arduous driving experiences, and so the concept was that the player would drive around a map of Guernsey, attempting to reach her destination, while a series of obstacles such as randomly-generated road closures would stand in her way. We actually managed to get fairly close to that in the time given. We managed to produce a game where the player could navigate round Guernsey, contending with suitably janky mechanics, and try to find a specific place having been given a tongue-in-cheek flavour text cue. There was a compass for guidance, if you veered off the road the car would slow to a crawl, and there were some pretty nifty engine sounds (I did those!). It was pretty fun, and I'm proud of what we achieved given how little collective experience we had. I learned a huge amount from this experience. Aside from technical things, like learning a little C#, Unity and sound editing, I learned a lot about working in a team. We suffered a lot from not having someone in charge - nobody wanted to step on anybody else's toes, but that meant nobody stepped up with a grand vision for the project. Most importantly, nobody coordinated how we could all work individually and then pool our work into one finished product, meaning that the resultant game was contributed to significantly more by some team members than others. Effective communication was very important in this intense environment, and I think I improved as the weekend went by, so I am hopeful this will translate into better efficacy in my day to day job. In retrospect I wish I had been able to contribute more to our game, either in the form of code or stepping up to fill the project manager type of role, but either way it was a huge amount of fun, I both laughed and learned a lot. I'll definitely be doing it next year, but hopefully I will have some Unity experience before then!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No More Zero Days</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/26/no-more-zero-days" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No More Zero Days" /><published>2019-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/26/no-more-zero-days</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/26/no-more-zero-days">&lt;p&gt;
  Continuing this week's theme of shitty life advice, today's is something I
  saw on Reddit a while back, which says it all really. Given you've read the
  title, you know what it is - no more zero days.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Given my propensity for both feeling overwhelmed and setting myself lofty (or
  unrealistic) goals, the mantra serves me well. In the past it has benefitted my
  mental health - rather than beating myself up for failure to readh the insurmountable
  heights of 'being happy', I would try and do something only slightly better than
  the previous day - some days this might've only been take a shower, clean my
  teeth, or get out of bed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  While I am temporarily on top of that, it seems like a good chance to apply it
  to two other areas of my life - health and career development/programming.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Becoming a better programmer is an intimidating task - the amount to learn is
  near infinite, and far more than one could comprehend in a lifetime, so it is
  easy to give up before I've even started. I also want to learn pretty much
  everything, from low level computer science concepts like algorithms and assembly
  languages, to containerisation, modern JavaScript libraries, machine learning in
  Python, DevOps, CI and (proper) unit testing, scalable infrastructure... and
  probably a hundred other things that could be an entire career all on their own.
  I feel overwhelmed just writing that - but I know that if I have no more zero
  days, even if all I do is refactor one line of code or watch a 5 minute Docker
  tutorial, eventually I will make meaningful progress, and possibly sooner than
  I think.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My health goal is obviously to be a super jacked marathon running powerlifter/bodybuilder
  with a bodyfat of 8% who can bench press a car. But that's a long way off,
  because right now I'm still rocking the 'chubby nerd' chic. If I take the NMZD
  approach - eat an apple, go for a 2 minute jog down the street, drive to the
  gym and then turn right back round and go home - once again, I'll make progress
  towards my goals without them seeming so terrifyingly distant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Wish me luck.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Continuing this week's theme of shitty life advice, today's is something I saw on Reddit a while back, which says it all really. Given you've read the title, you know what it is - no more zero days. Given my propensity for both feeling overwhelmed and setting myself lofty (or unrealistic) goals, the mantra serves me well. In the past it has benefitted my mental health - rather than beating myself up for failure to readh the insurmountable heights of 'being happy', I would try and do something only slightly better than the previous day - some days this might've only been take a shower, clean my teeth, or get out of bed. While I am temporarily on top of that, it seems like a good chance to apply it to two other areas of my life - health and career development/programming. Becoming a better programmer is an intimidating task - the amount to learn is near infinite, and far more than one could comprehend in a lifetime, so it is easy to give up before I've even started. I also want to learn pretty much everything, from low level computer science concepts like algorithms and assembly languages, to containerisation, modern JavaScript libraries, machine learning in Python, DevOps, CI and (proper) unit testing, scalable infrastructure... and probably a hundred other things that could be an entire career all on their own. I feel overwhelmed just writing that - but I know that if I have no more zero days, even if all I do is refactor one line of code or watch a 5 minute Docker tutorial, eventually I will make meaningful progress, and possibly sooner than I think. My health goal is obviously to be a super jacked marathon running powerlifter/bodybuilder with a bodyfat of 8% who can bench press a car. But that's a long way off, because right now I'm still rocking the 'chubby nerd' chic. If I take the NMZD approach - eat an apple, go for a 2 minute jog down the street, drive to the gym and then turn right back round and go home - once again, I'll make progress towards my goals without them seeming so terrifyingly distant. Wish me luck.</summary></entry></feed>