<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-19T18:53:57+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Grass is Greener</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/19/the-grass-is-greener" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Grass is Greener" /><published>2019-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/19/the-grass-is-greener</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/19/the-grass-is-greener">&lt;p&gt;
  The phrase 'the grass is always greener [on the other side]' fills me with
  an incandescent rage when I am its intended recipient (and indeed a rather more
  tepid peturbation in any other context). Not only should it hold no place in
  mature and productive discourse, it is degrading, damaging, and should be
  removed from our collective lexicon forthwith.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  'The grass is greener' is the equivalent of a parent telling a petulant
  child 'because I said so', and has roughly equal merit as a logical counterpoint.
  It is wholly synonymous with the following: 'You are ignorant and naive. I am more
  intelligent than you; you are too stupid to see your own folly. Continuing this
  discussion isn't worth my time, because you are so dumb.' - and then abruptly
  turning away. Quite frankly, whenever someone uses the offending phrase in
  question and directs it towards me, I have to summon previously untapped reserves of inner
  fortitude in order to prevent myself retaliating with the refreshing honest
  rebuttal of 'go fuck yourself'.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The expression implies that the grass is in fact, not actually greener on
  the other side, and that humans are conditioned to be unhappy with their
  own circumstances, forever trapped in the cycle of being desirous of
  other people's lives. The phrase esentially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NwVNuyfhF0Q&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  paraphrases Homer Simpson,&lt;/a&gt; saying 'why bother trying - even if you succeed, you will
  not find happiness'. In my mind, the joke is
  invariably on the speaker invoking the moronic platitude - clearly they
  are content with the waist deep mediocrity they are mired in, and do
  not think highly enough of themselves that they might be able to haul themselves
  free of it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The phrase is dangerous. While in a toxic relationship, it is easy to follow
  the greener grass fallacy - and think things would not be any better for you
  if you were rid of the very thing causing you pain. The same could be said of a
  job - your workload is overwhelming, your boss is callous and unempathetic, your
  clients excessively demanding and relentlessly unreasonable. You think to
  yourself that you should leave to find pastures fresh, where you might be
  happier. But then you remember that the grass is always greener on the other side,
  and that you are being a downright fool, and so you stay despite your present
  woeful predicament - which is ironically the infinitely more foolish thing
  than having the hope that you could bring about positive change.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I refuse to bow down to the arrogant suggestion imposed by the phrase, that
  I should &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/02/02/satisficing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;satisfice&lt;/a&gt;
  with my current situation. I welcome the implication that I am naive and
  idealistic, if it means I can retain the hope for a better future.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Please, stop subjecting me to this ludicrous slogan.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">The phrase 'the grass is always greener [on the other side]' fills me with an incandescent rage when I am its intended recipient (and indeed a rather more tepid peturbation in any other context). Not only should it hold no place in mature and productive discourse, it is degrading, damaging, and should be removed from our collective lexicon forthwith. 'The grass is greener' is the equivalent of a parent telling a petulant child 'because I said so', and has roughly equal merit as a logical counterpoint. It is wholly synonymous with the following: 'You are ignorant and naive. I am more intelligent than you; you are too stupid to see your own folly. Continuing this discussion isn't worth my time, because you are so dumb.' - and then abruptly turning away. Quite frankly, whenever someone uses the offending phrase in question and directs it towards me, I have to summon previously untapped reserves of inner fortitude in order to prevent myself retaliating with the refreshing honest rebuttal of 'go fuck yourself'. The expression implies that the grass is in fact, not actually greener on the other side, and that humans are conditioned to be unhappy with their own circumstances, forever trapped in the cycle of being desirous of other people's lives. The phrase esentially paraphrases Homer Simpson, saying 'why bother trying - even if you succeed, you will not find happiness'. In my mind, the joke is invariably on the speaker invoking the moronic platitude - clearly they are content with the waist deep mediocrity they are mired in, and do not think highly enough of themselves that they might be able to haul themselves free of it. The phrase is dangerous. While in a toxic relationship, it is easy to follow the greener grass fallacy - and think things would not be any better for you if you were rid of the very thing causing you pain. The same could be said of a job - your workload is overwhelming, your boss is callous and unempathetic, your clients excessively demanding and relentlessly unreasonable. You think to yourself that you should leave to find pastures fresh, where you might be happier. But then you remember that the grass is always greener on the other side, and that you are being a downright fool, and so you stay despite your present woeful predicament - which is ironically the infinitely more foolish thing than having the hope that you could bring about positive change. I refuse to bow down to the arrogant suggestion imposed by the phrase, that I should satisfice with my current situation. I welcome the implication that I am naive and idealistic, if it means I can retain the hope for a better future. Please, stop subjecting me to this ludicrous slogan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good Mood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/18/good-mood" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good Mood" /><published>2019-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/18/good-mood</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/18/good-mood">&lt;p&gt;
  Today, this afternoon in particular, I have been in a pretty good mood - this
  is of grave concern. Usually when I am in a good mood, there has been a correspondingly
  positive recent event that has played a role in my chirpy demeanour, but today
  that is not the case. Nothing whatsoever out of the ordinary has happened in
  the past week, and so this change in my tune has me worried. I am deeply
  suspicious of it. Is this the eye of the storm? Are things about to get much,
  much worse? Is my subconscious lulling me into a false sense of security before
  reducing every waking moment into a nihilistic oblivion later in the week?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Or maybe things are actually getting better. But I doubt it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Today, this afternoon in particular, I have been in a pretty good mood - this is of grave concern. Usually when I am in a good mood, there has been a correspondingly positive recent event that has played a role in my chirpy demeanour, but today that is not the case. Nothing whatsoever out of the ordinary has happened in the past week, and so this change in my tune has me worried. I am deeply suspicious of it. Is this the eye of the storm? Are things about to get much, much worse? Is my subconscious lulling me into a false sense of security before reducing every waking moment into a nihilistic oblivion later in the week? Or maybe things are actually getting better. But I doubt it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bonsai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/17/bonsai" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bonsai" /><published>2019-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/17/bonsai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/17/bonsai">&lt;p&gt;
  Last week I bought a bonsai tree, naïvely assuming they would be as easy to
  care for as cacti. This week I learned that this is in fact not the case, and
  they are quite demanding as far as plants go. Most bonsai aren't even meant to
  be kept in doors - fortunately I accidentally bought one that is. I have to
  mist it, and try to keep it as humid as possible by leaving it near an open
  window and keeping its saucer full of water. It needs regular attention and
  I must care for its needs - what started as an ornament is rapidly becoming
  more like a pet.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  At first I was frustrated at my own idiocy and sought to take it out on the plant
  - to wreak vengeance by leaving it in the dry and the dark. But now I think I
  can grow to like it - as we sit side by side on the windowsill, and I gently
  spray its petite leaves with filtered water, our bond will strengthen and we
  might yet fall in love with one another.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Gardening" /><summary type="html">Last week I bought a bonsai tree, naïvely assuming they would be as easy to care for as cacti. This week I learned that this is in fact not the case, and they are quite demanding as far as plants go. Most bonsai aren't even meant to be kept in doors - fortunately I accidentally bought one that is. I have to mist it, and try to keep it as humid as possible by leaving it near an open window and keeping its saucer full of water. It needs regular attention and I must care for its needs - what started as an ornament is rapidly becoming more like a pet. At first I was frustrated at my own idiocy and sought to take it out on the plant - to wreak vengeance by leaving it in the dry and the dark. But now I think I can grow to like it - as we sit side by side on the windowsill, and I gently spray its petite leaves with filtered water, our bond will strengthen and we might yet fall in love with one another.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What We Want</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/16/what-we-want" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What We Want" /><published>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/16/what-we-want</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/16/what-we-want">&lt;p&gt;
  I started watching Mad Men this weekend, and I've already made a pretty significant
  dent in the first season. Don Draper is a legendary character, and now I can
  see why. I am struck by how I think a great many men might aspire to be like
  him, despite the fact that he is a complete asshole. I refuse to be taken
  in by his charm and charisma, he is clearly devoid of any semblance of moral
  fibre.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With that being said, clearly there is something admirable about him, and I
  think part of that is that he knows what he wants and he sets out to get it.
  I think a lot of people could learn from that - we spent ages agonising over
  what it is that we want, and then even more time lamenting the impossibility
  of acquiring it. The idea that want Don Draper wants is unobtainable has yet
  to occur to him. In that sense, I think it is a quality worth emulating -
  really, I do know what I want out of every facet of my life. I am simply too
  scared or ashamed to pursue or admit to it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So, perhaps I can channel my inner Madison Avenue executive, and set out to
  put myself first and get what I want. The good news is that I'm not in a position
  to be as recklessly unfaithful to my wife as my boy Don is.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I started watching Mad Men this weekend, and I've already made a pretty significant dent in the first season. Don Draper is a legendary character, and now I can see why. I am struck by how I think a great many men might aspire to be like him, despite the fact that he is a complete asshole. I refuse to be taken in by his charm and charisma, he is clearly devoid of any semblance of moral fibre. With that being said, clearly there is something admirable about him, and I think part of that is that he knows what he wants and he sets out to get it. I think a lot of people could learn from that - we spent ages agonising over what it is that we want, and then even more time lamenting the impossibility of acquiring it. The idea that want Don Draper wants is unobtainable has yet to occur to him. In that sense, I think it is a quality worth emulating - really, I do know what I want out of every facet of my life. I am simply too scared or ashamed to pursue or admit to it. So, perhaps I can channel my inner Madison Avenue executive, and set out to put myself first and get what I want. The good news is that I'm not in a position to be as recklessly unfaithful to my wife as my boy Don is.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hope</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/15/hope" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hope" /><published>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/15/hope</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/15/hope">&lt;p&gt;
  Once again far, far too exhausted to write anything lengthy or thought out tonight.
  So, just an observation of the day - hope is severely underrated. I would say
  it is practically vital in order to have a fulfilling human experience. We are,
  by nature, never satisfied with the present, and if we don't have hope for a
  better future, the situations starts to become bleak very fast.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Sure, I should just focus on getting better at appreciating what I already have,
  and being satisfied with the way things are. But that would go against years
  of conditioning myself to think otherwise - so I am going to settle for
  trying to incubate as much hope for positive future change as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Once again far, far too exhausted to write anything lengthy or thought out tonight. So, just an observation of the day - hope is severely underrated. I would say it is practically vital in order to have a fulfilling human experience. We are, by nature, never satisfied with the present, and if we don't have hope for a better future, the situations starts to become bleak very fast. Sure, I should just focus on getting better at appreciating what I already have, and being satisfied with the way things are. But that would go against years of conditioning myself to think otherwise - so I am going to settle for trying to incubate as much hope for positive future change as possible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Valentine's Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/14/valentines-day" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Valentine&amp;#39;s Day" /><published>2019-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/14/valentines-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/14/valentines-day">&lt;p&gt;
  Today is Valentine's Day and traditionally that means I make some kind of
  miserly comments on the internet. This year however I plan on toning it down,
  at the very least. I would say I would put on a face of positivity and maturity,
  but I have already sent some of my friends a picture of ice cream and the Pornhub
  homepage on my PC, so... it's too late for that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But while I am going to spend the evening eating enough to make myself sick
  and then masturbating until comatose, this year I am actually feeling better
  about things than I usually might. Sure, I am very, very single, but I feel
  better about myself and about my romantic prospects than I have in years. I
  don't feel (as) bitter towards those around me celebrating their shared happiness -
  it's almost cute. I'm not as insecure, and the fear of loneliness is abating.
  Perhaps next year I will have someone to celebrate my love for on this day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Or perhaps I'm just kidding myself.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">Today is Valentine's Day and traditionally that means I make some kind of miserly comments on the internet. This year however I plan on toning it down, at the very least. I would say I would put on a face of positivity and maturity, but I have already sent some of my friends a picture of ice cream and the Pornhub homepage on my PC, so... it's too late for that. But while I am going to spend the evening eating enough to make myself sick and then masturbating until comatose, this year I am actually feeling better about things than I usually might. Sure, I am very, very single, but I feel better about myself and about my romantic prospects than I have in years. I don't feel (as) bitter towards those around me celebrating their shared happiness - it's almost cute. I'm not as insecure, and the fear of loneliness is abating. Perhaps next year I will have someone to celebrate my love for on this day. Or perhaps I'm just kidding myself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">God's Children</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/13/gods-children" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="God&amp;#39;s Children" /><published>2019-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/13/gods-children</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/13/gods-children">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I met Elder Chung and Elder Howard, two members of the Church of Jesus
  Christ of Latter-Day Saints. They approached me in the street and usually I
  would've ignored them, but I didn't immediately realise that their true
  intention, instead thinking they would just ask me an innocent question and
  be on their way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We ended up talking for 10 minutes or so. They were nice people, and clearly
  not unintelligent, although I didn't exactly feel intimidated by their intellectual
  prowess either. We talked a little about life, the problems we all face, a
  search for answers, a desire for happiness that is common to each and every
  human being on the planet. They had a sense of altruism - they found joy
  in what they were doing and wanted to share that with other people, that
  they might find similar joy. In a lot of ways, I was completely on board.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Until they told me they believed in a very literal (and specific) God - the
  specificty really bothers me. If you take 'does a Christian God exist?' as a
  Bayesian hypothesis, the starting probability is so staggeringly, infinitesimally
  small that I can't even theorize what kind of evidence would lead me to consider
  the hypothesis as having a meanginful probability of truth. Which is kind of
  a shame, because if they are truly happy, and I am not, then really the joke
  is on me, regardless of what I think about how they derive said happiness.
  Naturally I cannot overcome my existing thoughts and feelings about the nature
  of reality in order to share their viewpoint, so I do not think I will be
  joining the Church of Latter-Day Saints, but it did make me think if there is
  more to the whole spirituality thing than I've ever really given it credit it
  for. My God will not have created the Earth in 7 days, or sent their offspring
  to Earth (ironically, surely the realm of us mere mortals must be hell for a
  celestial being?), but that doesn't necessarily mean she doesn't exist, in one
  form or another.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  They also gave me a free book, which I thought was a pretty neat marketing trick.
  Startups, take note.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Spirituality" /><summary type="html">Today I met Elder Chung and Elder Howard, two members of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints. They approached me in the street and usually I would've ignored them, but I didn't immediately realise that their true intention, instead thinking they would just ask me an innocent question and be on their way. We ended up talking for 10 minutes or so. They were nice people, and clearly not unintelligent, although I didn't exactly feel intimidated by their intellectual prowess either. We talked a little about life, the problems we all face, a search for answers, a desire for happiness that is common to each and every human being on the planet. They had a sense of altruism - they found joy in what they were doing and wanted to share that with other people, that they might find similar joy. In a lot of ways, I was completely on board. Until they told me they believed in a very literal (and specific) God - the specificty really bothers me. If you take 'does a Christian God exist?' as a Bayesian hypothesis, the starting probability is so staggeringly, infinitesimally small that I can't even theorize what kind of evidence would lead me to consider the hypothesis as having a meanginful probability of truth. Which is kind of a shame, because if they are truly happy, and I am not, then really the joke is on me, regardless of what I think about how they derive said happiness. Naturally I cannot overcome my existing thoughts and feelings about the nature of reality in order to share their viewpoint, so I do not think I will be joining the Church of Latter-Day Saints, but it did make me think if there is more to the whole spirituality thing than I've ever really given it credit it for. My God will not have created the Earth in 7 days, or sent their offspring to Earth (ironically, surely the realm of us mere mortals must be hell for a celestial being?), but that doesn't necessarily mean she doesn't exist, in one form or another. They also gave me a free book, which I thought was a pretty neat marketing trick. Startups, take note.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GSL 2019 II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/12/gsl-2019-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GSL 2019 II" /><published>2019-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/12/gsl-2019-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/12/gsl-2019-ii">&lt;p&gt;
  Have I really only written about the GSL twice?!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm exhausted, today I worked 11 hours and then had a 3 hour chess game afterwards.
  But I refuse to let my fatigure get me down, because it's Scarlett's GSL group
  tomorrow, and I'm significantly more excited about this than I was about
  Christmas.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Gogo Scarlett fighting!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="esports" /><summary type="html">Have I really only written about the GSL twice?! I'm exhausted, today I worked 11 hours and then had a 3 hour chess game afterwards. But I refuse to let my fatigure get me down, because it's Scarlett's GSL group tomorrow, and I'm significantly more excited about this than I was about Christmas. Gogo Scarlett fighting!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Nature of Problem Solving</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/11/on-the-nature-of-problem-solving" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Nature of Problem Solving" /><published>2019-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/11/on-the-nature-of-problem-solving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/11/on-the-nature-of-problem-solving">&lt;p&gt;
  In my experience, development is roughly 20% planning your code, 5% writing
  your code, and 75% figuring out why the fuck your code doesn't work. Programmers
  are not &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/hp.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  painters,&lt;/a&gt; nor are they &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infinite_monkey_theorem&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  an infinite number of monkeys&lt;/a&gt; - they are problem solvers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I would arrogantly consider myself an above-average problem solver. In fact it
  is one of the few disciplines in which I think I am in the upper quartile of
  the general population.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In general, when presented with a problem, assuming the subject is not far
  outside my usual outstanding, I have a handlful of immediate ideas about
  how to go about solving it. The interesting part of solving a problem is when
  those ideas have been exhausted - how does one generate more potential solutions?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The most obvious answer is to seek outside help, for example from a search
  engine or Stack Overflow. Sometimes doing so is unsatisfying, and sometimes
  even these seemingly omnipotent tools do not contain the knowledge we seek.
  The next step usually involves trying to state the problem as concisely as possible;
  take note of every single relevant piece of information individually, and attack
  it from first principles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The most enjoyable, and hilarious part of attempting to solve a problem with
  one's code is the final step - the desperation play. At this point we are
  essentially trying to anti-fuzz the problem; we constantly feed it garbage
  inputs until something magically works. Comment out every modular piece of code.
  Add variables. Change variables. Delete variables. Run the code in a different
  environment. Run the code on the other environment a second time - make no other
  changes. Recompile the code. Restart your dev machine. Reinstall your OS.
  Try a different distro, upgrade your hardware, get a new job, relocate across
  the world - I don't know, something will work eventually.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Embarrassingly, I solve a lot of problems using the desperation play.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">In my experience, development is roughly 20% planning your code, 5% writing your code, and 75% figuring out why the fuck your code doesn't work. Programmers are not painters, nor are they an infinite number of monkeys - they are problem solvers. I would arrogantly consider myself an above-average problem solver. In fact it is one of the few disciplines in which I think I am in the upper quartile of the general population. In general, when presented with a problem, assuming the subject is not far outside my usual outstanding, I have a handlful of immediate ideas about how to go about solving it. The interesting part of solving a problem is when those ideas have been exhausted - how does one generate more potential solutions? The most obvious answer is to seek outside help, for example from a search engine or Stack Overflow. Sometimes doing so is unsatisfying, and sometimes even these seemingly omnipotent tools do not contain the knowledge we seek. The next step usually involves trying to state the problem as concisely as possible; take note of every single relevant piece of information individually, and attack it from first principles. The most enjoyable, and hilarious part of attempting to solve a problem with one's code is the final step - the desperation play. At this point we are essentially trying to anti-fuzz the problem; we constantly feed it garbage inputs until something magically works. Comment out every modular piece of code. Add variables. Change variables. Delete variables. Run the code in a different environment. Run the code on the other environment a second time - make no other changes. Recompile the code. Restart your dev machine. Reinstall your OS. Try a different distro, upgrade your hardware, get a new job, relocate across the world - I don't know, something will work eventually. Embarrassingly, I solve a lot of problems using the desperation play.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Ubuntu Installation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/10/new-ubuntu-installation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Ubuntu Installation" /><published>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/10/new-ubuntu-installation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/02/10/new-ubuntu-installation">&lt;p&gt;
  In exciting news, this weekend I managed to fix my previously documented
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/28/os-installation-issues&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  dual boot OS installation issues.&lt;/a&gt; Frustratingly, all I had to do was run
  the Ubuntu installer again with all my drives connected (which I'd already done
  once - or at least thought I had), and this time there were no bootloader issues.
  I guess the classic developer tactic of try-the-exact-same-thing-again-
  and-hope-for-a-different-result actually worked this time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Because I'm too tired to write anything interesting, here's a list of the
  first things I installed:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Guake&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Atom&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Apache&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;MySQL&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;PHP7&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pip - apparently this didn't come with the Python3 installation on Ubuntu?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jupyter&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pandas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jekyll&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NPM&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Compiz&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;create-react-app&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Spotify&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">In exciting news, this weekend I managed to fix my previously documented dual boot OS installation issues. Frustratingly, all I had to do was run the Ubuntu installer again with all my drives connected (which I'd already done once - or at least thought I had), and this time there were no bootloader issues. I guess the classic developer tactic of try-the-exact-same-thing-again- and-hope-for-a-different-result actually worked this time. Because I'm too tired to write anything interesting, here's a list of the first things I installed: Guake Atom Apache MySQL PHP7 Pip - apparently this didn't come with the Python3 installation on Ubuntu? Jupyter Pandas Matplotlib Ruby Jekyll NPM Compiz create-react-app Docker Spotify</summary></entry></feed>