<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-08T17:56:20+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Repeated Mistakes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Repeated Mistakes" /><published>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes">&lt;p&gt;
  Yesterday was my first session back in the gym after two weeks off, due to
  the holiday season and being ill. The building is a converted warehouse, so there's no
  heating and it's very cold in the winter, so even if you warm up, taking long rests
  in between sets can cause your temperature to drop quite quickly. Between
  that, still not being over my illness, and diving straight back into my
  programme after a fortnight's break, I should have been cogniscent of having
  a much higher injury risk than normal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are no prizes for guessing what I did next. After 3 of 5 of my sets of
  squats, I felt my right hamstring become incredibly tight, and considered
  whether or not to continue. I knew it was the sensible thing to stop and doing
  something else, but for whatever reason I didn't, and proceeded to do my
  last two sets while trying to load my right leg as little as possible - hardly ideal for squatting. I
  massively compensated using my back and today it's inflamed and very painful;
  walking is difficult and I had to skip the gym. I saw this coming,
  so why did still I make the decision I did?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Obviously it was calulcated risk - injury wasn't a certainty. But I have
  been injured in this exact scenario before, so it was highly probable. My
  decision making process broke down, and there are several reasons for that:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      ego - not finishing would be 'weak' mentally, and in this case physically;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      desire for improvement - I am not content with where I am presently in my
      training, and I know I need to do the sets to get to where I want to be. I
      can't afford to make excuses, or I will not progess;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      guilt - I'd just taken two weeks off, I need to make up for lost time;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      expectation - I'd already set my expectations to do the whole session that
      evening, I did not want to fall short;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      laziness (of a kind) - making a conscious effort to change your plan takes
      effort, and a lot of times it is easier to simply stick with the way things
      are and deal with any potential consequences later.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Of course, this is a relatively minor example of a bad decision. But, life is a
  series of decisions, and this one was something of a trap - furthermore, a trap
  I think we all fall victim to. Humans repeat they own poor decisions with such
  frequency that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/surprised-pikachu&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  meme flavour of the month is very much dedicated to it (and a personal favourite
  of mine too).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If I can improve the mushy grey inference engine between my ears then perhaps
  I will become a better, happier person. Another very human trait is to shirk
  our responsibility to confront our mistakes (especially if this isn't the first time we've made them),
  and simply tell ourselves we will do better next time. Perhaps this sounds familiar
  to you. But I think autopsying those decisions can provide a huge amount of value
  and direction on how to overcome wider issues in your life. I guess I just gotta
  get my hands dirty more often.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Health and Fitness" /><summary type="html">Yesterday was my first session back in the gym after two weeks off, due to the holiday season and being ill. The building is a converted warehouse, so there's no heating and it's very cold in the winter, so even if you warm up, taking long rests in between sets can cause your temperature to drop quite quickly. Between that, still not being over my illness, and diving straight back into my programme after a fortnight's break, I should have been cogniscent of having a much higher injury risk than normal. There are no prizes for guessing what I did next. After 3 of 5 of my sets of squats, I felt my right hamstring become incredibly tight, and considered whether or not to continue. I knew it was the sensible thing to stop and doing something else, but for whatever reason I didn't, and proceeded to do my last two sets while trying to load my right leg as little as possible - hardly ideal for squatting. I massively compensated using my back and today it's inflamed and very painful; walking is difficult and I had to skip the gym. I saw this coming, so why did still I make the decision I did? Obviously it was calulcated risk - injury wasn't a certainty. But I have been injured in this exact scenario before, so it was highly probable. My decision making process broke down, and there are several reasons for that: ego - not finishing would be 'weak' mentally, and in this case physically; desire for improvement - I am not content with where I am presently in my training, and I know I need to do the sets to get to where I want to be. I can't afford to make excuses, or I will not progess; guilt - I'd just taken two weeks off, I need to make up for lost time; expectation - I'd already set my expectations to do the whole session that evening, I did not want to fall short; laziness (of a kind) - making a conscious effort to change your plan takes effort, and a lot of times it is easier to simply stick with the way things are and deal with any potential consequences later. Of course, this is a relatively minor example of a bad decision. But, life is a series of decisions, and this one was something of a trap - furthermore, a trap I think we all fall victim to. Humans repeat they own poor decisions with such frequency that the meme flavour of the month is very much dedicated to it (and a personal favourite of mine too). If I can improve the mushy grey inference engine between my ears then perhaps I will become a better, happier person. Another very human trait is to shirk our responsibility to confront our mistakes (especially if this isn't the first time we've made them), and simply tell ourselves we will do better next time. Perhaps this sounds familiar to you. But I think autopsying those decisions can provide a huge amount of value and direction on how to overcome wider issues in your life. I guess I just gotta get my hands dirty more often.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Movie Reviews IV</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/07/movie-reviews-iv" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Movie Reviews IV" /><published>2019-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/07/movie-reviews-iv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/07/movie-reviews-iv">&lt;p&gt;
  Movie reviews are back! I watched a few films over the holiday period, so here
  they are.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;An Evening With Beverly Luff Linn&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I wanted to watch this film purely because of the people in it, namely Aubury
  Plaza, Jermaine Clement, Craig Robertson and Matt Berry. I'd honestly watch
  anything with Aubury in it, and so I tried to learn as little about the plot
  as possible beforehand, I didn't even watch the trailer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This film is &lt;i&gt;weird.&lt;/i&gt; I'm not sure how else to describe it, other than
  bizarre, at times hilarious, at others human and emotional. It was everything
  I wanted out of it and I loved every second, but... I can't recommend it to
  you. Unless you have the same penchant for oddity I do, you will not enjoy
  this film I'm afraid.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Fargo&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  After having watch this film, I have dedicated 10 minutes in front of my mirror
  every day to perfecting my Minnesotan accent. It still sucks, but it's totally
  worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Obviously this didn't come out in 2018, so it's more of a classic, but I
  also enjoyed it a lot. Another strange movie, but this time one I absolutely
  would recommend - thrilling and hilarious it heartily delivers on an evening
  of dark fun while giving you something to think about too. I hope you don't
  enjoy resolution, because you will still have plenty of questions left by the
  end, especially about if the movie is as true as it claims to be, but it is
  well worth watching either way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Eighth Grade&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Given that this film was made by one of my heroes, and got onto &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/barackobama/posts/10156393283416749&quot;
  rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Barack Obama's top films of 2018&lt;/a&gt;, I had
  very high hopes for Eighth Grade, and was relieved that it still smashed them out
  of a park. It scares the hell out of me how much I related to the 13 year old
  female protagonist at points in this film, but I defy any millenial to say they
  don't. This is the first time I have seen issues I have felt affected me personally
  displayed on the big screen, as Bo Burnham beautifully shows the pains of puberty
  in the social media age. 10/10, absolutely recommended.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Movies" /><summary type="html">Movie reviews are back! I watched a few films over the holiday period, so here they are. An Evening With Beverly Luff Linn I wanted to watch this film purely because of the people in it, namely Aubury Plaza, Jermaine Clement, Craig Robertson and Matt Berry. I'd honestly watch anything with Aubury in it, and so I tried to learn as little about the plot as possible beforehand, I didn't even watch the trailer. This film is weird. I'm not sure how else to describe it, other than bizarre, at times hilarious, at others human and emotional. It was everything I wanted out of it and I loved every second, but... I can't recommend it to you. Unless you have the same penchant for oddity I do, you will not enjoy this film I'm afraid. Fargo After having watch this film, I have dedicated 10 minutes in front of my mirror every day to perfecting my Minnesotan accent. It still sucks, but it's totally worth it. Obviously this didn't come out in 2018, so it's more of a classic, but I also enjoyed it a lot. Another strange movie, but this time one I absolutely would recommend - thrilling and hilarious it heartily delivers on an evening of dark fun while giving you something to think about too. I hope you don't enjoy resolution, because you will still have plenty of questions left by the end, especially about if the movie is as true as it claims to be, but it is well worth watching either way. Eighth Grade Given that this film was made by one of my heroes, and got onto Barack Obama's top films of 2018, I had very high hopes for Eighth Grade, and was relieved that it still smashed them out of a park. It scares the hell out of me how much I related to the 13 year old female protagonist at points in this film, but I defy any millenial to say they don't. This is the first time I have seen issues I have felt affected me personally displayed on the big screen, as Bo Burnham beautifully shows the pains of puberty in the social media age. 10/10, absolutely recommended.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Planning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/06/trip-planning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Planning" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/06/trip-planning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/06/trip-planning">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I spent &lt;i&gt;far&lt;/i&gt; too much money on plane tickets, but I am very excited -
  this is my first big, Adult Holiday. I am leaving work behind for two weeks and
  heading across the sea to the Big Apple, to go visit my best friend, along with
  another friend who I am excited to travel with and get to know better. I can't
  wait to get super fat on bagels, cheesecake and pizza, and learn to perfectly
  mimic a Lawn Guy Land accent. I'm gonna take a trip the Statue of Liberty,
  go see the Nets and then maybe bump into &lt;strike&gt;the President&lt;/strike&gt; Pete
  Davidson. It's gonna be sick.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's going to cost a lot, and there's a lot of potential for me to get super
  anxious. But you know what, I don't care. This could be one of the best
  trips of my life, and I'm not going to let shallow pockets or a restless
  mind stop me from enjoying it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's important for me to have things to look forward to when my health is bad.
  They're milestones, a place on the horizon that I can focus on slowly progressing
  towards. This one is gonna be a good one. USA, here I come.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today I spent far too much money on plane tickets, but I am very excited - this is my first big, Adult Holiday. I am leaving work behind for two weeks and heading across the sea to the Big Apple, to go visit my best friend, along with another friend who I am excited to travel with and get to know better. I can't wait to get super fat on bagels, cheesecake and pizza, and learn to perfectly mimic a Lawn Guy Land accent. I'm gonna take a trip the Statue of Liberty, go see the Nets and then maybe bump into the President Pete Davidson. It's gonna be sick. It's going to cost a lot, and there's a lot of potential for me to get super anxious. But you know what, I don't care. This could be one of the best trips of my life, and I'm not going to let shallow pockets or a restless mind stop me from enjoying it. It's important for me to have things to look forward to when my health is bad. They're milestones, a place on the horizon that I can focus on slowly progressing towards. This one is gonna be a good one. USA, here I come.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">YouTube</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YouTube" /><published>2019-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube">&lt;p&gt;
  I absolutely &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt; to hate popular things. Tropical house, Regina George and pumpkin
  spiced lattes can all suck my dick. I will usually completely forego any kind
  of fair judgment process for something if I knew it's well-liked by the masses,
  and skip straight towards loudly proclaiming my distaste for it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So, in the spirit of trying to not be as shitty of a person, today I wanted to
  talk about how much I love YouTube, and how I think it is a monument to the
  human experience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Firstly - YouTube has its problems. Its a subsidiary of Alphabet, so you
  bet they are gobbling your data. The site has an obligation to appease advertisers
  and copyright holders so they make a lot of strange and seemingly nonsensical
  decisions on those grounds, and in so doing threatening the livelihoods of people
  who rely on their platform as a sole form of income. There's a lot of weird,
  immoral, illegal shit on there. And it seems like there's a new bizarro world
  of Ukrainian content farms exploiting children for millions of dollars.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But, let's sweep those all under the carpet for a moment. I love YouTube as a
  platform. It educates and entertains me, and the ASMR videos on there literally
  help me sleep at night. Why do I hold it in such higher esteem than most other
  sites of its size?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think YouTube offers both creators and consumers of content far more freedom
  than other platforms. There isn't really a formula for success on YouTube the same
  way there is on, for example, Instagram (in case you were wondering, the formula
  there is to post airbrushed photos of scantily clad, but perfect, body). The
  infamous 'algorithm', as well as advertising stipulations, naturally reward some
  people more than others, but channels of all shapes and sizes flourish. With
  the obvious caveat that this is all based on my personal experience with the
  recommendation algorithm and my own interests, but I absorb content from 30 second
  glorious shitpost videos to documentaries over an hour long. I watch music videos,
  comedy videos, journalistic videos, review videos, podcasts, programming videos,
  lifting videos, gaming videos, chess videos, ASMR videos, and probably far more.
  Having all these interests in one convenient place, and getting recommendations
  for similar content based on my habits, is actually pretty neat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Of course what makes YouTube great is absolutely not the company or the website
  itself, it's the people on it. Sure, there are literally millions of people
  churning out hypergarbage every day, but there are a surprisingly large amount
  of really wonderful, funny, insightful, enriching channels that aren't unecessarily
  difficult to find. The oft-feared comment section is admittedly laden with naysayers
  and unwell-wishers, but there are plenty of corners of the site which feel like
  an actual &lt;i&gt;community,&lt;/i&gt; often formed around a group of niche channels, where
  people are not all total assholes to each other. If you look hard enough, you
  can find these pockets of resistance, where people are actually people and not
  monsters. And I like that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Give it a few more years and I'm sure it'll have all gone to shit though.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Social Media" /><summary type="html">I absolutely love to hate popular things. Tropical house, Regina George and pumpkin spiced lattes can all suck my dick. I will usually completely forego any kind of fair judgment process for something if I knew it's well-liked by the masses, and skip straight towards loudly proclaiming my distaste for it. So, in the spirit of trying to not be as shitty of a person, today I wanted to talk about how much I love YouTube, and how I think it is a monument to the human experience. Firstly - YouTube has its problems. Its a subsidiary of Alphabet, so you bet they are gobbling your data. The site has an obligation to appease advertisers and copyright holders so they make a lot of strange and seemingly nonsensical decisions on those grounds, and in so doing threatening the livelihoods of people who rely on their platform as a sole form of income. There's a lot of weird, immoral, illegal shit on there. And it seems like there's a new bizarro world of Ukrainian content farms exploiting children for millions of dollars. But, let's sweep those all under the carpet for a moment. I love YouTube as a platform. It educates and entertains me, and the ASMR videos on there literally help me sleep at night. Why do I hold it in such higher esteem than most other sites of its size? I think YouTube offers both creators and consumers of content far more freedom than other platforms. There isn't really a formula for success on YouTube the same way there is on, for example, Instagram (in case you were wondering, the formula there is to post airbrushed photos of scantily clad, but perfect, body). The infamous 'algorithm', as well as advertising stipulations, naturally reward some people more than others, but channels of all shapes and sizes flourish. With the obvious caveat that this is all based on my personal experience with the recommendation algorithm and my own interests, but I absorb content from 30 second glorious shitpost videos to documentaries over an hour long. I watch music videos, comedy videos, journalistic videos, review videos, podcasts, programming videos, lifting videos, gaming videos, chess videos, ASMR videos, and probably far more. Having all these interests in one convenient place, and getting recommendations for similar content based on my habits, is actually pretty neat. Of course what makes YouTube great is absolutely not the company or the website itself, it's the people on it. Sure, there are literally millions of people churning out hypergarbage every day, but there are a surprisingly large amount of really wonderful, funny, insightful, enriching channels that aren't unecessarily difficult to find. The oft-feared comment section is admittedly laden with naysayers and unwell-wishers, but there are plenty of corners of the site which feel like an actual community, often formed around a group of niche channels, where people are not all total assholes to each other. If you look hard enough, you can find these pockets of resistance, where people are actually people and not monsters. And I like that. Give it a few more years and I'm sure it'll have all gone to shit though.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gell-Mann Amnesia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/04/gell-mann-amnesia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gell-Mann Amnesia" /><published>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/04/gell-mann-amnesia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/04/gell-mann-amnesia">&lt;p&gt;
  I've been thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gell-Mann_amnesia_effect&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gell-Mann
  Amnesia&lt;/a&gt; a lot recently. It doesn't really have any legitimacy as a psychological
  idea - in fact, as far as I can tell, it is little more than an offhand anecdote
  made by Michael Crichton - but it's interesting nonetheless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The concept intuitively makes sense. Not that I am really an expert in anything,
  but I have seen my fair share of claims-as-facts in media that I think are dubious,
  if not pure bollocks. Sure, maybe I am wrong in all these instances, and the
  writer of said comment was correct - but it usually does little to shake my faith
  in the rest of the information in the publication as a whole.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are many nuances to be considered. For example, if you read something
  on my blog that you felt was clearly erroneous, it might greatly shake your trust in my
  blog as a source, whereas if you read an article in the New York Times that
  you felt similarly about, it might have a smaller affect on your feelings towards the Times as
  a whole. I suspect many readers of news outlets of that ilk ignore the actual
  author of the piece, although in the context of Gell-Mann Amnesia, it seems
  very important to pay attention to who that is. Which I suppose raises some
  questions about the differences between the group of individuals that compromise
  a journalistic endeavour, and the endeavour itself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We could examine the phenomenon on a very broad scale too. I have read an inordinate
  number of factually inaccurate tweets - should I no longer give any credence to
  anything I read on Twitter? Admittedly, in that example, probably not. What about the internet as a whole? There 
  is petabytes of blatant misinformation waiting to be consumed by unsuspecting
  webizens, can we believe any of it any more?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Well, that is the million dollar question. What do you think?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Psychology" /><summary type="html">I've been thinking about Gell-Mann Amnesia a lot recently. It doesn't really have any legitimacy as a psychological idea - in fact, as far as I can tell, it is little more than an offhand anecdote made by Michael Crichton - but it's interesting nonetheless. The concept intuitively makes sense. Not that I am really an expert in anything, but I have seen my fair share of claims-as-facts in media that I think are dubious, if not pure bollocks. Sure, maybe I am wrong in all these instances, and the writer of said comment was correct - but it usually does little to shake my faith in the rest of the information in the publication as a whole. There are many nuances to be considered. For example, if you read something on my blog that you felt was clearly erroneous, it might greatly shake your trust in my blog as a source, whereas if you read an article in the New York Times that you felt similarly about, it might have a smaller affect on your feelings towards the Times as a whole. I suspect many readers of news outlets of that ilk ignore the actual author of the piece, although in the context of Gell-Mann Amnesia, it seems very important to pay attention to who that is. Which I suppose raises some questions about the differences between the group of individuals that compromise a journalistic endeavour, and the endeavour itself. We could examine the phenomenon on a very broad scale too. I have read an inordinate number of factually inaccurate tweets - should I no longer give any credence to anything I read on Twitter? Admittedly, in that example, probably not. What about the internet as a whole? There is petabytes of blatant misinformation waiting to be consumed by unsuspecting webizens, can we believe any of it any more? Well, that is the million dollar question. What do you think?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sickness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/03/sickness" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sickness" /><published>2019-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/03/sickness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/03/sickness">&lt;p&gt;
  Today, I am very sick. After all the excitement of yesterday, it is a little
  disappointing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But there is something important to learn from this bullshit fever I have. As the
  long worn-out proverb says, when you have toothache, all you can think about
  is the pain your jaw. When it subside, you are filled with gratitude to the
  universe - but it never lasts. So, when I am better, I am going to try to hold
  on to the happiness of the status quo of my existence as much as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Today, I am very sick. After all the excitement of yesterday, it is a little disappointing. But there is something important to learn from this bullshit fever I have. As the long worn-out proverb says, when you have toothache, all you can think about is the pain your jaw. When it subside, you are filled with gratitude to the universe - but it never lasts. So, when I am better, I am going to try to hold on to the happiness of the status quo of my existence as much as possible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beware of Dog III</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/02/beware-of-dog-iii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beware of Dog III" /><published>2019-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/02/beware-of-dog-iii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/02/beware-of-dog-iii">&lt;p&gt;
  2019 is off to a flying start, I think I am happier today than any day I was
  in 2018. I feel like I could cry tears of joy. I know this feeling won't last,
  and it will hurt again soon, but I don't care. I want to enjoy these moments
  for what they are.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I saw the dog again today. I got to play with, pick it up, feed it. And the most
  amazing thing happened - I didn't feel scared at all. And I knew I wouldn't
  be scared again in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I feel like I can see in colour for the first time, like a tumour has been removed
  from my brain and the chronic pain has finally ceased after years of grinding
  me down. It's an indescribable relief.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  To depart from the analogy for a second - the real reason I have managed to
  conquer this particular anxiety is through perseverance. It's taken a lot of
  work to get to this point, I wanted to give up so many times, but I didn't,
  regardless of the pain. And now it's finally gone. And it wasn't fluke - I actually
  did it myself. I didn't fail or underachieve, instead I achieved more than I ever thought
  possible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And if I can beat this, I can beat anything.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">2019 is off to a flying start, I think I am happier today than any day I was in 2018. I feel like I could cry tears of joy. I know this feeling won't last, and it will hurt again soon, but I don't care. I want to enjoy these moments for what they are. I saw the dog again today. I got to play with, pick it up, feed it. And the most amazing thing happened - I didn't feel scared at all. And I knew I wouldn't be scared again in the future. I feel like I can see in colour for the first time, like a tumour has been removed from my brain and the chronic pain has finally ceased after years of grinding me down. It's an indescribable relief. To depart from the analogy for a second - the real reason I have managed to conquer this particular anxiety is through perseverance. It's taken a lot of work to get to this point, I wanted to give up so many times, but I didn't, regardless of the pain. And now it's finally gone. And it wasn't fluke - I actually did it myself. I didn't fail or underachieve, instead I achieved more than I ever thought possible. And if I can beat this, I can beat anything.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year's Resolutions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/01/new-years-resolutions" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year&amp;#39;s Resolutions" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/01/new-years-resolutions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/01/new-years-resolutions">&lt;p&gt;
  I'm sure I have decried the concept of New Year's Resolutions in the past, but
  now I am older and supposedly wiser, I think they're actually pretty great. Sure
  - if you want to change your life, start now. But we all get trapped in cycles
  of habit - January 1st is a good opportunity to take a step back and evaluate,
  to try to set yourself onto a new path.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have failed at so many things in my life. There are so many goals I have set
  over, and over, and over again, seemingly oblivious to the many previous defeats
  I had faced. For the past couple of weeks, I have pondered whether it's worth
  setting the same goals, or any goals at all. Am I being naïve by saying I want
  to lose weight, improve my self esteem and become more connected to people?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Who cares if I am. Naiveté is great - it gives me hope. Ignorance of potential
  negative realities of my situation is blissful. I don't want to give up on my
  idealism and by the same token I want to keep beleiving that I can change, even
  if I haven't managed it on previous occasions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My resolution last year was not to kill myself, and hey, I fucking nailed it.
  so I'm gonna up the ante for this year. I'm gonna lose weight and get jacked,
  I'm gonna improve my self esteem (but not as a result of losing weight and
  getting jacked) and I'm going to become closer to the people around me. Bring it
  on.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I'm sure I have decried the concept of New Year's Resolutions in the past, but now I am older and supposedly wiser, I think they're actually pretty great. Sure - if you want to change your life, start now. But we all get trapped in cycles of habit - January 1st is a good opportunity to take a step back and evaluate, to try to set yourself onto a new path. I have failed at so many things in my life. There are so many goals I have set over, and over, and over again, seemingly oblivious to the many previous defeats I had faced. For the past couple of weeks, I have pondered whether it's worth setting the same goals, or any goals at all. Am I being naïve by saying I want to lose weight, improve my self esteem and become more connected to people? Who cares if I am. Naiveté is great - it gives me hope. Ignorance of potential negative realities of my situation is blissful. I don't want to give up on my idealism and by the same token I want to keep beleiving that I can change, even if I haven't managed it on previous occasions. My resolution last year was not to kill myself, and hey, I fucking nailed it. so I'm gonna up the ante for this year. I'm gonna lose weight and get jacked, I'm gonna improve my self esteem (but not as a result of losing weight and getting jacked) and I'm going to become closer to the people around me. Bring it on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Unplanned Year</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Unplanned Year" /><published>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tartarus/2018/12/31/the-unplanned-year">&lt;p&gt;
  It’s fair to say that looking back at 2018, it was a radical departure from the
  plan. At the start of the year, I had been rudely awakened from the fever dream
  of ‘professional' poker and found myself lying in the cold pool of sweat that
  was not having a clue what I am going to do with my life. I had been forced to
  deviate from the path I had chosen, and had arrived at what felt more like a
  cul-de-sac than a fork in the road.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  To look further back in time, only a few short years ago I had been at university reading law, with a long
  term girlfriend. I was going to become an advocate, marry her, make an unnecessary
  amount of money, buy a boat and have 2.4 children and a hypoallergenic dog.
  Neither the law nor the lady panned out, so then I got a job as a sports trader
  and rented a flat. Then the plan became to rise through the ranks, become a god-tier
  market analyst, work hard and smart enough to make the company an amount of money
  exponentially more unnecessary than the one aforementioned, and be justly rewarded
  with a portion of it myself. I had officially fled the nest, I was never going
  to move back in with my parents, I would find a new partner and be less impetuous
  about the whole plan-to-be-together-forever thing. I was an Adult, with a capital A.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Obviously that didn’t work out either. It turned out that once again, I had
  displayed exceptionally poor judgment in selecting people close to me, and my
  roommate got us kicked out. Around that time I donked my way to a wholly undeserved
  $25k score in an MTT, and paired my lack of judgment with truly breathtaking
  naïveté by quitting my job and sheepishly moving back in with my parents to play
  poker full time. I slowly bled away the money I had earned over the next few months,
  meanwhile neither furthering my career nor acknowledging my deteriorating mental
  health. In a moment of blind optimism, I once again tried to flee my parents’
  metaphorical basement, by packing a suitcase and heading across the Atlantic,
  to Mexico. I vowed to never come back; I would work hard to overcome my poker
  woes, and enjoy the lifestyle of a digital nomad for the rest of my days. I
  would start a travel Instagram filled with more clichés than a Buzzfeed listicle
  and proceed to have sex with untold numbers of free-spirited
  backpackers who hadn’t showered in weeks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In retrospect, I really don’t understand how I thought that was actually going
  to a work. I’m equal part ashamed of myself and impressed at my own lack of touch
  with reality. This time last year, on the verge of having a breakdown
  that could well have ended my life, I flew back to Guernsey, and moved back in
  with my parents again. I had no job and no plan, but on the bright side I had
  the mother of all existential and identity crises to keep me warm at night. It
  wasn’t actually all that warm: to continue the metaphor, if my self esteem was
  a temperature, it was -273.15°C. The particles of my soul appeared to have ceased
  all vibrations. Everything I had built my identity around had evaporated and I
  really, truly felt like a failure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I survived for three months doing absolutely nothing, spending 15 hours a day
  playing Runescape, leaving the house once a week or less. I didn’t even think
  about the future, only bearing to take one day at a time, focusing solely on my
  virtual life, the entirety of my socialising being with members of my online clan. My character
  seemed to have his life in far better order than I did - he set goals and
  accomplished them. He was perseverant, successful and respected.  If my life
  goals were to complete quests, slay mythical beings and rescue damsels in distress,
  I could’ve learned a lot from being more like him. I was doing my best to numb
  myself to the visceral pain of reality, but I knew living off my parents’ pity
  forever was not a viable lifestyle choice. My less-than-comprehensive ‘plan’
  was to focus on improving my mental health first, and worry about actively
  participating in society later.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  As if I was not already abusing my privilege enough at this point, the universe
  delivered me another lightning bolt of unwarranted good karma at the end of March.
  I dread to think what manner of grim persecution I must’ve faced in a previous life
  to be so fortunate in this one. Out of nowhere, I got an email from my now-employers
  asking if I wanted to interview for a web development position, after having
  speculatively sent them my CV 4 years prior.
  My initial response could be summed up as ‘uhh…. are you sure?’, and much to my
  surprise the answer was yes. This surprise turned to full-blown bafflement upon
  being offered the job in question - what would it be like working for an employer
  that seemed to have such low hiring standards? Had they seen through my ruse of
  confidence and aptitude at the interview, and upon realising how pathetic my existence
  was, decided to offer me the position out of pure compassion? Was I the dog in
  the shelter that nobody else would take home at Christmas, after a lifetime of
  neglect, my fur matted and eyes milky?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It seems not, I had actually fooled them. I can only imagine what the other
  candidates were like. The job pool for developers here is more of a job puddle,
  so I suppose it shouldn’t be that much of a shock to me that they were faced
  with a best-of-a-bad-bunch situation. And here I am, 9 months later, having
  started with no meaningful knowledge of programming whatsoever, now a somewhat
  passable web developer. I’ve picked up quite a few marketable skills: front-end
  CSS and Javascript, back-end PHP, git, Linux, basic server admin and devops.
  I’ve read Hacker News every day for months and have discovered a newfound adoration
  of technology, startups and ideas, as dumb as the last one might sound. The
  industry has given me some sense of hope about the future, that there are people
  genuinely trying to make others’ lives better. I have increased the number of
  acronyms I know by several orders of magnitude, but I still have no clue why
  programmers like recursive ones so much - they’re not funny guys. You can do
  better. Stop it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It seems like I’ve at least accrued some good career capital in 2018 then, but
  has my mental health improved similarly over the last 9 months?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  No, of course not. Don’t be stupid.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I can’t really review the year fairly without talking about my health struggles.
  At the start of the year I was a true NEET, and seemed to have no direction in life at all. Now,
  I leave the house every day, have a full time job and have signed a lease for
  a flat, so you might think I am doing significantly better, but in truth, I don’t
  think I am.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Despite being high functioning, I have been battling depression as frantically as ever
  and I would say this has been one of the worst years of my life in
  that regard. It is a war of attrition, and it has been raging for a long
  time now. Where a proud rockface of motivation and emotional resilience once
  stood, an unforgiving sea of misery has eroded the cliffs such that they are crumbling
  and the homesteads atop them are in an evermore precarious position. I’ve struggled with it
  for 10 years, but when I was younger there was still a sense of hope that this
  was merely teenage angst, and I might grow out of it the same way I grew out of
  eczema and stuffed toys. This year has well and truly brought home the point that
  that isn’t going to happen and that any change is going to be slow, difficult
  and painful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Speaking about depression has become a little easier, but one component
  of it is still a taboo and immensely hard to speak about, even though it is
  the element most necessary to talk about openly and honestly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Talking about suicide is a little bit like talking about the menstrual cycle
  (hear me out). I didn’t get the best sex-ed in school, and when I was a teenager
  with a girlfriend for the first time, I thought I had the basics covered, but
  really I had no clue about how the whole period thing works. One month my it turned out that
  she was late by a couple of days, and I had no idea whether this was normal
  and fine or she was 100% pregnant and I needed to start re-planning my life accordingly.
  On one hand I was a dumb kid, but on the other hand I was in a terrifying situation
  with a lot less information than I would’ve liked. I think trying to talk to
  someone about suicidality is often the same - if I say to someone “I’ve been
  thinking about killing myself recently”, they really have no way of knowing if
  I mean that one rogue thought popped into my head and I have no dangerous intentions
  whatsoever, or if I am planning on ending it all tonight and this is my final
  goodbye. I have had that conversation with a few people this year and every time
  I think I have done a poor job of articulating the reality of the situation and
  explaining what I would like them to do to help me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The truth is, the concept of suicide is a big part of my life, and so I need to
  talk about it. I suppose a big part of the reason it’s difficult to talk about
  is because it can worry the other person, they can feel a sense of responsibility,
  and the knowledge may become a painful burden to them. To try to allay any of
  these worries you might have dear reader, I would like to tell you with a reasonable
  amount of certainty that I will never actually go through with killing myself,
  perhaps barring any major changes to my life circumstances.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There’s always been a part of me that very strongly wants to keep on living,
  and sometimes it is more noticeable than others. I think the fact it is part of my
  consciousness is a good reason to keep going. Given that I have not previously
  taken my own life despite reaching what felt like rock bottom on multiple occasions,
  it seems very unlikely that I will do it in the future, another positive sign.
  Right now I am also more hopeful about improving my health going forward than
  I have been in a long time, maybe ever, for reasons I have already talked about
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/12/david-goggins-ii&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/30/beware-of-dog-ii&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
  I’ve thought about it a lot and felt for a long time like there is a choice to
  be made between killing myself and trying to get better, accepting that the
  latter will be even more agonizing then I feel like my current situation is.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=46GwJbrMghQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  Get busy living or get busy dying,&lt;/a&gt; as one might say.
  So, I have finally made a choice to get better, no matter how harrowing that experience may be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Again, that might sound positive, but to be honest I am struggling with it. The
  main attraction of suicide is that it offers a solution to all your problems,
  albeit an inelegant one. With that solution removed, I am back to the drawing
  board on all the things that are causing me pain in the first place. I feel
  directionless and terrified at the prospect of trying to deal with everything.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But I am determined to deal with it nonetheless. I suppose I'll have to take baby steps.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So that was the unplanned year. Making any kind of plan for next year seems somewhat
  futile - perhaps my life will take another wholly unexpected turn and I make another
  suitably angular career change or end up in some far-flung part of the world or get married
  to someone I’ve yet to meet. Perhaps nothing will change, and I can just copy
  and paste this post for my 2019 year-in-review piece.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am making one plan though - to try everything I can to get better. Happy New Year, friends.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">It’s fair to say that looking back at 2018, it was a radical departure from the plan. At the start of the year, I had been rudely awakened from the fever dream of ‘professional' poker and found myself lying in the cold pool of sweat that was not having a clue what I am going to do with my life. I had been forced to deviate from the path I had chosen, and had arrived at what felt more like a cul-de-sac than a fork in the road. To look further back in time, only a few short years ago I had been at university reading law, with a long term girlfriend. I was going to become an advocate, marry her, make an unnecessary amount of money, buy a boat and have 2.4 children and a hypoallergenic dog. Neither the law nor the lady panned out, so then I got a job as a sports trader and rented a flat. Then the plan became to rise through the ranks, become a god-tier market analyst, work hard and smart enough to make the company an amount of money exponentially more unnecessary than the one aforementioned, and be justly rewarded with a portion of it myself. I had officially fled the nest, I was never going to move back in with my parents, I would find a new partner and be less impetuous about the whole plan-to-be-together-forever thing. I was an Adult, with a capital A. Obviously that didn’t work out either. It turned out that once again, I had displayed exceptionally poor judgment in selecting people close to me, and my roommate got us kicked out. Around that time I donked my way to a wholly undeserved $25k score in an MTT, and paired my lack of judgment with truly breathtaking naïveté by quitting my job and sheepishly moving back in with my parents to play poker full time. I slowly bled away the money I had earned over the next few months, meanwhile neither furthering my career nor acknowledging my deteriorating mental health. In a moment of blind optimism, I once again tried to flee my parents’ metaphorical basement, by packing a suitcase and heading across the Atlantic, to Mexico. I vowed to never come back; I would work hard to overcome my poker woes, and enjoy the lifestyle of a digital nomad for the rest of my days. I would start a travel Instagram filled with more clichés than a Buzzfeed listicle and proceed to have sex with untold numbers of free-spirited backpackers who hadn’t showered in weeks. In retrospect, I really don’t understand how I thought that was actually going to a work. I’m equal part ashamed of myself and impressed at my own lack of touch with reality. This time last year, on the verge of having a breakdown that could well have ended my life, I flew back to Guernsey, and moved back in with my parents again. I had no job and no plan, but on the bright side I had the mother of all existential and identity crises to keep me warm at night. It wasn’t actually all that warm: to continue the metaphor, if my self esteem was a temperature, it was -273.15°C. The particles of my soul appeared to have ceased all vibrations. Everything I had built my identity around had evaporated and I really, truly felt like a failure. I survived for three months doing absolutely nothing, spending 15 hours a day playing Runescape, leaving the house once a week or less. I didn’t even think about the future, only bearing to take one day at a time, focusing solely on my virtual life, the entirety of my socialising being with members of my online clan. My character seemed to have his life in far better order than I did - he set goals and accomplished them. He was perseverant, successful and respected. If my life goals were to complete quests, slay mythical beings and rescue damsels in distress, I could’ve learned a lot from being more like him. I was doing my best to numb myself to the visceral pain of reality, but I knew living off my parents’ pity forever was not a viable lifestyle choice. My less-than-comprehensive ‘plan’ was to focus on improving my mental health first, and worry about actively participating in society later. As if I was not already abusing my privilege enough at this point, the universe delivered me another lightning bolt of unwarranted good karma at the end of March. I dread to think what manner of grim persecution I must’ve faced in a previous life to be so fortunate in this one. Out of nowhere, I got an email from my now-employers asking if I wanted to interview for a web development position, after having speculatively sent them my CV 4 years prior. My initial response could be summed up as ‘uhh…. are you sure?’, and much to my surprise the answer was yes. This surprise turned to full-blown bafflement upon being offered the job in question - what would it be like working for an employer that seemed to have such low hiring standards? Had they seen through my ruse of confidence and aptitude at the interview, and upon realising how pathetic my existence was, decided to offer me the position out of pure compassion? Was I the dog in the shelter that nobody else would take home at Christmas, after a lifetime of neglect, my fur matted and eyes milky? It seems not, I had actually fooled them. I can only imagine what the other candidates were like. The job pool for developers here is more of a job puddle, so I suppose it shouldn’t be that much of a shock to me that they were faced with a best-of-a-bad-bunch situation. And here I am, 9 months later, having started with no meaningful knowledge of programming whatsoever, now a somewhat passable web developer. I’ve picked up quite a few marketable skills: front-end CSS and Javascript, back-end PHP, git, Linux, basic server admin and devops. I’ve read Hacker News every day for months and have discovered a newfound adoration of technology, startups and ideas, as dumb as the last one might sound. The industry has given me some sense of hope about the future, that there are people genuinely trying to make others’ lives better. I have increased the number of acronyms I know by several orders of magnitude, but I still have no clue why programmers like recursive ones so much - they’re not funny guys. You can do better. Stop it. It seems like I’ve at least accrued some good career capital in 2018 then, but has my mental health improved similarly over the last 9 months? No, of course not. Don’t be stupid. I can’t really review the year fairly without talking about my health struggles. At the start of the year I was a true NEET, and seemed to have no direction in life at all. Now, I leave the house every day, have a full time job and have signed a lease for a flat, so you might think I am doing significantly better, but in truth, I don’t think I am. Despite being high functioning, I have been battling depression as frantically as ever and I would say this has been one of the worst years of my life in that regard. It is a war of attrition, and it has been raging for a long time now. Where a proud rockface of motivation and emotional resilience once stood, an unforgiving sea of misery has eroded the cliffs such that they are crumbling and the homesteads atop them are in an evermore precarious position. I’ve struggled with it for 10 years, but when I was younger there was still a sense of hope that this was merely teenage angst, and I might grow out of it the same way I grew out of eczema and stuffed toys. This year has well and truly brought home the point that that isn’t going to happen and that any change is going to be slow, difficult and painful. Speaking about depression has become a little easier, but one component of it is still a taboo and immensely hard to speak about, even though it is the element most necessary to talk about openly and honestly. Talking about suicide is a little bit like talking about the menstrual cycle (hear me out). I didn’t get the best sex-ed in school, and when I was a teenager with a girlfriend for the first time, I thought I had the basics covered, but really I had no clue about how the whole period thing works. One month my it turned out that she was late by a couple of days, and I had no idea whether this was normal and fine or she was 100% pregnant and I needed to start re-planning my life accordingly. On one hand I was a dumb kid, but on the other hand I was in a terrifying situation with a lot less information than I would’ve liked. I think trying to talk to someone about suicidality is often the same - if I say to someone “I’ve been thinking about killing myself recently”, they really have no way of knowing if I mean that one rogue thought popped into my head and I have no dangerous intentions whatsoever, or if I am planning on ending it all tonight and this is my final goodbye. I have had that conversation with a few people this year and every time I think I have done a poor job of articulating the reality of the situation and explaining what I would like them to do to help me. The truth is, the concept of suicide is a big part of my life, and so I need to talk about it. I suppose a big part of the reason it’s difficult to talk about is because it can worry the other person, they can feel a sense of responsibility, and the knowledge may become a painful burden to them. To try to allay any of these worries you might have dear reader, I would like to tell you with a reasonable amount of certainty that I will never actually go through with killing myself, perhaps barring any major changes to my life circumstances. There’s always been a part of me that very strongly wants to keep on living, and sometimes it is more noticeable than others. I think the fact it is part of my consciousness is a good reason to keep going. Given that I have not previously taken my own life despite reaching what felt like rock bottom on multiple occasions, it seems very unlikely that I will do it in the future, another positive sign. Right now I am also more hopeful about improving my health going forward than I have been in a long time, maybe ever, for reasons I have already talked about here and here. I’ve thought about it a lot and felt for a long time like there is a choice to be made between killing myself and trying to get better, accepting that the latter will be even more agonizing then I feel like my current situation is. Get busy living or get busy dying, as one might say. So, I have finally made a choice to get better, no matter how harrowing that experience may be. Again, that might sound positive, but to be honest I am struggling with it. The main attraction of suicide is that it offers a solution to all your problems, albeit an inelegant one. With that solution removed, I am back to the drawing board on all the things that are causing me pain in the first place. I feel directionless and terrified at the prospect of trying to deal with everything. But I am determined to deal with it nonetheless. I suppose I'll have to take baby steps. So that was the unplanned year. Making any kind of plan for next year seems somewhat futile - perhaps my life will take another wholly unexpected turn and I make another suitably angular career change or end up in some far-flung part of the world or get married to someone I’ve yet to meet. Perhaps nothing will change, and I can just copy and paste this post for my 2019 year-in-review piece. I am making one plan though - to try everything I can to get better. Happy New Year, friends.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Language of Sadness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/31/the-language-of-sadness" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Language of Sadness" /><published>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/31/the-language-of-sadness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/31/the-language-of-sadness">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://daily.jstor.org/people-with-depression-use-language-differently/&quot;
  target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;this article,&lt;/a&gt; which talks about depression
  changing the language people use in speech and writing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Some of the points it makes are (very) intuitive, such as that depressed people
  tend to use more negative words, or deal in absolutes. I thought it was super
  interesting that depressed people use first person singular pronouns more often
  than not depressed people, in part because it is less obvious, and also because
  it's something I know I do a tonne in my own writing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The effect is supposedly linked to the social isolation experienced by people
  with depression. They rarely talk about 'they's, because they do not feel connected
  enough with people around them to relate to or talk about them. One of my biggest
  complaints about the way I write is that I start too many sentences with 'I feel',
  'I think' etc, but I have allowed it, as the purpose of writing here is of course
  to express myself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Maybe I will start writing about other people more, although I'm not sure
  that they'd appreciate it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Blogging" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Today I read this article, which talks about depression changing the language people use in speech and writing. Some of the points it makes are (very) intuitive, such as that depressed people tend to use more negative words, or deal in absolutes. I thought it was super interesting that depressed people use first person singular pronouns more often than not depressed people, in part because it is less obvious, and also because it's something I know I do a tonne in my own writing. The effect is supposedly linked to the social isolation experienced by people with depression. They rarely talk about 'they's, because they do not feel connected enough with people around them to relate to or talk about them. One of my biggest complaints about the way I write is that I start too many sentences with 'I feel', 'I think' etc, but I have allowed it, as the purpose of writing here is of course to express myself. Maybe I will start writing about other people more, although I'm not sure that they'd appreciate it.</summary></entry></feed>