<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-08T20:05:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Personality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/08/running-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Personality" /><published>2019-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/08/running-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/08/running-ii">&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/01/19/a-little-discussed-effect-of-therapy-it-changes-your-personality/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; today 
I was reminded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.understandmyself.com/&quot;&gt;Lobsterboy’s personality test&lt;/a&gt; last year, but I don’t think I ever wrote about the results. 
The self reported test measures the ‘Big Five’ personality taits, each of which are split into two sub-traits. All numbers relate to percentiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agreeableness - 57
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compassion - 48&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Politness - 65&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conscientiousness - 0
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Mental Health and Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">After reading this article today I was reminded Lobsterboy’s personality test last year, but I don’t think I ever wrote about the results. The self reported test measures the ‘Big Five’ personality taits, each of which are split into two sub-traits. All numbers relate to percentiles.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Should I Call Myself a Feminist II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/07/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Should I Call Myself a Feminist II" /><published>2019-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/07/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/07/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist-ii">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I may have inadvertently outed myself as a bit of a basement dweller. If any of my opinion around feminism is informed 
by consuming whatever I read on Reddit, I ought to re-evaluate.  I’ve seen it hypothesized that 1% of Redditors generate 99% of 
comments and posts, and intuitively I believe it - clearly that kind of system is not going to foster a healthy environment for 
discussion. It’s also a conversation in which I participate in very passively - I’ve only commented on anything across the entirety 
of Reddit in the last year, once to get a beta invite for &lt;a href=&quot;https://tildes.net/&quot;&gt;Tildes&lt;/a&gt; and once to troll my roommate (about something 
other than gender).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criticism has also been levied against me that I did not in fact answer the question of whether or not I should call myself a feminist, 
which I think is valid. My is that yes, I probably &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; call myself a feminist, but am still too much of a pussy to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d feel somewhat upset with myself to end on that note though, we need a hopeful sign off that leaves you feeling like there is the 
possibility of a brighter future for all of us, and lets me sleep wholly guilt free tonight. So, my promise is thus: I’ll try to 
talk to more people AFK about feminism, and overhaul my views to be in line with how I feel after those conversations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Social Issues" /><summary type="html">Yesterday I may have inadvertently outed myself as a bit of a basement dweller. If any of my opinion around feminism is informed by consuming whatever I read on Reddit, I ought to re-evaluate. I’ve seen it hypothesized that 1% of Redditors generate 99% of comments and posts, and intuitively I believe it - clearly that kind of system is not going to foster a healthy environment for discussion. It’s also a conversation in which I participate in very passively - I’ve only commented on anything across the entirety of Reddit in the last year, once to get a beta invite for Tildes and once to troll my roommate (about something other than gender).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Should I Call Myself a Feminist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/06/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Should I Call Myself a Feminist" /><published>2019-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/06/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/06/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist">&lt;p&gt;The Oxford English Dictionary defines femini- just kidding, fuck that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feminism is a perennial topic in social discourse at large, and recently in my own life too. As a man, I’ve always been apprehensive to 
approach the subject or voice any especially strong opinions on the matter because, well, I am de facto more likely to be part of the problem 
than the solution. But, in the spirit of trying to be a better person etc etc, perhaps I have a responsibility to infilitrate my own gender 
and dismantle the patriarchy from right under its very nose! If I were to brand myself as a feminist, surely fellow men, previously wallowing 
in misogyny, will see my example and realise the error of their ways?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I mean, I doubt it. I’m hardly a bastion of masculinity, nor a leader of many men, and frankly I wouldn’t take any notice of what I said if 
I were anyone else (and neither should you, dear reader). I think there is a credible argument to be made that even if I can move the needle one iota 
towards achieving gender equality that it would be worth my time, and if it were a true freeroll, then I would absolutely agree. My suspicion is that 
it is possible that branding myself as a feminist could certainly have a downside - admittedly I think that downside would be to me personally rather than 
the movement itself, but hey, we all know you’ve gotta look out for #1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I alluded to earlier, feminism is not easy to define (at least not for my small, malformed and regrettably male brain), and that is part of my reluctance
to take on the feminist label. Given that I spend much of my time in the radically polarised echo chambers that consitute the internet, I’m all too wary of 
misandry wearing the mask of fighting for equality, and I think that particular strategy is utterly doomed to fail in its quest to make any kind of inroads. 
For plenty of real people, I very much hope that feminism does simply mean social equality, particularly equality of opportunity, but seeing as I never go outside 
of never spoken to any of these “real” people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also something very disingenious in my mind about men who vocally brand themselves as allies of the feminist cause, but perhaps that is simply my relentless 
cynicism getting the better of me. I am mortally afraid of confrontation, and, rather upsettingly, I am sure the path to social parity is going to be defined by 
confrontation, and it would seem that I am too much of a coward to be willing to die on that particular hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I don’t feel as if I have earned the right to call myself a feminist. While it’s a dirty word in certain dark, unpleasant smelling corners of the web, all 
the women I know who staunchly avow the cause are strong, passionate, intelligent and inspirational. They are the ones who are suffering the great many injustices of 
modern society, not myself, and who are still resilient enough to fight tooth and nail to change things. I simply don’t deserve to ride on their 
coattails until I have actually done something meaningful to bring about change, and so until that happens, my reticence to call myself a feminist shall remain.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Social Issues" /><summary type="html">The Oxford English Dictionary defines femini- just kidding, fuck that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/05/running" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running" /><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/05/running</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/05/running">&lt;p&gt;I’m a runner now. I bought some shoes, I downloaded Strava and smashed out a 5k training run - my first ever 5k not on a treadmill. I’m not really sure if I find 
it fun yet, especially because the last 2km were determined much more by psychological rather than physical factors, but the satisfaction of being in significantly 
better shape than I thought I was has spurred me on to go again tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kipchoge here I come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Health and Fitness" /><summary type="html">I’m a runner now. I bought some shoes, I downloaded Strava and smashed out a 5k training run - my first ever 5k not on a treadmill. I’m not really sure if I find it fun yet, especially because the last 2km were determined much more by psychological rather than physical factors, but the satisfaction of being in significantly better shape than I thought I was has spurred me on to go again tomorrow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guernsey Literary Festival: Lionel Shriver</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/04/guernsey-literary-festival58-lionel-shriver" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guernsey Literary Festival&amp;#58; Lionel Shriver" /><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/04/guernsey-literary-festival58-lionel-shriver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/04/guernsey-literary-festival58-lionel-shriver">&lt;p&gt;In my second visit to a Guernsey Literary Festival event this week, I had the pleasure of watching Lionel Shriver in conversation with Libby Purves. 
Unfortunately for Ms Purves, I was less than blown away by her performance, although I regard Ms Shriver as something of an intellectual juggernaut 
so perhaps it was also going to be difficult to come off well by comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, Shriver came across as articulate, funny, wise and wholly unafraid to have her voice heard, arguably her most admirable quality. 
Known for expressing her views in spite of the prospect of meaningful backlash, she did the same here, even giving her stance as a Leave supporter 
(to the rapturous and spectacularly childish applause of approximately three members of the audience). Listening to her talk candidly about her process, her 
characters, her views on topics such as cultural appropriation, and her feelings towards her body of work was an enlightening and inspiring 
experience and one which I would highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">In my second visit to a Guernsey Literary Festival event this week, I had the pleasure of watching Lionel Shriver in conversation with Libby Purves. Unfortunately for Ms Purves, I was less than blown away by her performance, although I regard Ms Shriver as something of an intellectual juggernaut so perhaps it was also going to be difficult to come off well by comparison.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I love you II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/03/i-love-you-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I love you II" /><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/03/i-love-you-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/03/i-love-you-ii">&lt;p&gt;Two years after &lt;a href=&quot;https://intothepalta.wordpress.com/2017/10/19/me-too/&quot;&gt;Mica posted this&lt;/a&gt;, and while the title certainly hasn’t stood the test of time, I think 
I recently came to feel differently about what she wrote. While she longed for her boyfriend to reciprocate her verbal affection, she gave it anyway, knowing 
that he was unlikely to give her what she so desired in return. While I previously &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2017/10/20/yesterday-my-roommate-posted-this-and&quot;&gt;mused about how weird the phrase itself is&lt;/a&gt;,
I wanted to add a little to that, and update my stance on saying ‘I love you’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am better at saying it now then I was back in October 2017 (which was not exactly a time in my life that was full of life). If you give me a beer, I’ll probably tell you 
I love you, for example. But now I have realised when &lt;em&gt;saying&lt;/em&gt; the phrase, rather than hearing it, can bring me the most joy - when I have no expectations to hear it in return. 
When I simply don’t care what the other person’s response is, when I am saying it purely to inform or remind them of the fact and ‘speak my truth’ (a phrase I am growing to loathe more 
and more) three words at a time. Obviously it’s not easy, but when I previously talked of other times in my life I had said those words, they were almost always uttered for the purpose 
of being on the receiving end of it immediately afterwards. And now, they are not, and I like that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">Two years after Mica posted this, and while the title certainly hasn’t stood the test of time, I think I recently came to feel differently about what she wrote. While she longed for her boyfriend to reciprocate her verbal affection, she gave it anyway, knowing that he was unlikely to give her what she so desired in return. While I previously mused about how weird the phrase itself is, I wanted to add a little to that, and update my stance on saying ‘I love you’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guernsey Literary Festival: Adam Kay</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/02/guernsey-literary-festival-adam-kay" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guernsey Literary Festival&amp;#58; Adam Kay" /><published>2019-05-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/02/guernsey-literary-festival-adam-kay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/02/guernsey-literary-festival-adam-kay">&lt;p&gt;Today I had the pleasure of going to watch Adam Kay talk as part of the 7th edition of the Guernsey Literary Festival. It’s the first time 
I’ve actually attended one of these events, so I wasn’t entirely sure what to expect, but I hoped that the experience would make me feel cultured, 
and it was a great excuse to take a two hour lunchbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Kay (or Dr Kay, as he was formerly referred to) was speaking about his recent bestseller, “This is Going to Hurt” which recounts his experiences 
as a junior doctor in the NHS. Given that after he left medicine, he became a very successful comedian - repeatedly selling out a Fringe show and writing 
for Mitchell and Webb amongst others - it is no surprise that he was a funny guy and the book is marketed as being largely comedic. While I didn’t share
the crowds enthusiasm for all of his jokes, some of them did ellicit a genuine chuckle from me, so kudos to Mr Kay, and I am assured the book is definitely hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk, and I suspect the book, have a message that is far from comical, and indeed the things I took away from the venue this lunchtime were the brutal, harrowing 
personal stories that Kay shared. His expressed aim was to give the public at large an understanding of what doctors go through in their everyday lives, the toll it 
takes on their interpersonal relationships, the relentlessness of it all, the culture of suffering in silence and the lack of vital support networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there was a very much political component to his final, impassioned plea to the audience (which involved stressing the necessity of the NHS receiving more funding), 
I walked away with a change view of doctors and our healthcare system as a whole. They are every bit as human and mortal as the rest of us, but are frequently called on to 
perform superhuman tasks, without any of the recognition or admiration that comicbook heroes get. I feel incredibly privileged that I work in technology, that I will never have 
to do with anything as traumatising in my professional life as every healthcare professional does, and next time I visit my GP, I will have a far deeper level of respect for her than 
I previously held.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">Today I had the pleasure of going to watch Adam Kay talk as part of the 7th edition of the Guernsey Literary Festival. It’s the first time I’ve actually attended one of these events, so I wasn’t entirely sure what to expect, but I hoped that the experience would make me feel cultured, and it was a great excuse to take a two hour lunchbreak.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Another One Bites The Dust</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/01/another-one-bites-the-dust" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Another One Bites The Dust" /><published>2019-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/01/another-one-bites-the-dust</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/01/another-one-bites-the-dust">&lt;p&gt;So long, auf Wiedersehen, and goodnight to Snapchat, by some definitions the
vestigial social media app on my iPhone. Long gone are the days when you would
ferry me personalised pictures of women’s bodies and therefor, much of your
lustre has waned. My primary usage of you in the past couple of months has been twofold.
Firstly, you’re the last app with infinite scroll I had left, and whenever I
needed that glorious dopamine hit that comes from wasting my valuable time with
flashing lights and pretty colours, I will happily trawl through the sensationalist
pop culture garbage that is your discover section. The second is that a particular girl
who rejected me still keeps unilaterally sending me snaps of her complaining about
her work laptop being slow or running Windows updates or whatever. Is there some
social convention that I don’t understand? I have no qualms with you not wanting
to date me, in fact I think it’s laudable, it displays good decision making skills.
But don’t keep contacting me with your inane whining - isn’t that just socialisation 101?
Am I missing something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am reminded of my boy Torvalds’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/25-years-later-interview-linus-torvalds&quot;&gt;recent and now much-quoted interview&lt;/a&gt; where he bluntly described modern social media as a disease. I am
reluctant to even bring it up really, because I read the original interview first
and he makes multiple salient, relevant points, and the next day every tech media
outlet picked up on exactly that turn of phrase. He went on to elaborate that
they “encourage bad behaviour” and I think he is absolutely right, they have
encouraged my own personal bad behaviour, and even built whole new bad habits
into my psyche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/21/missing-social-media&quot;&gt;As discussed previously however,&lt;/a&gt;
ripping it out of my phone is not all I had hoped it would be. Hopefully saying
goodbye to Snapchat won’t create any additional FOMO, and will further my
drive to have more meaningful interactions with the people that matter to me, but
in anxious, troubled moments, perhaps flicking through it’s neverending stream
of trash was actually rather comforting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Social Media" /><summary type="html">So long, auf Wiedersehen, and goodnight to Snapchat, by some definitions the vestigial social media app on my iPhone. Long gone are the days when you would ferry me personalised pictures of women’s bodies and therefor, much of your lustre has waned. My primary usage of you in the past couple of months has been twofold. Firstly, you’re the last app with infinite scroll I had left, and whenever I needed that glorious dopamine hit that comes from wasting my valuable time with flashing lights and pretty colours, I will happily trawl through the sensationalist pop culture garbage that is your discover section. The second is that a particular girl who rejected me still keeps unilaterally sending me snaps of her complaining about her work laptop being slow or running Windows updates or whatever. Is there some social convention that I don’t understand? I have no qualms with you not wanting to date me, in fact I think it’s laudable, it displays good decision making skills. But don’t keep contacting me with your inane whining - isn’t that just socialisation 101? Am I missing something?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Playing at Being an Adult II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/30/playing-at-being-an-adult-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Playing at Being an Adult II" /><published>2019-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/30/playing-at-being-an-adult-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/30/playing-at-being-an-adult-ii">&lt;p&gt;After some thinking and a couple of interesting conversations following &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/04/12/playing-at-being-an-adult&quot;&gt;my first post on playing at being an adult&lt;/a&gt;,
I am quite seriously reconsidering my position. I missed out one key advantage of being an adult, although admittedly it is something of a double edged sword.
Adults have to accept the burden of responsibility over their own lives, but their reward for doing so is greater autonomy, and the chance to be the masters of their own
destiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps now is the time for me to transition into adulthood. I feel primed to cast off &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/02/07/reflecting-on-a-deleted-blog&quot;&gt;the notion that I’m a victim&lt;/a&gt;,
to accept that something doesn’t have to be my fault to be my responsibility, and to stop waxing lyrical in this blog about the changes I’m going to make in my life, and actually start
making them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never felt particularly in control of my own fate, and perhaps that is why I have historically felt so uneasy in my hometown, or in academia, or at the prospect of getting a desk job.
It very much feels like there’s been a path laid out before me, constituted primarily of those things, and part of me was resistant to that idea - not resistant enough to
change it much though. Maybe that was my life as a child, and my life as an adult will be to stand up for what I believe in, to take ownership of my future, and to ultimately
do what I want to do, rather than what I feel obligated to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">After some thinking and a couple of interesting conversations following my first post on playing at being an adult, I am quite seriously reconsidering my position. I missed out one key advantage of being an adult, although admittedly it is something of a double edged sword. Adults have to accept the burden of responsibility over their own lives, but their reward for doing so is greater autonomy, and the chance to be the masters of their own destiny.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Expectations Revisited</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/29/expectations-revisited" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Expectations Revisited" /><published>2019-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/29/expectations-revisited</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/29/expectations-revisited">&lt;p&gt;I am a big believe in the idea that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solveforhappy.com&quot;&gt;one’s happiness is the difference between one’s expectations and one’s reality&lt;/a&gt;.
I’ve also &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/03/i-expect-myself-to-have-more-than-24-hours-in-a-day&quot;&gt;previously hypothesized&lt;/a&gt; that one of the biggest causes of my 
historical unhappiness is my unrealisticly high expectations of myself and my life, and that I might be happier were I able to lower those expectations. 
That might sound easy, but in practice it has turned out to be substantially harder than I had expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I am enjoying this wave of newfound contentment, I am not so naive to think it will last forever, and it seems prescient to plan for one when 
things inevitably venture south once more. A good first step seems to be to try to internalise some new expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first trap is to think that if you set your expectations very, very low then you will be incredibly happy. If I repeat to myself 5x in the mirror every 
morning that my sole expectation is to wake up roughly once a day and respire consistently, then I’d be the happiest guy on earth. In actuality, our expectations run 
much deeper than that and are far more conditioner than at least I had initially realised. In all honesty, I’m not sure what the best way to change these 
internal settings is - but I think a good start would be to write them down, so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect to wake up roughly once a day and respire consistently;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect to make enough money to maintain my existing lifestyle;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to go to the gym at least 3x a week on average, unless I’m sick or travelling;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to eat less than 3000 calories a day, unless it’s a special occasion or I am particularly emotional that day;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to have no zero days;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to catch up with at least one friend a week;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to catch up with my brother at least every other week;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to learn at least one new thing about technology or my job every week;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to leave the house at least once a day;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect to make slow but continuous progress in my career;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect to make slow but continuous progress in the gym;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect to make slow but continuous progress at chess;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to continuously try to express myself more openly and more honestly;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to continuously work on loving myself more;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to continuously try to learn more about the world and try to be a better person in general;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I expect myself to write in this dumb blog every dumb day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seem like they are still fairly lofty goals, but perhaps I will have to come down slowly. Good luck me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">I am a big believe in the idea that one’s happiness is the difference between one’s expectations and one’s reality. I’ve also previously hypothesized that one of the biggest causes of my historical unhappiness is my unrealisticly high expectations of myself and my life, and that I might be happier were I able to lower those expectations. That might sound easy, but in practice it has turned out to be substantially harder than I had expected.</summary></entry></feed>