<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-20T12:12:57+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Book Reviews: Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/20/book-reviews-notes-from-underground-by-fyodor-dostoevsky" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Reviews&amp;#58; Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky" /><published>2019-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/20/book-reviews-notes-from-underground-by-fyodor-dostoevsky</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/20/book-reviews-notes-from-underground-by-fyodor-dostoevsky">&lt;p&gt;
  I've been wanting to start reading Russian literature for many years, largely
  for pretentious and narcissistic reasons. Dostoevsky seemed like a good place
  to start, in part because I enjoyed Richard Ayoade's film adaption of 'The Double'
  and because he is often cited by &lt;a href=&quot;https://jordanbpeterson.com/books/book-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  Jordan Peterson&lt;/a&gt; as a significant influence on his thinking.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This book made me feel... dumb. Which was good, and somewhat refreshing (apologies
  for the arrogance). To really understand what Dostoevsky was getting at, I think
  would require especially diligent reading, and perhaps I will read through it
  again at some point in the future, to see if I can extract anything more from it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I won't try to analyse the book in any great detail because I would surely only
  embarrass myself. I will say the book is certainly worth reading for the concepts
  contained within - Dostoevsky's ideas about society and human nature are thought
  provoking at the very least. Delivering his commentary on political and
  existential philosophy through the form of satire serves the author well, making
  the dense topics more relatable, and also allowing the reader to find his
  own way along the trail of breadcrumbs that Dostoevsky has carefully laid out.
  That way, I felt like I had actually come upon some of the notions about the
  nature of humanity of my own accord and volition, even though that clearly
  wasn't the case.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One of the images that struck me most was that of society and the anthill, and
  the protagonist's detestation of London's Crystal Palace. He postulates that
  humans are like ants, constantly working and improving our anthills. The ants
  aren't entirely sure why they do so, they are compelled by some unknown force
  to toil away. They don't enjoy it, they just do it. Were they ever to finish
  the anthill, such that it was perfect, the ants would surely feel directionless
  and simply lay around in the sun until they eventually died, more of boredom
  than any other cause. This is why the Crystal Palace is viewed as an abomination,
  because it represents the pinnacle of human achievements. It is perfect, nothing
  can surpass it - it is a finished anthill. And what if, after its completion,
  humanity no longer has anything to strive for? If no further improvements can
  be made to our race, what is there to do? There is nothing, the author postulates,
  but to wait for our death.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This concept hit close to home. I spend much of my life searching for enlightenment,
  in one way or another, under the assumption that enlightment will be blissful.
  I will feel pure peace and serenity. But what if that is not the case? What if
  I feel empty, lost, trapped in a void of my own design. Striving for something
  does seem important to me, both for myself and for people in general. Realistically,
  I will never attain enlightenment anyway, so it's something of a moot point,
  but Dostoevsky points out the irony in this - as humans, we are bound by our
  nature to constantly work towards something that we don't want. In fact it would
  be hell for us. We spend our lives desperately trying to construct our own Gehenna,
  and by some truly unimaginable stroke of luck, we are unable to ever finish our
  infernal project.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  9/10, read the damn book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Books read this year: 2/52
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Next book: The Double by Fyodor Dostoevsky
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">I've been wanting to start reading Russian literature for many years, largely for pretentious and narcissistic reasons. Dostoevsky seemed like a good place to start, in part because I enjoyed Richard Ayoade's film adaption of 'The Double' and because he is often cited by Jordan Peterson as a significant influence on his thinking. This book made me feel... dumb. Which was good, and somewhat refreshing (apologies for the arrogance). To really understand what Dostoevsky was getting at, I think would require especially diligent reading, and perhaps I will read through it again at some point in the future, to see if I can extract anything more from it. I won't try to analyse the book in any great detail because I would surely only embarrass myself. I will say the book is certainly worth reading for the concepts contained within - Dostoevsky's ideas about society and human nature are thought provoking at the very least. Delivering his commentary on political and existential philosophy through the form of satire serves the author well, making the dense topics more relatable, and also allowing the reader to find his own way along the trail of breadcrumbs that Dostoevsky has carefully laid out. That way, I felt like I had actually come upon some of the notions about the nature of humanity of my own accord and volition, even though that clearly wasn't the case. One of the images that struck me most was that of society and the anthill, and the protagonist's detestation of London's Crystal Palace. He postulates that humans are like ants, constantly working and improving our anthills. The ants aren't entirely sure why they do so, they are compelled by some unknown force to toil away. They don't enjoy it, they just do it. Were they ever to finish the anthill, such that it was perfect, the ants would surely feel directionless and simply lay around in the sun until they eventually died, more of boredom than any other cause. This is why the Crystal Palace is viewed as an abomination, because it represents the pinnacle of human achievements. It is perfect, nothing can surpass it - it is a finished anthill. And what if, after its completion, humanity no longer has anything to strive for? If no further improvements can be made to our race, what is there to do? There is nothing, the author postulates, but to wait for our death. This concept hit close to home. I spend much of my life searching for enlightenment, in one way or another, under the assumption that enlightment will be blissful. I will feel pure peace and serenity. But what if that is not the case? What if I feel empty, lost, trapped in a void of my own design. Striving for something does seem important to me, both for myself and for people in general. Realistically, I will never attain enlightenment anyway, so it's something of a moot point, but Dostoevsky points out the irony in this - as humans, we are bound by our nature to constantly work towards something that we don't want. In fact it would be hell for us. We spend our lives desperately trying to construct our own Gehenna, and by some truly unimaginable stroke of luck, we are unable to ever finish our infernal project. 9/10, read the damn book. Books read this year: 2/52 Next book: The Double by Fyodor Dostoevsky</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trial and Error</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/19/trial-and-error" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trial and Error" /><published>2019-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/19/trial-and-error</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/19/trial-and-error">&lt;p&gt;
  Intuitively, one might feel that the biggest problem with generalised or social
  anxiety is that it prevents an individual from succeeding - however I would
  disagree. The most prevalent issue faced by anxiety sufferers, and
  indeed myself, is a lack of &lt;i&gt;failure.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Ok, I admit that my point here isn't exactly revolutionary, but sometimes it takes me a
  while to arrive at even an obvious conclusion, so humour me. Having struggled
  a lot with anxiety, particularly in the time since I left university, my coping
  strategy has been largely to avoid situations in which I might experience said
  anxiety. This is naturally only to a certain extent - I still leave the house
  every day, despite having anxiety about doing so. But, generally speaking, I
  cut out as many non-critical interactions that I have anxiety about - in terms
  of fight or flight, I have fled. Flew. Flown. I don't know.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And now, I have suffered for it. I feel like my social skills are underdeveloped,
  my relationships aren't where I want them to be. In order to change those things,
  I will have to try, and failure is an inevitable part of trying. It's going to
  hurt - but I am hoping it won't hurt quite as bad as I think. I really need to
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/14/feel-the-pain-be-the-cowboy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  feel the pain&lt;/a&gt; - in fact my goal for the next couple of months is to feel as
  much of it as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  To that end, tomorrow in particular there is quite a lot of potential for discomfort. Wish me luck.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Intuitively, one might feel that the biggest problem with generalised or social anxiety is that it prevents an individual from succeeding - however I would disagree. The most prevalent issue faced by anxiety sufferers, and indeed myself, is a lack of failure. Ok, I admit that my point here isn't exactly revolutionary, but sometimes it takes me a while to arrive at even an obvious conclusion, so humour me. Having struggled a lot with anxiety, particularly in the time since I left university, my coping strategy has been largely to avoid situations in which I might experience said anxiety. This is naturally only to a certain extent - I still leave the house every day, despite having anxiety about doing so. But, generally speaking, I cut out as many non-critical interactions that I have anxiety about - in terms of fight or flight, I have fled. Flew. Flown. I don't know. And now, I have suffered for it. I feel like my social skills are underdeveloped, my relationships aren't where I want them to be. In order to change those things, I will have to try, and failure is an inevitable part of trying. It's going to hurt - but I am hoping it won't hurt quite as bad as I think. I really need to feel the pain - in fact my goal for the next couple of months is to feel as much of it as possible. To that end, tomorrow in particular there is quite a lot of potential for discomfort. Wish me luck.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sex Education Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/18/sex-education-review" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sex Education Review" /><published>2019-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/18/sex-education-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/18/sex-education-review">&lt;p&gt;
  I just got done watching the new Netflix show 'Sex Education', so here is
  what I thought of it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The first two episodes paint the series as a fun, quirky coming-of-age story
  about the whacky hijinks of two teenagers who set up a 'sex clinic' to help
  their peers as they collectively endure puberty. One is the stereotypical
  rebellious genius, a feminine firebrand who is wholly apathetic to the thoughts 
  and opinions of others. The other is the awkward, nerdy-but-nice guy who
  stares at the floor when girls talk to him and hands in all his homework on time
  but only gets slightly above average grades. He's the son of a sex therapist
  and regurgitates his mother's advice to her clients in place of her own,
  while his counterpart handles client acquisition and cash flow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Initially the stakes are low, and I assumed I was in for a lighthearted, feel-good
  adventure with these two misfits and their assorted stereotypical friends. As
  it turns out, the writers had cunningly lulled me into a false sense of
  emotional security - Sex Education has claws.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The show deals with a variety of social issues and makes its point in several
  raw, visceral scenes. Some of the plot points were very close to home for me,
  and I suspect that everyone who watches it will have been personally affected
  by one of the subjects raised. I cried at a couple of the episodes. The plot
  is obviously shaped in such a way as to serve the writers' agenda, which
  usually I would be highly critical of, but in this instance I will forgive it
  because of how well executed it was, and how much emotion it succeeded in
  eliciting from me, despite potentially being contrived.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The show illustrates a reality of life that I found compelling. Sometimes,
  human existence can be difficult and painful for everyone, for kids, for parents,
  for women, for members of the LGBTQ community and PoC, and even for straight
  white cis-gendered men like me. But conversely, there are always moments of pure
  beauty and love to be found - often close at hand, if you look hard enough. It
  doesn't sugarcoat anything, nor shy away from showing the brutality of life
  (or male genitalia - I would definitely like to commend the show for having parity
  in this regard). Unlike a lot of other series, Sex Education evokes the whole
  spectrum of emotions - sometimes it'll put you on cloud 9, and sometimes it'll
  leave you a sobbing mess. I think that's what's so great about the show - that
  is exactly what real life is like.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  8.5/10, recommended assuming you have a box of tissues to hand.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="TV" /><summary type="html">I just got done watching the new Netflix show 'Sex Education', so here is what I thought of it. The first two episodes paint the series as a fun, quirky coming-of-age story about the whacky hijinks of two teenagers who set up a 'sex clinic' to help their peers as they collectively endure puberty. One is the stereotypical rebellious genius, a feminine firebrand who is wholly apathetic to the thoughts and opinions of others. The other is the awkward, nerdy-but-nice guy who stares at the floor when girls talk to him and hands in all his homework on time but only gets slightly above average grades. He's the son of a sex therapist and regurgitates his mother's advice to her clients in place of her own, while his counterpart handles client acquisition and cash flow. Initially the stakes are low, and I assumed I was in for a lighthearted, feel-good adventure with these two misfits and their assorted stereotypical friends. As it turns out, the writers had cunningly lulled me into a false sense of emotional security - Sex Education has claws. The show deals with a variety of social issues and makes its point in several raw, visceral scenes. Some of the plot points were very close to home for me, and I suspect that everyone who watches it will have been personally affected by one of the subjects raised. I cried at a couple of the episodes. The plot is obviously shaped in such a way as to serve the writers' agenda, which usually I would be highly critical of, but in this instance I will forgive it because of how well executed it was, and how much emotion it succeeded in eliciting from me, despite potentially being contrived. The show illustrates a reality of life that I found compelling. Sometimes, human existence can be difficult and painful for everyone, for kids, for parents, for women, for members of the LGBTQ community and PoC, and even for straight white cis-gendered men like me. But conversely, there are always moments of pure beauty and love to be found - often close at hand, if you look hard enough. It doesn't sugarcoat anything, nor shy away from showing the brutality of life (or male genitalia - I would definitely like to commend the show for having parity in this regard). Unlike a lot of other series, Sex Education evokes the whole spectrum of emotions - sometimes it'll put you on cloud 9, and sometimes it'll leave you a sobbing mess. I think that's what's so great about the show - that is exactly what real life is like. 8.5/10, recommended assuming you have a box of tissues to hand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High Standards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/17/high-standards" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High Standards" /><published>2019-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/17/high-standards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/17/high-standards">&lt;p&gt;
  Ever since I was a kid, I've wanted to write a book. I remember when I was in
  primary school, resolving to pen a story 100 pages long, which at the time
  seemed like a feat that would bring me untold recognition and praise upon its
  completion. Naturally I didn't even come close to finishing it - my lack of
  execution obviously set in early in my life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  About 15 months ago I first considered writing short stories, as a way to
  express myself and the struggles I was dealing with in a less self-absorbed
  way than chronicling my own experiences factually. Obviously I didn't
  ever get round to doing that either, because I am a perennially weak-willed,
  lazy individual.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Recently I read a blog post (that I have not been able to rediscover
  in order to link or give credit to, sadly) that pointed out that if you wrote 200
  words a day for a mere 125 days, you would be left with 25,000 words of writing,
  and many would consider that to be approximately one book's-worth. Well, I thought
  to myself, I write approximate 200 words a day, and I have done for the past
  125 days or thereabouts. The issues were that firstly those writings
  were solely non-fictional, and I would have no interest in writing anything
  other than fiction; secondly that they are separate pieces and these incongruent
  and incoherent when viewed together; and thirdly that they are, by and large,
  perfectly fucking awful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I doubt there is much I will be able to do about the last one, but with some
  kind of concerted effort, I could surely remedy the former two problems. I
  clearly have it in me to write consistently enough to produce enough words
  to fill a book. Furthermore, when I was creating my &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reading list
  for this year,&lt;/a&gt; I tried to fill it with authors who I thought would inspire me,
  and whose influence I might be able to draw upon if and when I tried my own
  hand at writing fiction.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Talking to an old school friend this week, who is infinitely better read than I,
  I realised another hurdle I would have to jump over. If I tried to write a book,
  I would want it to be of an insanely high standard. I'd want to write like
  Proust or Dostoevsky. I'd want my text to be as deep and nuanced as Infinite Jest.
  I might write 200 words in a day, but I'd spend the next fortnight redrafting them.
  I would reject a million good ideas before finally settling on one, not because
  I was satisfied with it, but because I was frustrated at my own lack of progress.
  My vision of the plot would inevitably change often through the processes of
  planning, drafting and then editing. I would invariably find myself ensnared
  betwixt a desire to both emulate my literary heroes and also to produce
  something unique and original.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Despite all this, perhaps I'll write a book one day. It might be fun, in a
  masochistic kinda way.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">Ever since I was a kid, I've wanted to write a book. I remember when I was in primary school, resolving to pen a story 100 pages long, which at the time seemed like a feat that would bring me untold recognition and praise upon its completion. Naturally I didn't even come close to finishing it - my lack of execution obviously set in early in my life. About 15 months ago I first considered writing short stories, as a way to express myself and the struggles I was dealing with in a less self-absorbed way than chronicling my own experiences factually. Obviously I didn't ever get round to doing that either, because I am a perennially weak-willed, lazy individual. Recently I read a blog post (that I have not been able to rediscover in order to link or give credit to, sadly) that pointed out that if you wrote 200 words a day for a mere 125 days, you would be left with 25,000 words of writing, and many would consider that to be approximately one book's-worth. Well, I thought to myself, I write approximate 200 words a day, and I have done for the past 125 days or thereabouts. The issues were that firstly those writings were solely non-fictional, and I would have no interest in writing anything other than fiction; secondly that they are separate pieces and these incongruent and incoherent when viewed together; and thirdly that they are, by and large, perfectly fucking awful. I doubt there is much I will be able to do about the last one, but with some kind of concerted effort, I could surely remedy the former two problems. I clearly have it in me to write consistently enough to produce enough words to fill a book. Furthermore, when I was creating my reading list for this year, I tried to fill it with authors who I thought would inspire me, and whose influence I might be able to draw upon if and when I tried my own hand at writing fiction. Talking to an old school friend this week, who is infinitely better read than I, I realised another hurdle I would have to jump over. If I tried to write a book, I would want it to be of an insanely high standard. I'd want to write like Proust or Dostoevsky. I'd want my text to be as deep and nuanced as Infinite Jest. I might write 200 words in a day, but I'd spend the next fortnight redrafting them. I would reject a million good ideas before finally settling on one, not because I was satisfied with it, but because I was frustrated at my own lack of progress. My vision of the plot would inevitably change often through the processes of planning, drafting and then editing. I would invariably find myself ensnared betwixt a desire to both emulate my literary heroes and also to produce something unique and original. Despite all this, perhaps I'll write a book one day. It might be fun, in a masochistic kinda way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mom Jeans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/16/mom-jeans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mom Jeans" /><published>2019-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/16/mom-jeans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/16/mom-jeans">&lt;p&gt;
  Last night I got to see Just Friends and Mom Jeans life, and both were incredible.
  Watching the 10 piece ska-punk collective Just Friends all going nuts on stage
  in a tiny, sold-out venue that was essentially a pub was a heart-warming experience.
  Mom Jeans had tech problems and played without monitors and were phenomenal regardless.
  Gabe told truly awful jokes. Bart tuned Gabe's bass. Eric almost made me cry.
  Austin looked cute in the back, thereby fulfilling the entirety of his responsibilities
  as a drummer. They were perfect. Throughout their set, all I could think about
  was how purely, genuinely happy I was.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Tonight I am exhausted and feel kinda sad, and tomorrow I have to go to work.
  But I know that in the future, I will have the same feeling as I had last night
  once more.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Last night I got to see Just Friends and Mom Jeans life, and both were incredible. Watching the 10 piece ska-punk collective Just Friends all going nuts on stage in a tiny, sold-out venue that was essentially a pub was a heart-warming experience. Mom Jeans had tech problems and played without monitors and were phenomenal regardless. Gabe told truly awful jokes. Bart tuned Gabe's bass. Eric almost made me cry. Austin looked cute in the back, thereby fulfilling the entirety of his responsibilities as a drummer. They were perfect. Throughout their set, all I could think about was how purely, genuinely happy I was. Tonight I am exhausted and feel kinda sad, and tomorrow I have to go to work. But I know that in the future, I will have the same feeling as I had last night once more.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5am</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/15/5am" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5am" /><published>2019-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/15/5am</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/15/5am">&lt;p&gt;
  I am writing this at 5:15am, and have to leave in 30 minutes to catch a flight,
  so it is going to be quick.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Today I get to go floating, see one of my favourite bands live and stay with
  one of my oldest friends. It has the potential to be an amazing day, and I
  am very excited. Without getting my hopes up too much, I think I'm going to be
  really happy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm sure I'll tell you all about it tomorrow.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I am writing this at 5:15am, and have to leave in 30 minutes to catch a flight, so it is going to be quick. Today I get to go floating, see one of my favourite bands live and stay with one of my oldest friends. It has the potential to be an amazing day, and I am very excited. Without getting my hopes up too much, I think I'm going to be really happy. I'm sure I'll tell you all about it tomorrow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">People Are My Religion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/14/people-are-my-religion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People Are My Religion" /><published>2019-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/14/people-are-my-religion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/14/people-are-my-religion">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-u05Yc5zurI&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  People are my religion.&lt;/a&gt; Well, they are now at least. Having spent my entire
  adult life largely being a misanthrope, perpetually bitter at numerous perceived
  sleights, I am finally making an effort to get over myself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My loudly professed distate for humanity is a byproduct of my
  own insecurities is surely obvious to everyone but me. Perhaps it is even my
  Soul Toupee (or, one of them). It may have once served some purpose to insulate
  my fragile ego from the barbs of reality, but now it is obselete - and I would
  like to consign it to history, an artifact of my personality that is no more
  than a milestone for growth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In the past month or so, I have come to realise how pivotal other people are
  in my own happiness. Maintaining healthy, vulnerable relationships with the people
  that I care about is going to give me a feeling of connectedness that will stave
  off the icy grip of depression. Striving to be able to interact openly and easily with
  strangers and acquaintances is going to be integral to vanquishing my anxieties.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Inspired by reading &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Models,&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8fkTdr3snLQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  Elon Musk high as a kite,&lt;/a&gt; by my friend Ongun and by a great many other things,
  the hermetic life is not for me. As much as I would love to pretend that I am better
  than everyone around me, that I don't need them, today I begin to make a conscious
  effort to change that, to see the good in everyone, as corny as that might sound.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm not going to flip and become a hippy or a Buddhist monk overnight - I'm sure
  I will still get angry and frustrated by people, and lash out sometimes. But
  the important thing is that I'm going to try to make a positive difference.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">People are my religion. Well, they are now at least. Having spent my entire adult life largely being a misanthrope, perpetually bitter at numerous perceived sleights, I am finally making an effort to get over myself. My loudly professed distate for humanity is a byproduct of my own insecurities is surely obvious to everyone but me. Perhaps it is even my Soul Toupee (or, one of them). It may have once served some purpose to insulate my fragile ego from the barbs of reality, but now it is obselete - and I would like to consign it to history, an artifact of my personality that is no more than a milestone for growth. In the past month or so, I have come to realise how pivotal other people are in my own happiness. Maintaining healthy, vulnerable relationships with the people that I care about is going to give me a feeling of connectedness that will stave off the icy grip of depression. Striving to be able to interact openly and easily with strangers and acquaintances is going to be integral to vanquishing my anxieties. Inspired by reading Models, by Elon Musk high as a kite, by my friend Ongun and by a great many other things, the hermetic life is not for me. As much as I would love to pretend that I am better than everyone around me, that I don't need them, today I begin to make a conscious effort to change that, to see the good in everyone, as corny as that might sound. I'm not going to flip and become a hippy or a Buddhist monk overnight - I'm sure I will still get angry and frustrated by people, and lash out sometimes. But the important thing is that I'm going to try to make a positive difference.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Reviews: Models by Mark Manson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Reviews&amp;#58; Models by Mark Manson" /><published>2019-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson">&lt;p&gt;
  Thirteen days into the year and I have already read more books in 2019 than
  I did in 2018. I'm not quite on track for &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  reading 52 books in a year,&lt;/a&gt; but it's a good start.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have actually already read Models, about 2.5 years ago, and I can confidently
  say it changed my life. It provided the slap in the face I needed to finally
  cut off someone incredibly toxic in my life, by providing a blueprint for what
  a healthy, mutually fulfilling relationship should look like.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  While ostensibly a book about dating, the premise of its advice could be boiled
  down to 'if you improve yourself as a person, it will have the convenient side
  effect that women will be more attracted to you'. This might seem obvious, but
  the point Manson makes is that many men, when lamenting their romantic misfortune,
  focus too much on irrelevant details, like when to text a girl, whether or not
  to be mean to her, whether or not to pay for dinner etc. If you want to be luckier
  in love, then Manson prescribes a diet of self improvement: work on your insecurities
  and your anxieties, take an interest in the world around you, be confident in
  your intentions and actions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Upon first read, I was fairly enamoured with 100% of the content in this book,
  however with a couple more years of wisdom and experience (and of self-improvement)
  there are some things I am not so sure about anymore. Written in 2011, at one
  point the author references writing in a 'post-feminist age', but that landscape
  has shifted significantly, so perhaps the book needs updating to include
  post-post-feminist thinking. The chapter about sex (as in, what to do when you're
  actually between the sheets) was in my opinion, unnecessarily graphic. Figuring
  out what to put where is half the fun, and learning to communicate with an intimate
  partner is something that I have no desire to learn about from a book - even if
  the author of said book has had sex with infinitely more women than I have.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With that being said, there are a lot of things I still love about Models.
  Its stated aim is to provide a model for modern masculinity (hence the title),
  and by and large I think it does a good job. It offers practical, no nonsense
  advice for overcoming one's anxieties and growing in confidence. All of the
  commentary on the psychology of romance and attraction is at least plausible,
  even if there are frequent mentions of wholly uncited research.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Naturally, it's a self help book, so the million dollar question is whether or
  not it helped me - and the answer is yes, I think it did. There's a lot I will
  take away from Models and apply to my day to day life. Even reading it made me feel more confident -
  its emphasis on honesty and genuine expression, rather than trying to say
  certain things or act a certain way, felt like it was giving me permission to
  be myself and worry less about what everyone else thinks. It wasn't as life-changing
  as my first read, which hopefully is a sign that I have matured as a person in
  the interim, but it was worth it nonetheless. A solid 7/10.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Books read this year: 1/52
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Next book: Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">Thirteen days into the year and I have already read more books in 2019 than I did in 2018. I'm not quite on track for reading 52 books in a year, but it's a good start. I have actually already read Models, about 2.5 years ago, and I can confidently say it changed my life. It provided the slap in the face I needed to finally cut off someone incredibly toxic in my life, by providing a blueprint for what a healthy, mutually fulfilling relationship should look like. While ostensibly a book about dating, the premise of its advice could be boiled down to 'if you improve yourself as a person, it will have the convenient side effect that women will be more attracted to you'. This might seem obvious, but the point Manson makes is that many men, when lamenting their romantic misfortune, focus too much on irrelevant details, like when to text a girl, whether or not to be mean to her, whether or not to pay for dinner etc. If you want to be luckier in love, then Manson prescribes a diet of self improvement: work on your insecurities and your anxieties, take an interest in the world around you, be confident in your intentions and actions. Upon first read, I was fairly enamoured with 100% of the content in this book, however with a couple more years of wisdom and experience (and of self-improvement) there are some things I am not so sure about anymore. Written in 2011, at one point the author references writing in a 'post-feminist age', but that landscape has shifted significantly, so perhaps the book needs updating to include post-post-feminist thinking. The chapter about sex (as in, what to do when you're actually between the sheets) was in my opinion, unnecessarily graphic. Figuring out what to put where is half the fun, and learning to communicate with an intimate partner is something that I have no desire to learn about from a book - even if the author of said book has had sex with infinitely more women than I have. With that being said, there are a lot of things I still love about Models. Its stated aim is to provide a model for modern masculinity (hence the title), and by and large I think it does a good job. It offers practical, no nonsense advice for overcoming one's anxieties and growing in confidence. All of the commentary on the psychology of romance and attraction is at least plausible, even if there are frequent mentions of wholly uncited research. Naturally, it's a self help book, so the million dollar question is whether or not it helped me - and the answer is yes, I think it did. There's a lot I will take away from Models and apply to my day to day life. Even reading it made me feel more confident - its emphasis on honesty and genuine expression, rather than trying to say certain things or act a certain way, felt like it was giving me permission to be myself and worry less about what everyone else thinks. It wasn't as life-changing as my first read, which hopefully is a sign that I have matured as a person in the interim, but it was worth it nonetheless. A solid 7/10. Books read this year: 1/52 Next book: Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In the Aeroplane Over The Sea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In the Aeroplane Over The Sea" /><published>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/5COXoP5kj2DWfCDg0vxi4F?si=nTRqRsXyRHyoLtd7D82aFw&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  In the Aeroplane Over the Sea&lt;/a&gt; was the second and last album by the mysterious
  and oddly-named Neutral Milk Hotel, released in 1998 to little commercial success
  initially. Over the years however, its popularity has grown massively, and the
  record is now a critics' favourite, appearing on numerous
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Aeroplane_Over_the_Sea#Accolades&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  'Top X' style lists.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  For all its influence and acclaim, this album is... weird. It has a wonderfully
  lo-fi quality to it, and some of the instrumentation is uncommon - for example
  the uilleann pipes, which I had to Google (they're Irish bagpipes). Then there's
  the lyrics, which are abstract and &lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Neutral-milk-hotel-communist-daughter-lyrics&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  sometimes sexual in a very confusing way.&lt;/a&gt; The most bizarre thing about the
  album is without doubt that it appears to chronicle frontman Jeff Mangum's fascination
  with Anne Frank, including the line:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
      I wished I could save her in some sort of time machine
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Which seems like a strange premise for an album, but Mangum was apparently greatly
  moved by Frank's story, and understandably so. He seems like a odd dude, and
  its an odd album.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But the critics are absolutely right - this is one of the best records ever made.
  It's beautiful and evocative, despite its bizarre nature. The fact that it is so
  rough around the edges lends a sense of authenticity to the music, allowing the
  listener to emotionally connect with it. It is 39 minutes of raw, unfiltered
  human expression, and that is what art should be, even if you don't agree or
  empathise with what the artist is expressing. This is a true masterpiece, one
  of the greatest albums ever made. Go listen to it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">In the Aeroplane Over the Sea was the second and last album by the mysterious and oddly-named Neutral Milk Hotel, released in 1998 to little commercial success initially. Over the years however, its popularity has grown massively, and the record is now a critics' favourite, appearing on numerous 'Top X' style lists. For all its influence and acclaim, this album is... weird. It has a wonderfully lo-fi quality to it, and some of the instrumentation is uncommon - for example the uilleann pipes, which I had to Google (they're Irish bagpipes). Then there's the lyrics, which are abstract and sometimes sexual in a very confusing way. The most bizarre thing about the album is without doubt that it appears to chronicle frontman Jeff Mangum's fascination with Anne Frank, including the line: I wished I could save her in some sort of time machine Which seems like a strange premise for an album, but Mangum was apparently greatly moved by Frank's story, and understandably so. He seems like a odd dude, and its an odd album. But the critics are absolutely right - this is one of the best records ever made. It's beautiful and evocative, despite its bizarre nature. The fact that it is so rough around the edges lends a sense of authenticity to the music, allowing the listener to emotionally connect with it. It is 39 minutes of raw, unfiltered human expression, and that is what art should be, even if you don't agree or empathise with what the artist is expressing. This is a true masterpiece, one of the greatest albums ever made. Go listen to it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yudkowsky Ambititon Scale</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yudkowsky Ambititon Scale" /><published>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale">&lt;p&gt;
  While trawling through various 'best of Hacker News' articles, I learned of
  the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4509934&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Yudkowsky Ambition Scale.&lt;/a&gt; It's naturally meant to be tongue-in-cheek, and
  I think it's pretty funny - now we're living in 2019 it seems hard to list Apple and Facebook
  as entirely separate tiers of ambition. The mention of seasteading also caused
  me to go down a wiki-rabbithole for a few hours during which I became enamoured
  with the idea, but in a science fiction kinda way rather than a this-has-practical-applications 
  kinda way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Ambition is something I value highly in people, and until reading the scale,
  I would've labelled myself ambitious (as well as arrogant) .Naturally, the scale
  pertains to start-ups, but I am not a start-up, I'm just a guy,
  trying to figure out how to become a better guy. It's commonly
  given advice to be more ambitious, and I can see why that is - if you aim high
  and fail, you will invariably have achieved more than if you aimed lower and
  failed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This advice is a double edged sword though - high ambitions are good, but high
  expectations can be damaging, especially in the context of 'being a better guy'.
  The easiest way to be happier is to lower your expectations. When considering
  ambition and expectation, it seems important to be consciously aware of this
  disconnect, and so with that in mind, should I be more ambitious? In terms
  of my career, my personal relationship, my romantic prospects, my mental health?
  Maybe I'll come up with a new scale. The Spicer Ambitionish Scale™, coming soon.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Entrepreneurism" /><summary type="html">While trawling through various 'best of Hacker News' articles, I learned of the Yudkowsky Ambition Scale. It's naturally meant to be tongue-in-cheek, and I think it's pretty funny - now we're living in 2019 it seems hard to list Apple and Facebook as entirely separate tiers of ambition. The mention of seasteading also caused me to go down a wiki-rabbithole for a few hours during which I became enamoured with the idea, but in a science fiction kinda way rather than a this-has-practical-applications kinda way. Ambition is something I value highly in people, and until reading the scale, I would've labelled myself ambitious (as well as arrogant) .Naturally, the scale pertains to start-ups, but I am not a start-up, I'm just a guy, trying to figure out how to become a better guy. It's commonly given advice to be more ambitious, and I can see why that is - if you aim high and fail, you will invariably have achieved more than if you aimed lower and failed. This advice is a double edged sword though - high ambitions are good, but high expectations can be damaging, especially in the context of 'being a better guy'. The easiest way to be happier is to lower your expectations. When considering ambition and expectation, it seems important to be consciously aware of this disconnect, and so with that in mind, should I be more ambitious? In terms of my career, my personal relationship, my romantic prospects, my mental health? Maybe I'll come up with a new scale. The Spicer Ambitionish Scale™, coming soon.</summary></entry></feed>