<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-05T17:59:10+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Build All The Things II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/05/build-all-the-things-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build All The Things II" /><published>2018-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/05/build-all-the-things-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/05/build-all-the-things-ii">&lt;p&gt;
  First small Python programme written! It is pretty easy to output just 'hello
  world', so I did it three different ways. I learned about:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Importing modules;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Tuples, lists and sets;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How to sort and remove duplicates from a list;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Using sys.stdout.write vs print().
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Personally I think this is a good start, especially for half an hour's work.
  Here's the code, check it works!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;
    &lt;code&gt;
      import sys

      print('hello world')

      characters = [ 'h', 'e', 'l', 'l', 'o', ' ', 'w', 'o', 'r', 'l', 'd']
      for x in characters:
          sys.stdout.write(x)

      sorted_characters = list(set(characters))
      sorted_characters.sort()
      print(&quot;&quot;)
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[3])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[2])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[4])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[4])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[5])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[0])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[7])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[5])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[6])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[4])
      sys.stdout.write(sorted_characters[1])
    &lt;/code&gt;
  &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Software Engineering" /><summary type="html">First small Python programme written! It is pretty easy to output just 'hello world', so I did it three different ways. I learned about: Importing modules; Tuples, lists and sets; How to sort and remove duplicates from a list; Using sys.stdout.write vs print(). Personally I think this is a good start, especially for half an hour's work. Here's the code, check it works! import sys</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build All The Things</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/04/build-all-the-things" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build All The Things" /><published>2018-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/04/build-all-the-things</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/04/build-all-the-things">&lt;p&gt;
  I want to learn Python. I am bored of putting it off and saying to myself that
  I will learn it at some unspecified point in the future. So, I want to learn Python
  now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are two problems with this. Firstly, my attention span and concentration
  are both awful at the moment. Watching video tutorials and learning anything from them
  is going to be nearly impossible. Secondly, I have no time. I used to say that
  as a kind of excuse, really I had plenty of time, I just chose to spend it playing
  video games (which I still think is a perfectly valid way of spending one's time,
  if you make the active choice to prioritise it over other things). Now, I really
  do have no time - my entire week is divided into sleeping, the gym, working,
  and enough self-care time to stop me losing my mind. There's virtually no wiggle
  room. So, again, even if I could make myself absorb videos - I don't have the time
  to sit and watch them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So... the solution I'm going to attempt to use to solve the problem is 'just in time
  learning'. I am going to try and build as many things as possible in Python, each
  one hopefully adding more complexity or exploring a new aspect of the language.
  Rather than learn any of it beforehand, I am going to try to learn exactly
  as much as I need to solve each problem as it arises, meaning I get to immediately
  apply anything and everything I learn to a practical coding scenario. Naturally
  I will have to try to reduce every problem down to its smallest possible constituent
  parts, a skill that will have a meaningful crossover to other languages.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Honestly, this might be a terrible way to learn a language, it's something
  that I don't feel gets advocated for very much. But maybe it'll be fun, and
  maybe it'll be better than the traditional way. Tomorrow I'll post my &lt;code&gt;hello_world&lt;/code&gt;
  programme.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><category term="Software Engineering" /><summary type="html">I want to learn Python. I am bored of putting it off and saying to myself that I will learn it at some unspecified point in the future. So, I want to learn Python now. There are two problems with this. Firstly, my attention span and concentration are both awful at the moment. Watching video tutorials and learning anything from them is going to be nearly impossible. Secondly, I have no time. I used to say that as a kind of excuse, really I had plenty of time, I just chose to spend it playing video games (which I still think is a perfectly valid way of spending one's time, if you make the active choice to prioritise it over other things). Now, I really do have no time - my entire week is divided into sleeping, the gym, working, and enough self-care time to stop me losing my mind. There's virtually no wiggle room. So, again, even if I could make myself absorb videos - I don't have the time to sit and watch them. So... the solution I'm going to attempt to use to solve the problem is 'just in time learning'. I am going to try and build as many things as possible in Python, each one hopefully adding more complexity or exploring a new aspect of the language. Rather than learn any of it beforehand, I am going to try to learn exactly as much as I need to solve each problem as it arises, meaning I get to immediately apply anything and everything I learn to a practical coding scenario. Naturally I will have to try to reduce every problem down to its smallest possible constituent parts, a skill that will have a meaningful crossover to other languages. Honestly, this might be a terrible way to learn a language, it's something that I don't feel gets advocated for very much. But maybe it'll be fun, and maybe it'll be better than the traditional way. Tomorrow I'll post my hello_world programme.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">David Goggins</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/03/david-goggins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="David Goggins" /><published>2018-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/03/david-goggins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/03/david-goggins">&lt;p&gt;
  This weekend I decided I should try and catch up on some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  JRE episodes,&lt;/a&gt; and I wound up watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/5tSTk1083VY&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  this one,&lt;/a&gt; with David Goggins.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  His story is obviously incredible - a complete 'nobody' who turned his life wholly
  around to become an accomplished ultramarathon runner, one of the military's elite,
  and the world record holder for most pull-ups in 24 hours. He claims he isn't
  a genetic freak, he is simply someone who worked incredibly hard and was able
  to mentally push himself far past his perceived limit - in fact he coined the now-famous
  '40% rule', the idea that you believe you're 'done' when you're actually at about
  40% of your maximum. He is certainly motivational, and anyone who watches the
  podcast will inevitably be inspired to go for a run immediately afterwards.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But... is there anything meaningful I can actually glean from this? If we assume
  our common goal is maximumising our own happiness (using that word in a fairly
  broad context, to include content, fulfillment, self-worth etc), what can I apply
  from his story to mine? I don't think becoming an ultra runner is going to provide
  a good payoff in terms of effort to reward for me. Everyone around him had no
  expectations of him, and he was determined to prove them wrong, however I feel
  like people around me have high expectations of me, and I am terrified of not
  meeting them. Would achieving or even surpassing those expectations be that
  satisfying? I don't want to dedicate my time to someone else's goals.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Should I throw myself into working, pushing through the mental anguish of burnout
  and stress the same way he pushed through the pain of broken bones and internal
  bleeding? If I ascend to becoming a god-tier programmer one day, on Linus Torvalds'
  speed dial, would I look back and be proud of what I had accomplished in the
  same way that he is? Knowing that I did it, purely to prove to myself that I could?
  I'm not sure. Would I sacrifice other things in my life for this, that could potentially
  make me happy? How am I meant to prioritise? Can I still live a noble, worthy life
  by pursuing balance?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  That's only really the start of the questions I have been asking myself in the wake
  of the podcast. Is his story nothing but inspiration porn? Is he perpetuating
  toxic masculinity? Because if so, then he is very convincing, and I am compelled
  to pursue mental and physical fortitude, to outdo my peers, to fight my demons
  alone and win.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I don't really know. I think if there is one thing I am going to take away from
  it, it's this: fuck my comfort zone. I need to leave it more often, and wander
  as far off into the horizon as I can.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">This weekend I decided I should try and catch up on some JRE episodes, and I wound up watching this one, with David Goggins. His story is obviously incredible - a complete 'nobody' who turned his life wholly around to become an accomplished ultramarathon runner, one of the military's elite, and the world record holder for most pull-ups in 24 hours. He claims he isn't a genetic freak, he is simply someone who worked incredibly hard and was able to mentally push himself far past his perceived limit - in fact he coined the now-famous '40% rule', the idea that you believe you're 'done' when you're actually at about 40% of your maximum. He is certainly motivational, and anyone who watches the podcast will inevitably be inspired to go for a run immediately afterwards. But... is there anything meaningful I can actually glean from this? If we assume our common goal is maximumising our own happiness (using that word in a fairly broad context, to include content, fulfillment, self-worth etc), what can I apply from his story to mine? I don't think becoming an ultra runner is going to provide a good payoff in terms of effort to reward for me. Everyone around him had no expectations of him, and he was determined to prove them wrong, however I feel like people around me have high expectations of me, and I am terrified of not meeting them. Would achieving or even surpassing those expectations be that satisfying? I don't want to dedicate my time to someone else's goals. Should I throw myself into working, pushing through the mental anguish of burnout and stress the same way he pushed through the pain of broken bones and internal bleeding? If I ascend to becoming a god-tier programmer one day, on Linus Torvalds' speed dial, would I look back and be proud of what I had accomplished in the same way that he is? Knowing that I did it, purely to prove to myself that I could? I'm not sure. Would I sacrifice other things in my life for this, that could potentially make me happy? How am I meant to prioritise? Can I still live a noble, worthy life by pursuing balance? That's only really the start of the questions I have been asking myself in the wake of the podcast. Is his story nothing but inspiration porn? Is he perpetuating toxic masculinity? Because if so, then he is very convincing, and I am compelled to pursue mental and physical fortitude, to outdo my peers, to fight my demons alone and win. I don't really know. I think if there is one thing I am going to take away from it, it's this: fuck my comfort zone. I need to leave it more often, and wander as far off into the horizon as I can.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Upgrade and Compromise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/02/upgrade-and-compromise" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Upgrade and Compromise" /><published>2018-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/02/upgrade-and-compromise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/02/upgrade-and-compromise">&lt;p&gt;
  As I'm sure you have noticed, today the site has an exciting new feature - colour!
  There is actually a slightly less obvious, but equally exciting, new feature that
  I have added today as well, which is a JavaScript file. I'd like to talk
  a bit about why I decided to add these two things to my site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Both new additions actually have a common objective, that of improving accessibility.
  In my opinion, accessibility is overlooked by a very large number of web devs,
  and there isn't really a good excuse for it. All that is required to make a site
  accessible is some education and a tiny amount of time, and if a site is built
  with accessibility in mind, the extra effort is negligible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The problem with my lovely CSS-only hamburger menus and accordions was that they
  were completely un-navigable with only a keyboard. Their current JavaScript-enhanced
  iterations aren't much better, but when I next have some time to work on the site,
  the improvements will allow full, and hopefully easy, keyboard navigation of
  the site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My monochrome design choices may have fit my minimalist &lt;span style=&quot;white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;【﻿ａｅｓｔｈｅｔｉｃ】&lt;/span&gt; but
  a lot of the greys had poor colour-contrast, and my link styles were confusing and
  inconsistent. Now, with only a primary and alternate colour,
  every link on the site should look the same &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they are suitably
  different from regular text.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There is an element of compromise here - any JavaScript added will slow the
  performance of my site (although I have only added 15 or so lines so far, so
  the degradation will be infinitesimal), and I can no longer say the site is a
  no-JS-zone. With regards to the colours, I am not entirely sold on the actual
  hues I picked, at least not yet. It was a pretty tough decision, I wanted to pick ones
  that had solid contrast and were complementary, and avoid blue because everything
  on the internet is blue... Perhaps they will grow on me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The next wave of upgrades for this site will be to make it compliant with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  WCAG 2.0 AA&lt;/a&gt; standard. I am hopefully most of the way there already, but I
  am quite excited for the additional challenge, and I think I will learn a lot
  on the way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have made these changes to the site because I believe the web should be for
  everyone, and developers have a responsibility to cater for anyone who wants
  or needs to use their site.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Web Development" /><summary type="html">As I'm sure you have noticed, today the site has an exciting new feature - colour! There is actually a slightly less obvious, but equally exciting, new feature that I have added today as well, which is a JavaScript file. I'd like to talk a bit about why I decided to add these two things to my site. Both new additions actually have a common objective, that of improving accessibility. In my opinion, accessibility is overlooked by a very large number of web devs, and there isn't really a good excuse for it. All that is required to make a site accessible is some education and a tiny amount of time, and if a site is built with accessibility in mind, the extra effort is negligible. The problem with my lovely CSS-only hamburger menus and accordions was that they were completely un-navigable with only a keyboard. Their current JavaScript-enhanced iterations aren't much better, but when I next have some time to work on the site, the improvements will allow full, and hopefully easy, keyboard navigation of the site. My monochrome design choices may have fit my minimalist 【﻿ａｅｓｔｈｅｔｉｃ】 but a lot of the greys had poor colour-contrast, and my link styles were confusing and inconsistent. Now, with only a primary and alternate colour, every link on the site should look the same and they are suitably different from regular text. There is an element of compromise here - any JavaScript added will slow the performance of my site (although I have only added 15 or so lines so far, so the degradation will be infinitesimal), and I can no longer say the site is a no-JS-zone. With regards to the colours, I am not entirely sold on the actual hues I picked, at least not yet. It was a pretty tough decision, I wanted to pick ones that had solid contrast and were complementary, and avoid blue because everything on the internet is blue... Perhaps they will grow on me. The next wave of upgrades for this site will be to make it compliant with the WCAG 2.0 AA standard. I am hopefully most of the way there already, but I am quite excited for the additional challenge, and I think I will learn a lot on the way. I have made these changes to the site because I believe the web should be for everyone, and developers have a responsibility to cater for anyone who wants or needs to use their site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Too Fast</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/01/too-fast" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Too Fast" /><published>2018-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/01/too-fast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/12/01/too-fast">&lt;p&gt;
  Today has gone by too fast... I had so much I wanted to do. And I haven't spent
  any time frivously I don't think, no games, no Youtube videos, just productivity, the gym
  and socialising out with a friend, something that seems important for my health.
  But I am exhausted (again) and feel like I haven't made a dent in my to-do list
  for the weekend. If only there were more hours in the day... Time to try again
  tomorrow.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today has gone by too fast... I had so much I wanted to do. And I haven't spent any time frivously I don't think, no games, no Youtube videos, just productivity, the gym and socialising out with a friend, something that seems important for my health. But I am exhausted (again) and feel like I haven't made a dent in my to-do list for the weekend. If only there were more hours in the day... Time to try again tomorrow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Obligations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/30/obligations" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Obligations" /><published>2018-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/30/obligations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/30/obligations">&lt;p&gt;
  On this week's episode of 'things my therapist says...', we have the word 'should'.
  If I start saying 'I should...' she always asks me: 'Why? Why should you?'.
  I can rarely muster an answer to convince myself, let alone her. She postulates
  that if I didn't feel such strong obligations on such flimsy bases, perhaps
  I might be happier.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think she has a very good point, but tonight I still feel a strong sense of
  obligation. It's Friday evening, and I have a long and tough week at work. I
  would like to relax and play video games, but I have multiple personal projects
  that I feel compelled to work on, frontend code I should write, APIs I should learn, blog
  posts I should compose.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  What if I never said 'should' again?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">On this week's episode of 'things my therapist says...', we have the word 'should'. If I start saying 'I should...' she always asks me: 'Why? Why should you?'. I can rarely muster an answer to convince myself, let alone her. She postulates that if I didn't feel such strong obligations on such flimsy bases, perhaps I might be happier. I think she has a very good point, but tonight I still feel a strong sense of obligation. It's Friday evening, and I have a long and tough week at work. I would like to relax and play video games, but I have multiple personal projects that I feel compelled to work on, frontend code I should write, APIs I should learn, blog posts I should compose. What if I never said 'should' again?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exhaustion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/29/exhaustion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exhaustion" /><published>2018-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/29/exhaustion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/29/exhaustion">&lt;p&gt;
  Yikes, I am so exhausted. Between the new (intense) gym programme, work being
  as busy as ever, a couple of side projects, trying to maintain a social
  life, decent sleep schedule AND not lose my mind... it's tough man.
  But the show must go on, so I'm off to the gym.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Yikes, I am so exhausted. Between the new (intense) gym programme, work being as busy as ever, a couple of side projects, trying to maintain a social life, decent sleep schedule AND not lose my mind... it's tough man. But the show must go on, so I'm off to the gym.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flirting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/28/flirting" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flirting" /><published>2018-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/28/flirting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/28/flirting">&lt;p&gt;
  Flirting is hard, especially when your anxiety-to-social-skills ratio is as
  off-kilter as mine. It's not really something I partake in very much, as I
  don't have a clue how you're meant to do it, which means that when I do,
  I am... &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/25/everyone-is-totally-winging-it&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  totally winging it, again.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It is a lot of fun though. Especially when it might actually lead somewhere.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Flirting is hard, especially when your anxiety-to-social-skills ratio is as off-kilter as mine. It's not really something I partake in very much, as I don't have a clue how you're meant to do it, which means that when I do, I am... totally winging it, again. It is a lot of fun though. Especially when it might actually lead somewhere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intelligent New Programme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/27/intelligent-new-programme" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intelligent New Programme" /><published>2018-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/27/intelligent-new-programme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/27/intelligent-new-programme">&lt;p&gt;
  This week I have finally started a proper powerlifting programme, rather than
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/25/everyone-is-totally-winging-it&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;totally winging it&lt;/a&gt; when I work out.
  It is a little different to your average programme though, it is in fact the
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jtsstrength.com/juggernaut-ai-coaching/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Juggernaut 'AI' Coaching&lt;/a&gt; programme. I put 'AI' in well-deserved quotes, because
  as far as I can tell, the only intelligence involved in its creation is purely organic,
  and the rest is done by a (presumably complicated) spreadsheet. If there is any
  truth in the meme that machine learning is just a massive tree of &lt;code&gt;if{}&lt;/code&gt;
  statements... this really &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a massive tree of &lt;code&gt;if{}&lt;/code&gt; statements.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With that being said, it is supposed to be a good compromise between a cookie cutter
  programme and one-on-one coaching in terms of customisation and price. I am very
  impressed with the number of factors it takes into account and how well it seems
  to handle each input. It seems to be a very good price for what it is ($27/month),
  in my opinion at least.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am very excited to get back into training 'properly' and hopefully start seeing
  some meaningful progress. I am a little scared though - there is a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt;
  more volume in my upcoming weeks then I have been doing in the past few months!
  There's gonna be a lot of sore mornings this winter.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Diet and Fitness" /><summary type="html">This week I have finally started a proper powerlifting programme, rather than totally winging it when I work out. It is a little different to your average programme though, it is in fact the Juggernaut 'AI' Coaching programme. I put 'AI' in well-deserved quotes, because as far as I can tell, the only intelligence involved in its creation is purely organic, and the rest is done by a (presumably complicated) spreadsheet. If there is any truth in the meme that machine learning is just a massive tree of if{} statements... this really is a massive tree of if{} statements. With that being said, it is supposed to be a good compromise between a cookie cutter programme and one-on-one coaching in terms of customisation and price. I am very impressed with the number of factors it takes into account and how well it seems to handle each input. It seems to be a very good price for what it is ($27/month), in my opinion at least. I am very excited to get back into training 'properly' and hopefully start seeing some meaningful progress. I am a little scared though - there is a lot more volume in my upcoming weeks then I have been doing in the past few months! There's gonna be a lot of sore mornings this winter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Joy as an act of resistance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/26/joy-as-an-act-of-resistance" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joy as an act of resistance" /><published>2018-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/26/joy-as-an-act-of-resistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/26/joy-as-an-act-of-resistance">&lt;p&gt;
  Twice this year, I have listened to an album for the first time, and the
  message it contained was exactly what I needed to hear in the moment.
  The first was Graduating Life's nearly-eponymous 'Grad Life', a semi-underground
  emo-punk album filled with wall to wall bangers. The second was IDLES'
  'Joy as an Act of Resistance', the British punk powerhouse's followup
  to 2017 breakout success 'Brutalism'.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  After seeing it crop up a couple of times in some early 'album of the year'
  lists I finally decided to give it a listen, despite having been fairly
  dismissive of the recent British punk resurgence in favour of their moodier,
  more introspective American counterparts. Even though the band rejecting the 'punk'
  label, I am firmly slapping it on them - the album is a proper punk album,
  with the righteous anger of the movement's founders in the 70s, but updated
  for the 2018 British public dealing with Brexit, racism and a society rife
  with division.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The song 'Never Fight a Man with a Perm' features one of my favourite lyrics possibly
  ever:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Me, oh me, oh my, Roy&lt;br /&gt;
    You look like a walking thyroid&lt;br /&gt;
    You're not a man, you're a gland&lt;br /&gt;
    You're one big neck with sausage hands
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I can't really describe how good it is. It made me feel a way I haven't felt
  in a long time. Angry - but determined to do something about. Not content
  to do nothing. Spurred to act, to facilitate the changes that I want to see, rather
  than merely whine about them on a blog that nobody reads. Go listen to it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Twice this year, I have listened to an album for the first time, and the message it contained was exactly what I needed to hear in the moment. The first was Graduating Life's nearly-eponymous 'Grad Life', a semi-underground emo-punk album filled with wall to wall bangers. The second was IDLES' 'Joy as an Act of Resistance', the British punk powerhouse's followup to 2017 breakout success 'Brutalism'. After seeing it crop up a couple of times in some early 'album of the year' lists I finally decided to give it a listen, despite having been fairly dismissive of the recent British punk resurgence in favour of their moodier, more introspective American counterparts. Even though the band rejecting the 'punk' label, I am firmly slapping it on them - the album is a proper punk album, with the righteous anger of the movement's founders in the 70s, but updated for the 2018 British public dealing with Brexit, racism and a society rife with division. The song 'Never Fight a Man with a Perm' features one of my favourite lyrics possibly ever: Me, oh me, oh my, Roy You look like a walking thyroid You're not a man, you're a gland You're one big neck with sausage hands I can't really describe how good it is. It made me feel a way I haven't felt in a long time. Angry - but determined to do something about. Not content to do nothing. Spurred to act, to facilitate the changes that I want to see, rather than merely whine about them on a blog that nobody reads. Go listen to it.</summary></entry></feed>