<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-27T19:07:18+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Intelligent New Programme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/27/intelligent-new-programme" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intelligent New Programme" /><published>2018-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/27/intelligent-new-programme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/27/intelligent-new-programme">&lt;p&gt;
  This week I have finally started a proper powerlifting programme, rather than
  &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/11/25/everyone-is-totally-winging-it&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;totally winging it&lt;/a&gt; when I work out.
  It is a little different to your average programme though, it is in fact the
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jtsstrength.com/juggernaut-ai-coaching/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Juggernaut 'AI' Coaching&lt;/a&gt; programme. I put 'AI' in well-deserved quotes, because
  as far as I can tell, the only intelligence involved in its creation is purely organic,
  and the rest is done by a (presumably complicated) spreadsheet. If there is any
  truth in the meme that machine learning is just a massive tree of &lt;code&gt;if{}&lt;/code&gt;
  statements... this really &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a massive tree of &lt;code&gt;if{}&lt;/code&gt; statements.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With that being said, it is supposed to be a good compromise between a cookie cutter
  programme and one-on-one coaching in terms of customisation and price. I am very
  impressed with the number of factors it takes into account and how well it seems
  to handle each input. It seems to be a very good price for what it is ($27/month),
  in my opinion at least.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am very excited to get back into training 'properly' and hopefully start seeing
  some meaningful progress. I am a little scared though - there is a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt;
  more volume in my upcoming weeks then I have been doing in the past few months!
  There's gonna be a lot of sore mornings this winter.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Diet and Fitness" /><summary type="html">This week I have finally started a proper powerlifting programme, rather than totally winging it when I work out. It is a little different to your average programme though, it is in fact the Juggernaut 'AI' Coaching programme. I put 'AI' in well-deserved quotes, because as far as I can tell, the only intelligence involved in its creation is purely organic, and the rest is done by a (presumably complicated) spreadsheet. If there is any truth in the meme that machine learning is just a massive tree of if{} statements... this really is a massive tree of if{} statements. With that being said, it is supposed to be a good compromise between a cookie cutter programme and one-on-one coaching in terms of customisation and price. I am very impressed with the number of factors it takes into account and how well it seems to handle each input. It seems to be a very good price for what it is ($27/month), in my opinion at least. I am very excited to get back into training 'properly' and hopefully start seeing some meaningful progress. I am a little scared though - there is a lot more volume in my upcoming weeks then I have been doing in the past few months! There's gonna be a lot of sore mornings this winter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Joy as an act of resistance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/26/joy-as-an-act-of-resistance" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joy as an act of resistance" /><published>2018-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/26/joy-as-an-act-of-resistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/26/joy-as-an-act-of-resistance">&lt;p&gt;
  Twice this year, I have listened to an album for the first time, and the
  message it contained was exactly what I needed to hear in the moment.
  The first was Graduating Life's nearly-eponymous 'Grad Life', a semi-underground
  emo-punk album filled with wall to wall bangers. The second was IDLES'
  'Joy as an Act of Resistance', the British punk powerhouse's followup
  to 2017 breakout success 'Brutalism'.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  After seeing it crop up a couple of times in some early 'album of the year'
  lists I finally decided to give it a listen, despite having been fairly
  dismissive of the recent British punk resurgence in favour of their moodier,
  more introspective American counterparts. Even though the band rejecting the 'punk'
  label, I am firmly slapping it on them - the album is a proper punk album,
  with the righteous anger of the movement's founders in the 70s, but updated
  for the 2018 British public dealing with Brexit, racism and a society rife
  with division.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The song 'Never Fight a Man with a Perm' features one of my favourite lyrics possibly
  ever:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Me, oh me, oh my, Roy&lt;br /&gt;
    You look like a walking thyroid&lt;br /&gt;
    You're not a man, you're a gland&lt;br /&gt;
    You're one big neck with sausage hands
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I can't really describe how good it is. It made me feel a way I haven't felt
  in a long time. Angry - but determined to do something about. Not content
  to do nothing. Spurred to act, to facilitate the changes that I want to see, rather
  than merely whine about them on a blog that nobody reads. Go listen to it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Twice this year, I have listened to an album for the first time, and the message it contained was exactly what I needed to hear in the moment. The first was Graduating Life's nearly-eponymous 'Grad Life', a semi-underground emo-punk album filled with wall to wall bangers. The second was IDLES' 'Joy as an Act of Resistance', the British punk powerhouse's followup to 2017 breakout success 'Brutalism'. After seeing it crop up a couple of times in some early 'album of the year' lists I finally decided to give it a listen, despite having been fairly dismissive of the recent British punk resurgence in favour of their moodier, more introspective American counterparts. Even though the band rejecting the 'punk' label, I am firmly slapping it on them - the album is a proper punk album, with the righteous anger of the movement's founders in the 70s, but updated for the 2018 British public dealing with Brexit, racism and a society rife with division. The song 'Never Fight a Man with a Perm' features one of my favourite lyrics possibly ever: Me, oh me, oh my, Roy You look like a walking thyroid You're not a man, you're a gland You're one big neck with sausage hands I can't really describe how good it is. It made me feel a way I haven't felt in a long time. Angry - but determined to do something about. Not content to do nothing. Spurred to act, to facilitate the changes that I want to see, rather than merely whine about them on a blog that nobody reads. Go listen to it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Everyone is totally winging it</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/25/everyone-is-totally-winging-it" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everyone is totally winging it" /><published>2018-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/25/everyone-is-totally-winging-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/25/everyone-is-totally-winging-it">&lt;p&gt;
  I absolutely do not have my shit together. Every day is a constant struggle to
  stave off the impending threat of an existential meltdown. I am perpetually
  fighting the feeling that I am not x, y or z enough, for practically every
  combination of those three letters. Somedays, it really gets me down.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Today, I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/oliver-burkeman-s-blog/2014/may/21/everyone-is-totally-just-winging-it&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; wonderful,
  uplifting (and short, in case you were getting worried) article from 2014 in The Guardian,
  entitled 'Everyone is totally just winging it, all the time'. It is an idea
  that on some level, of course I know, and I think everybody knows, we are just
  exceptionally bad at remembering it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Nobody knows if they are on the 'right' career path, if their current relationship
  is the One (with a capital 'O'), or if and when they might meet the One, if they
  should go back to school, drop out of school, perservere with school, start a school.
  Nobody is completely content with their relationships, with the way they look,
  with their job, or with their life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  BUT you fuckers try so hard to pretend like you &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; on top of all of that
  shit. And it makes everyone around you believe it, and feel like they should be
  cruising down life's highway too. But they're not, their engine's spluttering,
  there's smoke coming out of the hood and they're 90% sure that smell is burning.
  Please, &lt;i&gt;please&lt;/i&gt; can we collectively agree to drop this facade. Yes, I know
  it will be difficult, that it is deeply ingrained, and you are scared. But we've got
  to stop this, before we're all fucking miserable, despite posting smiling selfies
  with 'live laugh love' captions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Your move.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">I absolutely do not have my shit together. Every day is a constant struggle to stave off the impending threat of an existential meltdown. I am perpetually fighting the feeling that I am not x, y or z enough, for practically every combination of those three letters. Somedays, it really gets me down. Today, I read this wonderful, uplifting (and short, in case you were getting worried) article from 2014 in The Guardian, entitled 'Everyone is totally just winging it, all the time'. It is an idea that on some level, of course I know, and I think everybody knows, we are just exceptionally bad at remembering it. Nobody knows if they are on the 'right' career path, if their current relationship is the One (with a capital 'O'), or if and when they might meet the One, if they should go back to school, drop out of school, perservere with school, start a school. Nobody is completely content with their relationships, with the way they look, with their job, or with their life. BUT you fuckers try so hard to pretend like you are on top of all of that shit. And it makes everyone around you believe it, and feel like they should be cruising down life's highway too. But they're not, their engine's spluttering, there's smoke coming out of the hood and they're 90% sure that smell is burning. Please, please can we collectively agree to drop this facade. Yes, I know it will be difficult, that it is deeply ingrained, and you are scared. But we've got to stop this, before we're all fucking miserable, despite posting smiling selfies with 'live laugh love' captions. Your move.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whining</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/24/whining" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whining" /><published>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/24/whining</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/24/whining">&lt;p&gt;
  Somedays, you just need to have a good whine, and today is one of those days.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My wrists hurt, my gym session today felt lethargic and weak and I think I
  hurt my shoulder, driving to and from the gym was as frustrating and terrifying
  as ever, I feel like I've eaten too much the past two days, I have done virtually
  nothing productive today, I haven't made any real effort to talk to anyone today
  even though I wanted to do, I have felt super anxious all day, and I'm exhausted.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Time to go to bed and try again tomorrow.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Somedays, you just need to have a good whine, and today is one of those days. My wrists hurt, my gym session today felt lethargic and weak and I think I hurt my shoulder, driving to and from the gym was as frustrating and terrifying as ever, I feel like I've eaten too much the past two days, I have done virtually nothing productive today, I haven't made any real effort to talk to anyone today even though I wanted to do, I have felt super anxious all day, and I'm exhausted. Time to go to bed and try again tomorrow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I'm a convincing actor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/23/im-a-convincing-actor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I&amp;#39;m a convincing actor" /><published>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/23/im-a-convincing-actor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/23/im-a-convincing-actor">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I talked a little to one of my remote coworkers about my mental health
  issues. I've deliberately tried to hide it as much as possible at work, for
  fear it could affect my employability or my status within the company, but
  I trust the guy I talked to, and I don't think he'll say anything to anyone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's not especially enjoyable to have to hide it, and I am relatively open
  to talking about things these days, so it was something of a relief to tell
  him, and have one fewer person to have to hide it from. One of the things he
  said really tickled me though - he had no idea, and wouldn't have pegged me
  as someone with any kind of problem at all. It's somewhat reassuring - I have,
  for the most part, stopped putting much effort into covering up my 'secret' (which
  I talk about somewhat candid about on this blog). But it seems, I am a good actor,
  and am so immersed in my character of somebody-who's-fine, that most people
  can't tell the difference. I'm glad I still have the ability to fool people,
  if necessary.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Today I talked a little to one of my remote coworkers about my mental health issues. I've deliberately tried to hide it as much as possible at work, for fear it could affect my employability or my status within the company, but I trust the guy I talked to, and I don't think he'll say anything to anyone. It's not especially enjoyable to have to hide it, and I am relatively open to talking about things these days, so it was something of a relief to tell him, and have one fewer person to have to hide it from. One of the things he said really tickled me though - he had no idea, and wouldn't have pegged me as someone with any kind of problem at all. It's somewhat reassuring - I have, for the most part, stopped putting much effort into covering up my 'secret' (which I talk about somewhat candid about on this blog). But it seems, I am a good actor, and am so immersed in my character of somebody-who's-fine, that most people can't tell the difference. I'm glad I still have the ability to fool people, if necessary.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">World Chess Championships</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/22/world-chess-championships" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World Chess Championships" /><published>2018-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/22/world-chess-championships</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/22/world-chess-championships">&lt;p&gt;
  After the first 10 games of the Open World Chess Championships, it's 5 points all,
  with every game having been a draw. There has been a lot of criticism in public media
  for these games all being ended peacefully - which is a little odd, seeing as
  the world seems more interested in this match than usual. It's a little depressing
  that people still don't see beauty in the draws - they just want blood over the board.
  And, to be fair there has been blood - there have been thrills and spills, mistakes,
  opening novelties, and sacrifices. It just so happens that all of these have
  balanced out thusfar. I wish people would stop complaining and enjoy the game.
  There hasn't even been a single Berlin Defence yet - how can you say that's boring?!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  On a related note, today was game 4 of the final of the Women's World Chess Championship.
  I was super happy that one of my favourite players, reigning champ Ju Wenjun managed
  to secure a win with black in a scenario where she had to secure the full point
  not to concede the title altogether. I'm hopeful she can overcome her opponent,
  Kateryna Lagno in the rapid tiebreaks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  However... the waya lot of people talk about womens' chess is disgusting. Everyone is eager
  to jump on any minor inaccuracy, only discoverable to humans with the aid of a
  supercomputer, and slander the combatants as bad, the games as a comedy of errors.
  These players are top grandmasters, regardless of what gender their opposition may be,
  they are undeniably experts in their field. Their ratings are invariably much, much
  higher than the majority of their detractors (although I was upset to see some strong
  male players also disparage the match).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It reminds me a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monty_Hall_problem#Vos_Savant_and_the_media_furor&quot;
  target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Marilyn vos Savant and the Monty Hall Problem.&lt;/a&gt;
  I had hoped that society had progressed meaningfully in the brief 30 or so years
  since that happened, but it seems not, and that misogyny is still deep-rooted
  in our collective consciousness.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  People fucking suck.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Chess" /><summary type="html">After the first 10 games of the Open World Chess Championships, it's 5 points all, with every game having been a draw. There has been a lot of criticism in public media for these games all being ended peacefully - which is a little odd, seeing as the world seems more interested in this match than usual. It's a little depressing that people still don't see beauty in the draws - they just want blood over the board. And, to be fair there has been blood - there have been thrills and spills, mistakes, opening novelties, and sacrifices. It just so happens that all of these have balanced out thusfar. I wish people would stop complaining and enjoy the game. There hasn't even been a single Berlin Defence yet - how can you say that's boring?! On a related note, today was game 4 of the final of the Women's World Chess Championship. I was super happy that one of my favourite players, reigning champ Ju Wenjun managed to secure a win with black in a scenario where she had to secure the full point not to concede the title altogether. I'm hopeful she can overcome her opponent, Kateryna Lagno in the rapid tiebreaks. However... the waya lot of people talk about womens' chess is disgusting. Everyone is eager to jump on any minor inaccuracy, only discoverable to humans with the aid of a supercomputer, and slander the combatants as bad, the games as a comedy of errors. These players are top grandmasters, regardless of what gender their opposition may be, they are undeniably experts in their field. Their ratings are invariably much, much higher than the majority of their detractors (although I was upset to see some strong male players also disparage the match). It reminds me a lot of Marilyn vos Savant and the Monty Hall Problem. I had hoped that society had progressed meaningfully in the brief 30 or so years since that happened, but it seems not, and that misogyny is still deep-rooted in our collective consciousness. People fucking suck.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Missing Social Media</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/21/missing-social-media" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Missing Social Media" /><published>2018-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/21/missing-social-media</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/21/missing-social-media">&lt;p&gt;
  A couple of months ago I ditched the Twitter account I used under a screenname,
  and purged the app from my phone. Since then I've had no Facebook, Instagram,
  or Twitter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  When I decided to get rid of all of my accounts, I had assumed that after some
  kind of initial period of withdrawal, I would get to reap the benefits of my actions -
  both in the form of a smug sense of moral superiority over my lesser-willed peers
  and also in my newfound productivity, no longer endlessly scrolling on my phone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But I don't. Actually I kinda miss social media.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In its absence, I realise now that all those apps were scratching an itch for me -
  the itch for human connection. It made connectedness feel effortless
  and available 24/7, 365. Even if everything my friends posted on Facebook was mindless
  drivel, and I couldn't care less about the people who were supposedly my 'friends'
  on there anyway, at least I could get to see, like, interact with them. On Instagram,
  even if everyone I followed only ever posted pictures with the rose-tinted-est of filters,
  I still got to like, comment fire emojis, and feel as if that was some kind of
  meaningful interaction. On Twitter... actually I have nothing good to say about
  Twitter. It's a fundamentally flawed premise and a blight on digital culture and
  modern society.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I don't know if this feeling of interaction was 'real'. Perhaps some social engineer
  in a lab in Silicon Valley had perfectly calibrated the platform and its various
  algorithms in such a way that they knew I would receive just the right amount of
  dopamine. Perhaps it was in my own head, and the delusion was all mine, a way to
  justify my decision to avoid reaching out or being vulnerable with people. Perhaps
  it was a combination of both.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Maybe I have it right, by ditching these sites. Maybe everybody else has it right by
  embracing them. Maybe both, maybe neither, maybe something in between. I'm not
  smart enough to even posit a reasonable suggestion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  What I do know is that maintaining relationships is tough, especially without the easy
  interactions afforded to me by social media. If I want to gently remind someone
  that I still exist, I can no longer just like one of their posts, I have to
  send them a message, and it turns out that's a lot harder. I am prone to being
  bad at talking to people, and now I think without social apps I often feel
  isolated, even though I know rationally that if I did still have them, any
  sense of inclusion I might feel would only be superficial and fleeting. So...
  I don't really know what to do. Try really hard to make more of an effort I guess,
  and hope I can do it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Social Media" /><summary type="html">A couple of months ago I ditched the Twitter account I used under a screenname, and purged the app from my phone. Since then I've had no Facebook, Instagram, or Twitter. When I decided to get rid of all of my accounts, I had assumed that after some kind of initial period of withdrawal, I would get to reap the benefits of my actions - both in the form of a smug sense of moral superiority over my lesser-willed peers and also in my newfound productivity, no longer endlessly scrolling on my phone. But I don't. Actually I kinda miss social media. In its absence, I realise now that all those apps were scratching an itch for me - the itch for human connection. It made connectedness feel effortless and available 24/7, 365. Even if everything my friends posted on Facebook was mindless drivel, and I couldn't care less about the people who were supposedly my 'friends' on there anyway, at least I could get to see, like, interact with them. On Instagram, even if everyone I followed only ever posted pictures with the rose-tinted-est of filters, I still got to like, comment fire emojis, and feel as if that was some kind of meaningful interaction. On Twitter... actually I have nothing good to say about Twitter. It's a fundamentally flawed premise and a blight on digital culture and modern society. I don't know if this feeling of interaction was 'real'. Perhaps some social engineer in a lab in Silicon Valley had perfectly calibrated the platform and its various algorithms in such a way that they knew I would receive just the right amount of dopamine. Perhaps it was in my own head, and the delusion was all mine, a way to justify my decision to avoid reaching out or being vulnerable with people. Perhaps it was a combination of both. Maybe I have it right, by ditching these sites. Maybe everybody else has it right by embracing them. Maybe both, maybe neither, maybe something in between. I'm not smart enough to even posit a reasonable suggestion. What I do know is that maintaining relationships is tough, especially without the easy interactions afforded to me by social media. If I want to gently remind someone that I still exist, I can no longer just like one of their posts, I have to send them a message, and it turns out that's a lot harder. I am prone to being bad at talking to people, and now I think without social apps I often feel isolated, even though I know rationally that if I did still have them, any sense of inclusion I might feel would only be superficial and fleeting. So... I don't really know what to do. Try really hard to make more of an effort I guess, and hope I can do it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Too Busy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/20/too-busy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Too Busy" /><published>2018-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/20/too-busy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/20/too-busy">&lt;p&gt;
  I'm far too busy - too busy to think of a meaningful topic for today's blog.
  Too busy to relax or to slow down, too much to do - why do I do this to myself?
  I don't have time to answer the question, or else I'll be late for chess club.
  Chess will run later than my bed time too, so I'm even too busy to sleep. Fuck!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I'm far too busy - too busy to think of a meaningful topic for today's blog. Too busy to relax or to slow down, too much to do - why do I do this to myself? I don't have time to answer the question, or else I'll be late for chess club. Chess will run later than my bed time too, so I'm even too busy to sleep. Fuck!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Church of Iron</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/19/the-church-of-iron" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Church of Iron" /><published>2018-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/19/the-church-of-iron</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/19/the-church-of-iron">&lt;p&gt;
  The gym is infinitely more therapeutic than this 'talking about my feelings'
  bullshit. Or getting blackout drunk. Or, uhh, therapy. It's taken more 5 or so
  months to ease back into the routine and be able to start making progress, but
  I'm happy I've done it this way. I've tried to keep my injury risk as low as possible
  and I have yet to injure myself, touch wood. I've been able to pretty consistent
  about going 4-5 times a week, by only going for an hour at a time and not burning
  myself out too much. I've tried to keep things light, build my confidence, and resist
  the temptation to lift with my ego.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And finally, I am seeing progress. My lifts are slowly going up. I see some
  small physical differences. I feel slightly better about my body, and I feel
  better in general. 10/10 heartily recommend the church of iron. 
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Health and Fitness" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">The gym is infinitely more therapeutic than this 'talking about my feelings' bullshit. Or getting blackout drunk. Or, uhh, therapy. It's taken more 5 or so months to ease back into the routine and be able to start making progress, but I'm happy I've done it this way. I've tried to keep my injury risk as low as possible and I have yet to injure myself, touch wood. I've been able to pretty consistent about going 4-5 times a week, by only going for an hour at a time and not burning myself out too much. I've tried to keep things light, build my confidence, and resist the temptation to lift with my ego. And finally, I am seeing progress. My lifts are slowly going up. I see some small physical differences. I feel slightly better about my body, and I feel better in general. 10/10 heartily recommend the church of iron.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Surviving Mars</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/18/surviving-mars" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surviving Mars" /><published>2018-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/18/surviving-mars</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2018/11/18/surviving-mars">&lt;p&gt;
  Today was the first time in a long time that I decided I was going to play video games
  all day and not feel guilty about it. I managed to go to the gym and take a long
  call too, but I've smashed out a solid 8 hours of Surviving Mars. It's a lot
  of fun, a solid 7/10 of a game, and allowing myself to relax and do something I
  enjoy with no pressure, for a whole day, felt great. I'm glad I still have it
  in me to do this.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Gaming" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Today was the first time in a long time that I decided I was going to play video games all day and not feel guilty about it. I managed to go to the gym and take a long call too, but I've smashed out a solid 8 hours of Surviving Mars. It's a lot of fun, a solid 7/10 of a game, and allowing myself to relax and do something I enjoy with no pressure, for a whole day, felt great. I'm glad I still have it in me to do this.</summary></entry></feed>