<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-13T13:57:43+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Book Reviews: Models by Mark Manson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Reviews&amp;#58; Models by Mark Manson" /><published>2019-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson">&lt;p&gt;
  Thirteen days into the year and I have already read more books in 2019 than
  I did in 2018. I'm not quite on track for &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  reading 52 books in a year,&lt;/a&gt; but it's a good start.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have actually already read Models, about 2.5 years ago, and I can confidently
  say it changed my life. It provided the slap in the face I needed to finally
  cut off someone incredibly toxic in my life, by providing a blueprint for what
  a healthy, mutually fulfilling relationship should look like.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  While ostensibly a book about dating, the premise of its advice could be boiled
  down to 'if you improve yourself as a person, it will have the convenient side
  effect that women will be more attracted to you'. This might seem obvious, but
  the point Manson makes is that many men, when lamenting their romantic misfortune,
  focus too much on irrelevant details, like when to text a girl, whether or not
  to be mean to her, whether or not to pay for dinner etc. If you want to be luckier
  in love, then Manson prescribes a diet of self improvement: work on your insecurities
  and your anxieties, take an interest in the world around you, be confident in
  your intentions and actions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Upon first read, I was fairly enamoured with 100% of the content in this book,
  however with a couple more years of wisdom and experience (and of self-improvement)
  there are some things I am not so sure about anymore. Written in 2011, at one
  point the author references writing in a 'post-feminist age', but that landscape
  has shifted significantly, so perhaps the book needs updating to include
  post-post-feminist thinking. The chapter about sex (as in, what to do when you're
  actually between the sheets) was in my opinion, unnecessarily graphic. Figuring
  out what to put where is half the fun, and learning to communicate with an intimate
  partner is something that I have no desire to learn about from a book - even if
  the author of said book has had sex with infinitely more women than I have.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With that being said, there are a lot of things I still love about Models.
  Its stated aim is to provide a model for modern masculinity (hence the title),
  and by and large I think it does a good job. It offers practical, no nonsense
  advice for overcoming one's anxieties and growing in confidence. All of the
  commentary on the psychology of romance and attraction is at least plausible,
  even if there are frequent mentions of wholly uncited research.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Naturally, it's a self help book, so the million dollar question is whether or
  not it helped me - and the answer is yes, I think it did. There's a lot I will
  take away and apply from Models. Even reading it made me feel more confident -
  it's emphasis on honesty and genuine expression, rather than trying to say
  certain things or act a certain way, felt like it was giving me permission to
  be myself and worry less about what everyone else thinks. It wasn't as life-changing
  as my first read, which hopefully is a sign that I have matured as a person in
  the interim, but it was worth it nonetheless. A solid 7/10.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Books read this year: 1/52
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Next book: Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">Thirteen days into the year and I have already read more books in 2019 than I did in 2018. I'm not quite on track for reading 52 books in a year, but it's a good start. I have actually already read Models, about 2.5 years ago, and I can confidently say it changed my life. It provided the slap in the face I needed to finally cut off someone incredibly toxic in my life, by providing a blueprint for what a healthy, mutually fulfilling relationship should look like. While ostensibly a book about dating, the premise of its advice could be boiled down to 'if you improve yourself as a person, it will have the convenient side effect that women will be more attracted to you'. This might seem obvious, but the point Manson makes is that many men, when lamenting their romantic misfortune, focus too much on irrelevant details, like when to text a girl, whether or not to be mean to her, whether or not to pay for dinner etc. If you want to be luckier in love, then Manson prescribes a diet of self improvement: work on your insecurities and your anxieties, take an interest in the world around you, be confident in your intentions and actions. Upon first read, I was fairly enamoured with 100% of the content in this book, however with a couple more years of wisdom and experience (and of self-improvement) there are some things I am not so sure about anymore. Written in 2011, at one point the author references writing in a 'post-feminist age', but that landscape has shifted significantly, so perhaps the book needs updating to include post-post-feminist thinking. The chapter about sex (as in, what to do when you're actually between the sheets) was in my opinion, unnecessarily graphic. Figuring out what to put where is half the fun, and learning to communicate with an intimate partner is something that I have no desire to learn about from a book - even if the author of said book has had sex with infinitely more women than I have. With that being said, there are a lot of things I still love about Models. Its stated aim is to provide a model for modern masculinity (hence the title), and by and large I think it does a good job. It offers practical, no nonsense advice for overcoming one's anxieties and growing in confidence. All of the commentary on the psychology of romance and attraction is at least plausible, even if there are frequent mentions of wholly uncited research. Naturally, it's a self help book, so the million dollar question is whether or not it helped me - and the answer is yes, I think it did. There's a lot I will take away and apply from Models. Even reading it made me feel more confident - it's emphasis on honesty and genuine expression, rather than trying to say certain things or act a certain way, felt like it was giving me permission to be myself and worry less about what everyone else thinks. It wasn't as life-changing as my first read, which hopefully is a sign that I have matured as a person in the interim, but it was worth it nonetheless. A solid 7/10. Books read this year: 1/52 Next book: Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In the Aeroplane Over The Sea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In the Aeroplane Over The Sea" /><published>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/5COXoP5kj2DWfCDg0vxi4F?si=nTRqRsXyRHyoLtd7D82aFw&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  In the Aeroplane Over the Sea&lt;/a&gt; was the second and last album by the mysterious
  and oddly-named Neutral Milk Hotel, released in 1998 to little commercial success
  initially. Over the years however, its popularity has grown massively, and the
  record is now a critics' favourite, appearing on numerous
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Aeroplane_Over_the_Sea#Accolades&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  'Top X' style lists.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  For all its influence and acclaim, this album is... weird. It has a wonderfully
  lo-fi quality to it, and some of the instrumentation is uncommon - for example
  the uilleann pipes, which I had to Google (they're Irish bagpipes). Then there's
  the lyrics, which are abstract and &lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Neutral-milk-hotel-communist-daughter-lyrics&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  sometimes sexual in a very confusing way.&lt;/a&gt; The most bizarre thing about the
  album is without doubt that it appears to chronicle frontman Jeff Mangum's fascination
  with Anne Frank, including the line:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
      I wished I could save her in some sort of time machine
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Which seems like a strange premise for an album, but Mangum was apparently greatly
  moved by Frank's story, and understandably so. He seems like a odd dude, and
  its an odd album.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But the critics are absolutely right - this is one of the best records ever made.
  It's beautiful and evocative, despite its bizarre nature. The fact that it is so
  rough around the edges lends a sense of authenticity to the music, allowing the
  listener to emotionally connect with it. It is 39 minutes of raw, unfiltered
  human expression, and that is what art should be, even if you don't agree or
  empathise with what the artist is expressing. This is a true masterpiece, one
  of the greatest albums ever made. Go listen to it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">In the Aeroplane Over the Sea was the second and last album by the mysterious and oddly-named Neutral Milk Hotel, released in 1998 to little commercial success initially. Over the years however, its popularity has grown massively, and the record is now a critics' favourite, appearing on numerous 'Top X' style lists. For all its influence and acclaim, this album is... weird. It has a wonderfully lo-fi quality to it, and some of the instrumentation is uncommon - for example the uilleann pipes, which I had to Google (they're Irish bagpipes). Then there's the lyrics, which are abstract and sometimes sexual in a very confusing way. The most bizarre thing about the album is without doubt that it appears to chronicle frontman Jeff Mangum's fascination with Anne Frank, including the line: I wished I could save her in some sort of time machine Which seems like a strange premise for an album, but Mangum was apparently greatly moved by Frank's story, and understandably so. He seems like a odd dude, and its an odd album. But the critics are absolutely right - this is one of the best records ever made. It's beautiful and evocative, despite its bizarre nature. The fact that it is so rough around the edges lends a sense of authenticity to the music, allowing the listener to emotionally connect with it. It is 39 minutes of raw, unfiltered human expression, and that is what art should be, even if you don't agree or empathise with what the artist is expressing. This is a true masterpiece, one of the greatest albums ever made. Go listen to it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yudkowsky Ambititon Scale</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yudkowsky Ambititon Scale" /><published>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale">&lt;p&gt;
  While trawling through various 'best of Hacker News' articles, I learned of
  the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4509934&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Yudkowsky Ambition Scale.&lt;/a&gt; It's naturally meant to be tongue-in-cheek, and
  I think it's pretty funny - now we're living in 2019 it seems hard to list Apple and Facebook
  as entirely separate tiers of ambition. The mention of seasteading also caused
  me to go down a wiki-rabbithole for a few hours during which I became enamoured
  with the idea, but in a science fiction kinda way rather than a this-has-practical-applications 
  kinda way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Ambition is something I value highly in people, and until reading the scale,
  I would've labelled myself ambitious (as well as arrogant) .Naturally, the scale
  pertains to start-ups, but I am not a start-up, I'm just a guy,
  trying to figure out how to become a better guy. It's commonly
  given advice to be more ambitious, and I can see why that is - if you aim high
  and fail, you will invariably have achieved more than if you aimed lower and
  failed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This advice is a double edged sword though - high ambitions are good, but high
  expectations can be damaging, especially in the context of 'being a better guy'.
  The easiest way to be happier is to lower your expectations. When considering
  ambition and expectation, it seems important to be consciously aware of this
  disconnect, and so with that in mind, should I be more ambitious? In terms
  of my career, my personal relationship, my romantic prospects, my mental health?
  Maybe I'll come up with a new scale. The Spicer Ambitionish Scale™, coming soon.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Entrepreneurism" /><summary type="html">While trawling through various 'best of Hacker News' articles, I learned of the Yudkowsky Ambition Scale. It's naturally meant to be tongue-in-cheek, and I think it's pretty funny - now we're living in 2019 it seems hard to list Apple and Facebook as entirely separate tiers of ambition. The mention of seasteading also caused me to go down a wiki-rabbithole for a few hours during which I became enamoured with the idea, but in a science fiction kinda way rather than a this-has-practical-applications kinda way. Ambition is something I value highly in people, and until reading the scale, I would've labelled myself ambitious (as well as arrogant) .Naturally, the scale pertains to start-ups, but I am not a start-up, I'm just a guy, trying to figure out how to become a better guy. It's commonly given advice to be more ambitious, and I can see why that is - if you aim high and fail, you will invariably have achieved more than if you aimed lower and failed. This advice is a double edged sword though - high ambitions are good, but high expectations can be damaging, especially in the context of 'being a better guy'. The easiest way to be happier is to lower your expectations. When considering ambition and expectation, it seems important to be consciously aware of this disconnect, and so with that in mind, should I be more ambitious? In terms of my career, my personal relationship, my romantic prospects, my mental health? Maybe I'll come up with a new scale. The Spicer Ambitionish Scale™, coming soon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In Defence of Popular Music</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/10/in-defence-of-popular-music" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In Defence of Popular Music" /><published>2019-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/10/in-defence-of-popular-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/10/in-defence-of-popular-music">&lt;p&gt;
  In a &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent post&lt;/a&gt; I
  talked about my pathological contrarianism and my need to dislike things people like
  to fuel some narcisstic superiority complex. It is, obviously, a negative quality
  to possess and one I would duly like to correct. So today, I'd like to briefly
  admit that I actually quite like some pop music.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Having watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1YcYTdwEfoc&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  this video with pop musician and producer Grimes&lt;/a&gt;, I was struck by something
  she said in one of the clips. For her, it was an obvious choice to pursue pop,
  despite any criticims that it's a vapid or unfulfilling genre, because it's
  primary focus is the listeners happiness, or in her words:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    It's music that just seeks to hit the pleasure centre.
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And really, if I was critical of something with such pure intentions (let's pretend
  capitalism isn't a thing), I would be the asshole. My central criticism of pop
  is usually that it is not as interesting and emotionally engaging as other genres,
  and its over-commercialisation. If I were to start decrying everything I thought
  was unnecessarily commercialised, there wouldn't be a whole lot left. And just
  because something isn't emotionally engaging to me, especially given my melancholy
  disposition, doesn't mean it's not a valid art form.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Besides, I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; actually like some pop songs and artists, I'm just too proud
  to admit it. The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AX3Bsiq-13k&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Dua Lipa feat Blackpink song&lt;/a&gt; is awesome - admittedly I unashamedly loved Blackpink
  before hearing it. I adored &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Alice Merton's
  No Roots&lt;/a&gt; which was all over the radio last year.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCiGm_E4ZwYSHV3bcW1pnSeQ&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Billie Eilish&lt;/a&gt;
  is as much my Sad Queen as anyone else's. I am a big fan of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/Marinaandthediamonds&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marina and the Diamonds,&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/kimbramusic&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kimbra,&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/LordeMusic&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lorde,&lt;/a&gt;
  and the aforementioned
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/Grimezsz&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Grimes.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Maybe if I got over myself and listened to more of it, I'd be happier. Everyone
  else must like it for a reason.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">In a recent post I talked about my pathological contrarianism and my need to dislike things people like to fuel some narcisstic superiority complex. It is, obviously, a negative quality to possess and one I would duly like to correct. So today, I'd like to briefly admit that I actually quite like some pop music. Having watched this video with pop musician and producer Grimes, I was struck by something she said in one of the clips. For her, it was an obvious choice to pursue pop, despite any criticims that it's a vapid or unfulfilling genre, because it's primary focus is the listeners happiness, or in her words: It's music that just seeks to hit the pleasure centre. And really, if I was critical of something with such pure intentions (let's pretend capitalism isn't a thing), I would be the asshole. My central criticism of pop is usually that it is not as interesting and emotionally engaging as other genres, and its over-commercialisation. If I were to start decrying everything I thought was unnecessarily commercialised, there wouldn't be a whole lot left. And just because something isn't emotionally engaging to me, especially given my melancholy disposition, doesn't mean it's not a valid art form. Besides, I do actually like some pop songs and artists, I'm just too proud to admit it. The new Dua Lipa feat Blackpink song is awesome - admittedly I unashamedly loved Blackpink before hearing it. I adored Alice Merton's No Roots which was all over the radio last year. Billie Eilish is as much my Sad Queen as anyone else's. I am a big fan of Marina and the Diamonds, Kimbra, Lorde, and the aforementioned Grimes. Maybe if I got over myself and listened to more of it, I'd be happier. Everyone else must like it for a reason.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When it's easy, it's easy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/09/when-its-easy-its-easy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When it&amp;#39;s easy&amp;#44; it&amp;#39;s easy" /><published>2019-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/09/when-its-easy-its-easy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/09/when-its-easy-its-easy">&lt;p&gt;
  For the last 10 days I've been far less depressed than usual. So much so, you
  might say that for the last 10 days I haven't been depressed &lt;i&gt;at all.&lt;/i&gt; Neat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One thing that strikes me about not being constantly fucking miserable is
  how easier pretty much everything is. It's easier to get up and go to bed earlier,
  it's easier to eat healthier, to go to the gym, to talk to friends. It's easier to
  sit down and write these posts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  When I feel down, I still want to do all those things, but they take a lot of
  willpower. Even though they are relatively basic, getting them all done can
  take a lot out of me. Thinking about it now, I think this is one of the worst
  aspect of depression - performing simple tasks, tasks that you want to
  do, which will make you happier, becomes exhausting and can feel impossible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Whenever I'm in a period of time where I'm vaguely mentally healthy, I usually
  have two goals; firstly, to enjoy it fully, and secondly, to try to prepare for
  the next time things go south. I'm doing a pretty good job of the former, and I
  want to progress with the latter, particularly in relation to making the basics
  less tiresome. Other than trying to be disciplined, build routines and internalise
  the habits as much as possible... I am open to suggestions.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">For the last 10 days I've been far less depressed than usual. So much so, you might say that for the last 10 days I haven't been depressed at all. Neat. One thing that strikes me about not being constantly fucking miserable is how easier pretty much everything is. It's easier to get up and go to bed earlier, it's easier to eat healthier, to go to the gym, to talk to friends. It's easier to sit down and write these posts. When I feel down, I still want to do all those things, but they take a lot of willpower. Even though they are relatively basic, getting them all done can take a lot out of me. Thinking about it now, I think this is one of the worst aspect of depression - performing simple tasks, tasks that you want to do, which will make you happier, becomes exhausting and can feel impossible. Whenever I'm in a period of time where I'm vaguely mentally healthy, I usually have two goals; firstly, to enjoy it fully, and secondly, to try to prepare for the next time things go south. I'm doing a pretty good job of the former, and I want to progress with the latter, particularly in relation to making the basics less tiresome. Other than trying to be disciplined, build routines and internalise the habits as much as possible... I am open to suggestions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Repeated Mistakes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Repeated Mistakes" /><published>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes">&lt;p&gt;
  Yesterday was my first session back in the gym after two weeks off, due to
  the holiday season and being ill. The building is a converted warehouse, so there's no
  heating and it's very cold in the winter, so even if you warm up, taking long rests
  in between sets can cause your temperature to drop quite quickly. Between
  that, still not being over my illness, and diving straight back into my
  programme after a fortnight's break, I should have been cogniscent of having
  a much higher injury risk than normal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are no prizes for guessing what I did next. After 3 of 5 of my sets of
  squats, I felt my right hamstring become incredibly tight, and considered
  whether or not to continue. I knew it was the sensible thing to stop and doing
  something else, but for whatever reason I didn't, and proceeded to do my
  last two sets while trying to load my right leg as little as possible - hardly ideal for squatting. I
  massively compensated using my back and today it's inflamed and very painful;
  walking is difficult and I had to skip the gym. I saw this coming,
  so why did still I make the decision I did?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Obviously it was calulcated risk - injury wasn't a certainty. But I have
  been injured in this exact scenario before, so it was highly probable. My
  decision making process broke down, and there are several reasons for that:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      ego - not finishing would be 'weak' mentally, and in this case physically;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      desire for improvement - I am not content with where I am presently in my
      training, and I know I need to do the sets to get to where I want to be. I
      can't afford to make excuses, or I will not progess;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      guilt - I'd just taken two weeks off, I need to make up for lost time;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      expectation - I'd already set my expectations to do the whole session that
      evening, I did not want to fall short;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      laziness (of a kind) - making a conscious effort to change your plan takes
      effort, and a lot of times it is easier to simply stick with the way things
      are and deal with any potential consequences later.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Of course, this is a relatively minor example of a bad decision. But, life is a
  series of decisions, and this one was something of a trap - furthermore, a trap
  I think we all fall victim to. Humans repeat their own poor decisions with such
  frequency that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/surprised-pikachu&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  meme flavour of the month is very much dedicated to it (and a personal favourite
  of mine too).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If I can improve the mushy grey inference engine between my ears then perhaps
  I will become a better, happier person. Another very human trait is to shirk
  our responsibility to confront our mistakes (especially if this isn't the first time we've made them),
  and simply tell ourselves we will do better next time. Perhaps this sounds familiar
  to you. But I think autopsying those decisions can provide a huge amount of value
  and direction on how to overcome wider issues in your life. I guess I just gotta
  get my hands dirty more often.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Health and Fitness" /><summary type="html">Yesterday was my first session back in the gym after two weeks off, due to the holiday season and being ill. The building is a converted warehouse, so there's no heating and it's very cold in the winter, so even if you warm up, taking long rests in between sets can cause your temperature to drop quite quickly. Between that, still not being over my illness, and diving straight back into my programme after a fortnight's break, I should have been cogniscent of having a much higher injury risk than normal. There are no prizes for guessing what I did next. After 3 of 5 of my sets of squats, I felt my right hamstring become incredibly tight, and considered whether or not to continue. I knew it was the sensible thing to stop and doing something else, but for whatever reason I didn't, and proceeded to do my last two sets while trying to load my right leg as little as possible - hardly ideal for squatting. I massively compensated using my back and today it's inflamed and very painful; walking is difficult and I had to skip the gym. I saw this coming, so why did still I make the decision I did? Obviously it was calulcated risk - injury wasn't a certainty. But I have been injured in this exact scenario before, so it was highly probable. My decision making process broke down, and there are several reasons for that: ego - not finishing would be 'weak' mentally, and in this case physically; desire for improvement - I am not content with where I am presently in my training, and I know I need to do the sets to get to where I want to be. I can't afford to make excuses, or I will not progess; guilt - I'd just taken two weeks off, I need to make up for lost time; expectation - I'd already set my expectations to do the whole session that evening, I did not want to fall short; laziness (of a kind) - making a conscious effort to change your plan takes effort, and a lot of times it is easier to simply stick with the way things are and deal with any potential consequences later. Of course, this is a relatively minor example of a bad decision. But, life is a series of decisions, and this one was something of a trap - furthermore, a trap I think we all fall victim to. Humans repeat their own poor decisions with such frequency that the meme flavour of the month is very much dedicated to it (and a personal favourite of mine too). If I can improve the mushy grey inference engine between my ears then perhaps I will become a better, happier person. Another very human trait is to shirk our responsibility to confront our mistakes (especially if this isn't the first time we've made them), and simply tell ourselves we will do better next time. Perhaps this sounds familiar to you. But I think autopsying those decisions can provide a huge amount of value and direction on how to overcome wider issues in your life. I guess I just gotta get my hands dirty more often.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Movie Reviews IV</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/07/movie-reviews-iv" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Movie Reviews IV" /><published>2019-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/07/movie-reviews-iv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/07/movie-reviews-iv">&lt;p&gt;
  Movie reviews are back! I watched a few films over the holiday period, so here
  they are.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;An Evening With Beverly Luff Linn&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I wanted to watch this film purely because of the people in it, namely Aubury
  Plaza, Jermaine Clement, Craig Robertson and Matt Berry. I'd honestly watch
  anything with Aubury in it, and so I tried to learn as little about the plot
  as possible beforehand, I didn't even watch the trailer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This film is &lt;i&gt;weird.&lt;/i&gt; I'm not sure how else to describe it, other than
  bizarre, at times hilarious, at others human and emotional. It was everything
  I wanted out of it and I loved every second, but... I can't recommend it to
  you. Unless you have the same penchant for oddity I do, you will not enjoy
  this film I'm afraid.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Fargo&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  After having watch this film, I have dedicated 10 minutes in front of my mirror
  every day to perfecting my Minnesotan accent. It still sucks, but it's totally
  worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Obviously this didn't come out in 2018, so it's more of a classic, but I
  also enjoyed it a lot. Another strange movie, but this time one I absolutely
  would recommend - thrilling and hilarious, it heartily delivers on an evening
  of dark fun while giving you something to think about too. I hope you don't
  enjoy resolution, because you will still have plenty of questions left by the
  end, especially regarding whether the movie is as true as it claims to be; but it is
  well worth watching either way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Eighth Grade&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Given that this film was made by one of my heroes, and got onto &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/barackobama/posts/10156393283416749&quot;
  rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Barack Obama's top films of 2018&lt;/a&gt;, I had
  very high hopes for Eighth Grade, and was relieved that it still smashed them out
  of a park. It scares the hell out of me how much I related to the 13 year old
  female protagonist at points in this film, but I defy any millenial to say they
  don't. This is the first time I have seen issues I have felt affected me personally
  displayed on the big screen, as Bo Burnham beautifully shows the pains of puberty
  in the social media age. 10/10, absolutely recommended.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Movies" /><summary type="html">Movie reviews are back! I watched a few films over the holiday period, so here they are. An Evening With Beverly Luff Linn I wanted to watch this film purely because of the people in it, namely Aubury Plaza, Jermaine Clement, Craig Robertson and Matt Berry. I'd honestly watch anything with Aubury in it, and so I tried to learn as little about the plot as possible beforehand, I didn't even watch the trailer. This film is weird. I'm not sure how else to describe it, other than bizarre, at times hilarious, at others human and emotional. It was everything I wanted out of it and I loved every second, but... I can't recommend it to you. Unless you have the same penchant for oddity I do, you will not enjoy this film I'm afraid. Fargo After having watch this film, I have dedicated 10 minutes in front of my mirror every day to perfecting my Minnesotan accent. It still sucks, but it's totally worth it. Obviously this didn't come out in 2018, so it's more of a classic, but I also enjoyed it a lot. Another strange movie, but this time one I absolutely would recommend - thrilling and hilarious, it heartily delivers on an evening of dark fun while giving you something to think about too. I hope you don't enjoy resolution, because you will still have plenty of questions left by the end, especially regarding whether the movie is as true as it claims to be; but it is well worth watching either way. Eighth Grade Given that this film was made by one of my heroes, and got onto Barack Obama's top films of 2018, I had very high hopes for Eighth Grade, and was relieved that it still smashed them out of a park. It scares the hell out of me how much I related to the 13 year old female protagonist at points in this film, but I defy any millenial to say they don't. This is the first time I have seen issues I have felt affected me personally displayed on the big screen, as Bo Burnham beautifully shows the pains of puberty in the social media age. 10/10, absolutely recommended.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trip Planning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/06/trip-planning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trip Planning" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/06/trip-planning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/06/trip-planning">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I spent &lt;i&gt;far&lt;/i&gt; too much money on plane tickets, but I am very excited -
  this is my first Big Adult Holiday™. I am leaving work behind for two weeks and
  heading across the sea to the New York City, to go visit my best friend, along with
  another friend who I am excited to travel with and get to know better. I can't
  wait to get super fat on bagels, cheesecake and pizza, and learn to perfectly
  mimic a Lawn Guy Land accent. I'm gonna take a trip the Statue of Liberty,
  go see the Nets and then maybe bump into &lt;strike&gt;the President&lt;/strike&gt; Pete
  Davidson. It's gonna be sick.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's going to cost a lot, and there's a lot of potential for me to get super
  anxious. But you know what, I don't care. This could be one of the best
  trips of my life, and I'm not going to let shallow pockets or a restless
  mind stop me from enjoying it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's important for me to have things to look forward to when my health is bad.
  They're milestones, a place on the horizon that I can focus on slowly progressing
  towards. This one is gonna be a good one. USA, here I come.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today I spent far too much money on plane tickets, but I am very excited - this is my first Big Adult Holiday™. I am leaving work behind for two weeks and heading across the sea to the New York City, to go visit my best friend, along with another friend who I am excited to travel with and get to know better. I can't wait to get super fat on bagels, cheesecake and pizza, and learn to perfectly mimic a Lawn Guy Land accent. I'm gonna take a trip the Statue of Liberty, go see the Nets and then maybe bump into the President Pete Davidson. It's gonna be sick. It's going to cost a lot, and there's a lot of potential for me to get super anxious. But you know what, I don't care. This could be one of the best trips of my life, and I'm not going to let shallow pockets or a restless mind stop me from enjoying it. It's important for me to have things to look forward to when my health is bad. They're milestones, a place on the horizon that I can focus on slowly progressing towards. This one is gonna be a good one. USA, here I come.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">YouTube</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YouTube" /><published>2019-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube">&lt;p&gt;
  I absolutely &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt; to hate popular things. Tropical house, Regina George and pumpkin
  spiced lattes can all suck my dick. I will usually completely forego any kind
  of fair judgment process for something if I knew it's well-liked by the masses,
  and skip straight towards loudly proclaiming my distaste for it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So, in the spirit of trying to not be as shitty of a person, today I wanted to
  talk about how much I love YouTube, and how I think it is a monument to the
  human experience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Firstly - YouTube has its problems. Its a subsidiary of Alphabet, so you
  bet they are gobbling your data. The site has an obligation to appease advertisers
  and copyright holders so they make a lot of strange and seemingly nonsensical
  decisions on those grounds, and in so doing threatening the livelihoods of people
  who rely on their platform as a sole form of income. There's a lot of weird,
  immoral, illegal shit on there. And it seems like there's a new bizarro world
  of Ukrainian content farms exploiting children for millions of dollars.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But, let's sweep those all under the carpet for a moment. I love YouTube as a
  platform. It educates and entertains me, and the ASMR videos on there literally
  help me sleep at night. Why do I hold it in such higher esteem than most other
  sites of its size?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think YouTube offers both creators and consumers of content far more freedom
  than other platforms. There isn't really a formula for success on YouTube the same
  way there is on, for example, Instagram (in case you were wondering, the formula
  there is to post airbrushed photos of your scantily clad, but perfect, body). The
  infamous 'algorithm', as well as advertising stipulations, naturally reward some
  people more than others, but channels of all shapes and sizes flourish. With
  the obvious caveat that this is all based on my personal experience with the
  recommendation algorithm and my own interests, I absorb content from 30 second
  glorious shitpost videos to documentaries over an hour long. I watch music videos,
  comedy videos, journalistic videos, review videos, podcasts, programming videos,
  lifting videos, gaming videos, chess videos, ASMR videos, and probably far more.
  Having all these interests in one convenient place, and getting recommendations
  for similar content based on my habits, is actually pretty neat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Of course what makes YouTube great is absolutely not the company or the website
  itself, it's the people on it. Sure, there are literally millions of people
  churning out hypergarbage every day, but there are a surprisingly large amount
  of really wonderful, funny, insightful, enriching channels that aren't unecessarily
  difficult to find. The oft-feared comment section is admittedly laden with naysayers
  and unwell-wishers, but there are plenty of corners of the site which feel like
  an actual &lt;i&gt;community,&lt;/i&gt; often formed around a group of niche channels, where
  people are not all total assholes to each other. If you look hard enough, you
  can find these pockets of resistance, where people are actually people and not
  monsters. And I like that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Give it a few more years and I'm sure it'll have all gone to shit though.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Social Media" /><summary type="html">I absolutely love to hate popular things. Tropical house, Regina George and pumpkin spiced lattes can all suck my dick. I will usually completely forego any kind of fair judgment process for something if I knew it's well-liked by the masses, and skip straight towards loudly proclaiming my distaste for it. So, in the spirit of trying to not be as shitty of a person, today I wanted to talk about how much I love YouTube, and how I think it is a monument to the human experience. Firstly - YouTube has its problems. Its a subsidiary of Alphabet, so you bet they are gobbling your data. The site has an obligation to appease advertisers and copyright holders so they make a lot of strange and seemingly nonsensical decisions on those grounds, and in so doing threatening the livelihoods of people who rely on their platform as a sole form of income. There's a lot of weird, immoral, illegal shit on there. And it seems like there's a new bizarro world of Ukrainian content farms exploiting children for millions of dollars. But, let's sweep those all under the carpet for a moment. I love YouTube as a platform. It educates and entertains me, and the ASMR videos on there literally help me sleep at night. Why do I hold it in such higher esteem than most other sites of its size? I think YouTube offers both creators and consumers of content far more freedom than other platforms. There isn't really a formula for success on YouTube the same way there is on, for example, Instagram (in case you were wondering, the formula there is to post airbrushed photos of your scantily clad, but perfect, body). The infamous 'algorithm', as well as advertising stipulations, naturally reward some people more than others, but channels of all shapes and sizes flourish. With the obvious caveat that this is all based on my personal experience with the recommendation algorithm and my own interests, I absorb content from 30 second glorious shitpost videos to documentaries over an hour long. I watch music videos, comedy videos, journalistic videos, review videos, podcasts, programming videos, lifting videos, gaming videos, chess videos, ASMR videos, and probably far more. Having all these interests in one convenient place, and getting recommendations for similar content based on my habits, is actually pretty neat. Of course what makes YouTube great is absolutely not the company or the website itself, it's the people on it. Sure, there are literally millions of people churning out hypergarbage every day, but there are a surprisingly large amount of really wonderful, funny, insightful, enriching channels that aren't unecessarily difficult to find. The oft-feared comment section is admittedly laden with naysayers and unwell-wishers, but there are plenty of corners of the site which feel like an actual community, often formed around a group of niche channels, where people are not all total assholes to each other. If you look hard enough, you can find these pockets of resistance, where people are actually people and not monsters. And I like that. Give it a few more years and I'm sure it'll have all gone to shit though.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gell-Mann Amnesia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/04/gell-mann-amnesia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gell-Mann Amnesia" /><published>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/04/gell-mann-amnesia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/04/gell-mann-amnesia">&lt;p&gt;
  I've been thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gell-Mann_amnesia_effect&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gell-Mann
  Amnesia&lt;/a&gt; a lot recently. It doesn't really have any legitimacy as a psychological
  idea - in fact, as far as I can tell, it is little more than an offhand anecdote
  made by Michael Crichton - but it's interesting nonetheless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The concept intuitively makes sense. Not that I am really an expert in anything,
  but I have seen my fair share of claims-as-facts in media that I think are dubious,
  if not pure bollocks. Sure, maybe I am wrong in all these instances, and the
  writer of said comment was correct - but it usually does little to shake my faith
  in the rest of the information in the publication as a whole.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are many nuances to be considered. For example, if you read something
  on my blog that you felt was clearly erroneous, it might greatly shake your trust in my
  blog as a source, to the extent that you might stop believing what I wrote altogether.
  Conversely, if you read an article in the New York Times that
  you felt similarly about, it might have a smaller affect on your feelings towards the Times as
  a whole. I suspect many readers of news outlets of that ilk ignore the actual
  author of the piece, although in the context of Gell-Mann Amnesia, it seems
  very important to pay attention to who that is. Which I suppose raises some
  questions about the differences between the group of individuals that compromise
  a journalistic endeavour, and the endeavour itself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We could examine the phenomenon on a very broad scale too. I have read an inordinate
  number of factually inaccurate tweets - should I no longer give any credence to
  anything I read on Twitter? Admittedly, in that example, probably not. What about the internet as a whole? There
  are petabytes of blatant misinformation waiting to be consumed by unsuspecting
  webizens, can we believe any of it any more?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Well, that is the million dollar question. What do you think?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Psychology" /><summary type="html">I've been thinking about Gell-Mann Amnesia a lot recently. It doesn't really have any legitimacy as a psychological idea - in fact, as far as I can tell, it is little more than an offhand anecdote made by Michael Crichton - but it's interesting nonetheless. The concept intuitively makes sense. Not that I am really an expert in anything, but I have seen my fair share of claims-as-facts in media that I think are dubious, if not pure bollocks. Sure, maybe I am wrong in all these instances, and the writer of said comment was correct - but it usually does little to shake my faith in the rest of the information in the publication as a whole. There are many nuances to be considered. For example, if you read something on my blog that you felt was clearly erroneous, it might greatly shake your trust in my blog as a source, to the extent that you might stop believing what I wrote altogether. Conversely, if you read an article in the New York Times that you felt similarly about, it might have a smaller affect on your feelings towards the Times as a whole. I suspect many readers of news outlets of that ilk ignore the actual author of the piece, although in the context of Gell-Mann Amnesia, it seems very important to pay attention to who that is. Which I suppose raises some questions about the differences between the group of individuals that compromise a journalistic endeavour, and the endeavour itself. We could examine the phenomenon on a very broad scale too. I have read an inordinate number of factually inaccurate tweets - should I no longer give any credence to anything I read on Twitter? Admittedly, in that example, probably not. What about the internet as a whole? There are petabytes of blatant misinformation waiting to be consumed by unsuspecting webizens, can we believe any of it any more? Well, that is the million dollar question. What do you think?</summary></entry></feed>