<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-27T12:57:16+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Oatmeal and the Blerch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/26/oatmeal-and-the-blerch" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oatmeal and the Blerch" /><published>2019-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/26/oatmeal-and-the-blerch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/26/oatmeal-and-the-blerch">&lt;p&gt;As part of my newfound enthusiasm for running, this weekend I’ve tried to find which corners of the internet runners tend to frequent, so I can 
properly integrate myself into their society. In so doing, I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://theoatmeal.com/comics/running&quot;&gt;this wonderful series of webcomics&lt;/a&gt; by The Oatmeal, who it turns out 
is an ultra runner. I was particularly inspired by the Blerch, and there is undoubtedly a part of my brain that I can freely associate with it (incidentally, I’ve 
previously come to think of it as Jerry, the catastrophically uninspiring father from Rick and Morty). During my brief foray into the crossroads between online 
and running culture, it seems distance runners in particular seem to revel in a particularly bizzare masochism-induced euphoria that comes from pushing your body 
to its limits. The feeling of achievement after completing a run has been a big motivator for me so far - it really is blissful. It makes me feel more confident 
about myself, even though nothing has changed. It feels good to push myself and consistently find that I have a lot more to give, and I’m excited to see how far I can 
take that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">As part of my newfound enthusiasm for running, this weekend I’ve tried to find which corners of the internet runners tend to frequent, so I can properly integrate myself into their society. In so doing, I discovered this wonderful series of webcomics by The Oatmeal, who it turns out is an ultra runner. I was particularly inspired by the Blerch, and there is undoubtedly a part of my brain that I can freely associate with it (incidentally, I’ve previously come to think of it as Jerry, the catastrophically uninspiring father from Rick and Morty). During my brief foray into the crossroads between online and running culture, it seems distance runners in particular seem to revel in a particularly bizzare masochism-induced euphoria that comes from pushing your body to its limits. The feeling of achievement after completing a run has been a big motivator for me so far - it really is blissful. It makes me feel more confident about myself, even though nothing has changed. It feels good to push myself and consistently find that I have a lot more to give, and I’m excited to see how far I can take that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Park Run</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/25/park-run" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Park Run" /><published>2019-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/25/park-run</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/25/park-run">&lt;p&gt;Today I ran my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Park Run&lt;/a&gt; something which even 6 weeks ago I didn’t think I’d be remotely close to being able to achieve. 
I managed a time of 30:34 when I was expecting to be nearer the 34-35m mark, so that was a pleasant surprise, especially given I had intentionally not set 
myself a goal other than to complete the run without getting injured. Well - my goal was to do it in less than double the time of my housemate Sam, who 
finished only 1.5 minutes after I began my second lap, winning the race in a cool 17:50. Getting to run with that many people, on a gorgeous day, around 
a beautiful course, was an amazing experience, and one I am excited to repeat next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I am enjoying the whole running experience a lot, in part because the weather has been amazing and the routes around me are stunning, and in part 
because I started off better than I’d thought and I’m progressing fast in a short space of time. I am already getting ahead of myself a little in terms 
of plans and goals, so I have been making an effort to reel it back and just take it one run at a time. Hopefully I can maintain at least some of this 
enthusiasm once my initial infuatation fades.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">Today I ran my first Park Run something which even 6 weeks ago I didn’t think I’d be remotely close to being able to achieve. I managed a time of 30:34 when I was expecting to be nearer the 34-35m mark, so that was a pleasant surprise, especially given I had intentionally not set myself a goal other than to complete the run without getting injured. Well - my goal was to do it in less than double the time of my housemate Sam, who finished only 1.5 minutes after I began my second lap, winning the race in a cool 17:50. Getting to run with that many people, on a gorgeous day, around a beautiful course, was an amazing experience, and one I am excited to repeat next week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ding Dong The Witch is Dead</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/24/ding-dong-the-witch-is-dead" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ding Dong The Witch is Dead" /><published>2019-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/24/ding-dong-the-witch-is-dead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/24/ding-dong-the-witch-is-dead">&lt;p&gt;This is, I believe, my first blog on the subject of politics, a subject that I have by and large deliberately avoided writing about. In part because I don’t think anyone 
should care about my political opinions, given my total lack of research or comprehension of any of the issues involved, and also in part because political discourse on 
the internet is, for lack of a better phrase, a total shitshow and I have no desire to contribute to that. I have always labelled myself as apathetic to the subject at 
large, believing that in the end, which particular posh wanker gets elected won’t actually produce a meaningful effect on my life, however Brexit changed all that, when 
I realised the rubbernecking opportunity to end them all, the chance to watch an entire country’s political system derail, crash, explode and then scatter debris, up close 
over the course of three years (and counting of course). It’s been compelling viewing to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the train conductor has flung herself from the lead carriage, with Mrs May announcing her imminent resignation, and despite using that particular metaphor, I am in 
fact rather sad to see her go. Ignoring the fact that all of her likely successors are inevitably self-serving, career driven xenophobes, and that I have disagreed with 
her decisions at many points in the Brexit process, I have come to admire her a great deal, even more so as a result of her speech today. I truly cannot think of any job 
I would have wanted less than to be Prime Minister over the past three years - Mrs May’s task was to unite a country that has never been more divided in living memory, 
preserve democracy, strengthen an unstable economy, and restore faith in not just her government, but indeed the entire political system. I cannot even begin to imagine 
the strains and the pressures that she must have felt as she tried to accomplish this insurmountable task while beseiged on all sides, yet at all times she remained 
resolute, dignified and remained true to what she believed in, truly acting as a servant to her country, in the way that she believed was best. It was only today 
that she finally cracked and displayed emotion publically, a reminder to the nation that she is as human as any of us, serving to really emphasise her resilience during 
her time as leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure plenty of people will not be writing nice things about Mrs May this evening, but I for one have been inspired by her.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Politics" /><summary type="html">This is, I believe, my first blog on the subject of politics, a subject that I have by and large deliberately avoided writing about. In part because I don’t think anyone should care about my political opinions, given my total lack of research or comprehension of any of the issues involved, and also in part because political discourse on the internet is, for lack of a better phrase, a total shitshow and I have no desire to contribute to that. I have always labelled myself as apathetic to the subject at large, believing that in the end, which particular posh wanker gets elected won’t actually produce a meaningful effect on my life, however Brexit changed all that, when I realised the rubbernecking opportunity to end them all, the chance to watch an entire country’s political system derail, crash, explode and then scatter debris, up close over the course of three years (and counting of course). It’s been compelling viewing to say the least.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Feeling Overwhelmed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/23/feeling-overwhelmed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feeling Overwhelmed" /><published>2019-05-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/23/feeling-overwhelmed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/23/feeling-overwhelmed">&lt;p&gt;Whenever I have tried to articulate how I feel during a period of mental struggle in the past, I have often said that I am overwhelmed. Overwhelmed by obligations, 
expectations, calendars and to-do lists, social calls to be made and blog posts to be written. At some point it all gets too much, and rather than face any of it, 
I shy away from everything and confine myself to my bed, paralysed by the fear that I won’t get everything I need to done, and so ironically doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is of course that that was then, and this is now, and so I am better equiped to deal with those feelings before they become insurmountable. This week I can 
see them creeping up - I am pushing myself to do well in my new job, have been trying to hold conversations with many friends, plan trips, court my wife-to-be 
on Tinder, run, not eat total shit, troubleshoot various tech problems, and finally make some long overdue updates to this site.
Somewhere in all of that, I need to find time to stop, breath, and look after myself. To remember what makes me happy, to reevaluate and reprioritise accordingly.
To watch Netflix and eat ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s odd, to feel myself slipping, but even armed with that knowledge not to be sure how to catch myself. Being aware of it seems like a good start, trying 
consciously to put less pressure on myself in all the areas described above, trying to value time spent looking after myself more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep breaths…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">Whenever I have tried to articulate how I feel during a period of mental struggle in the past, I have often said that I am overwhelmed. Overwhelmed by obligations, expectations, calendars and to-do lists, social calls to be made and blog posts to be written. At some point it all gets too much, and rather than face any of it, I shy away from everything and confine myself to my bed, paralysed by the fear that I won’t get everything I need to done, and so ironically doing nothing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adventures in Online Dating II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/22/adventures-in-online-dating-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adventures in Online Dating II" /><published>2019-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/22/adventures-in-online-dating-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/22/adventures-in-online-dating-ii">&lt;p&gt;There’s been both good and bad developments since my last update on the whole Tinder malarkey, but first…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… some unsolicited advice! The best kind. My favourite kind in fact. I am clearly in no position to lecture people 
on what they should and should not put on their Tinder profiles, but I cannot help myself from commenting on a snippet 
of one young lady’s biography that I came across the other day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you don’t like the Big Band Theory don’t even bother swiping right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sentence physically hurt me to read. I pinched myself, worried that I was thrashing around in my bed, caught in the 
throes of a nightmare, but alas I was not - the dystopia surrounding me was very real. I wanted to scream but all that came out of 
my mouth was a canned laugh track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, now I’ve made my point, let’s get into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, and I am aware that this not exactly a hot take, but the Big Bang is far from the peak of comedy. My (teenage) brother 
has been a fan for years and as such I have had to sit through pretty much the entirety of the show, and the only joke that 
has elicited genuine amusement from me is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2DBSQswHTsw&quot;&gt;“I don’t care for perchloroethylene, and I don’t like glycol ether”&lt;/a&gt;, and frankly if you 
have the above slogan splashed across your dating profile then I suspect you do not understand it. It’s comedy for the masses, 
designed to appeal to the lowest common denominator, the equivalent of writing that you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPYiTpy5F5I&quot;&gt;love dogs, wine and travelling&lt;/a&gt;.
Except, rather than just casting the widest net possible, you are cutting off anyone not in the bell of the curve; what kind of 
generic experiences are you hoping for? How narrow is your vision, how near are your horizons? The incredible thing about people is that 
they’re all weird and wonderful and &lt;em&gt;unique&lt;/em&gt;, not that they all love garbage TV. Why are you so fervent about culling Big Bang naysayers 
from your romantic prospects anyway? I can understand not wishing to entertain the thought of dating someone with different religious or political 
views, but if Mr Perfect’s favourite series is Brooklyn Nine Nine, are you really going to throw him in the trash?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all talking about the principle, and wholly ignoring that the show is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X3-hOigoxHs&quot;&gt;unrepentently misogynistic throughout&lt;/a&gt;, to 
the extent I don’t believe it should have a place in modern television, let alone the praise, viewership and money that it has brought in. 
The writing is cheap, has no integrity, and perpetuates a multitude of harmful stereotypes about pretty much everyone it portrays in the 
show, especially women. I may be &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/05/06/should-i-call-myself-a-feminist&quot;&gt;reluctant to call myself a feminist&lt;/a&gt; but if you 
are going to fight for gender equality by only aligning yourself with people who think portrayals of long-term sexual harrassment are the 
zenith of our culture, then I’m Emily Davison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. The bad news is that it’s pretty easy to blitz through the entirety of Guernsey’s Tinder population, and I have done so with little success.
I think the plan is to come back in 6 months time, try to lose some weight, get better pictures, yadda yadda yadda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news, is that little success != zero success. But maybe more on that another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy swiping, friends.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">There’s been both good and bad developments since my last update on the whole Tinder malarkey, but first…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smalltalk Revisited</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/21/smalltalk-revisited" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smalltalk Revisited" /><published>2019-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/21/smalltalk-revisited</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/21/smalltalk-revisited">&lt;p&gt;Today I had, by far, the most in depth conversation I’ve ever had with someone while they were cutting my hair - and yes, that includes my mother.
The classic barbershop smalltalk has forever been something that terrifies me, to the extent that I have pretty bad anxiety about the whole process, 
from phoning to book an appointment, turning up and having to awkwardly wait while whoever is before me is laughing and joking around, to very Britishly 
saying ‘looks great, thanks’ when shown the back of my head, wholly irregardless of whether or not the back of my head does in fact look great. But today, 
I was determined to have some kind of conversation, even if it was only minor, and guess what - I actually did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked for a solid ten minutes, mostly about her daughter’s dance competitions in the UK, and I think I finally see the appeal of smalltalk as a whole. 
Conversation doesn’t have to be deep or meaningful, it can be slathered with thick layers of deflection, but people’s personalities will always shine 
through, and there will be shiny golden nuggets of inner beauty to be found if only I am willing to pan through the silt of having to describe what I do 
for my job and listening to a banal weekend’s plan or three.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Today I had, by far, the most in depth conversation I’ve ever had with someone while they were cutting my hair - and yes, that includes my mother. The classic barbershop smalltalk has forever been something that terrifies me, to the extent that I have pretty bad anxiety about the whole process, from phoning to book an appointment, turning up and having to awkwardly wait while whoever is before me is laughing and joking around, to very Britishly saying ‘looks great, thanks’ when shown the back of my head, wholly irregardless of whether or not the back of my head does in fact look great. But today, I was determined to have some kind of conversation, even if it was only minor, and guess what - I actually did!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Windows Terminal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/20/windows-terminal" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windows Terminal" /><published>2019-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/20/windows-terminal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/20/windows-terminal">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/terminal&quot;&gt;Windows Terminal&lt;/a&gt; is on the way and I am very excited for it, because that means 
there will &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; be a CLI I can use on Windows which has tabs… seriously, how did it take so long?! For me, PowerShell 
has always paled in comparison to both iTerm2 and guake which I use on other systems, in terms of flexibility and functionality 
as well as the whole tab shebang. Not only that, but being able to seemlessly add WSL tabs where I can script in bash and actually 
know the commands will be a godsent, rather than having to do the weird mish-mash of dotnet commands in PowerShell and then do 
everything else in my Ubuntu shell like I’m currently doing, which is a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my currently massive preference for VSCode over competing editors, if Terminal is everything it promises to be then I think I might 
be back on the Microsoft development hype train.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Windows" /><summary type="html">Windows Terminal is on the way and I am very excited for it, because that means there will finally be a CLI I can use on Windows which has tabs… seriously, how did it take so long?! For me, PowerShell has always paled in comparison to both iTerm2 and guake which I use on other systems, in terms of flexibility and functionality as well as the whole tab shebang. Not only that, but being able to seemlessly add WSL tabs where I can script in bash and actually know the commands will be a godsent, rather than having to do the weird mish-mash of dotnet commands in PowerShell and then do everything else in my Ubuntu shell like I’m currently doing, which is a nightmare.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Barkley Marathons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/19/the-barkley-marathons" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Barkley Marathons" /><published>2019-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/19/the-barkley-marathons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/19/the-barkley-marathons">&lt;p&gt;The Netflix documentary about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barkley_Marathons&quot;&gt;The Barkley Marathons&lt;/a&gt; is subtitled ‘The Race That Eats Its Children’, 
and after watching it, I entirely understand that choice. The ultramarathon covers a distance of ‘100.00M’ - however ask any runner and they will say 
it is likely close to 130M, and with 120000 feet of elevation change, it is the equivalent of climbing up Everest from sea level and back down again - twice - in just 60 hours. 
The terrain is brutal, with every single competitiors legs getting slashed to pieces by briars all over the course. In order to prove that you’ve completed 
an entire loop (there are five in total - completing three is known as a ‘Fun Run’), you have to tear out pages of books that correlate to your race number, placed 
at various locations around the course. The race officially begins when the organizer lights his cigarette, which he does an hour after blowing a conch shell, 
which can be done anytime between midnight and noon on race day. When you drop out, a bugler plays Taps to signal your ‘death’. Every year, of the forty allocated 
slots, one is given to the ‘Human Sacrifice’ - a runner who has applied to be in the race, but who the organizers feel have no chance whatsoever of completing it. 
Fortunately there is a very small application fee of just $1.60 - however that must be supplemented with an essay on why you ought to be selected to run the Barkley. 
If you are selected, then you receive a letter of condolences informing you so. If this is your first time, the entry fee is a license plate from your home state or 
country, and if it’s not, then the entry fee is often a miscellaneous piece of clothing - it’s previously been socks and white shirts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s beyond ludicrous. The fact that anyone has ever completed this thing is a testament to humanity, but the fact that someone dreamed it up in the first place 
is an even bigger one. It certainly make me feel like I should aim higher.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">The Netflix documentary about The Barkley Marathons is subtitled ‘The Race That Eats Its Children’, and after watching it, I entirely understand that choice. The ultramarathon covers a distance of ‘100.00M’ - however ask any runner and they will say it is likely close to 130M, and with 120000 feet of elevation change, it is the equivalent of climbing up Everest from sea level and back down again - twice - in just 60 hours. The terrain is brutal, with every single competitiors legs getting slashed to pieces by briars all over the course. In order to prove that you’ve completed an entire loop (there are five in total - completing three is known as a ‘Fun Run’), you have to tear out pages of books that correlate to your race number, placed at various locations around the course. The race officially begins when the organizer lights his cigarette, which he does an hour after blowing a conch shell, which can be done anytime between midnight and noon on race day. When you drop out, a bugler plays Taps to signal your ‘death’. Every year, of the forty allocated slots, one is given to the ‘Human Sacrifice’ - a runner who has applied to be in the race, but who the organizers feel have no chance whatsoever of completing it. Fortunately there is a very small application fee of just $1.60 - however that must be supplemented with an essay on why you ought to be selected to run the Barkley. If you are selected, then you receive a letter of condolences informing you so. If this is your first time, the entry fee is a license plate from your home state or country, and if it’s not, then the entry fee is often a miscellaneous piece of clothing - it’s previously been socks and white shirts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WCS Spring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/18/wcs-spring" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WCS Spring" /><published>2019-05-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/18/wcs-spring</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/18/wcs-spring">&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of productive things on my todo list this week, including a lot of work on this website and the Guernsey chess site as well, but then today I woke up, 
checked reddit, and saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=unLLM3Jann8&amp;amp;t=920s&quot;&gt;this beautiful game&lt;/a&gt; at the top of r/starcraft and realised that I was not in fact 
going to get anything done today whatsoever. It’s been a lovely evening of being sat in front of my desk, sipping my matcha juice trying to recover from my 
hangover, and watching the best Starcraft that everywhere-except-Korea has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always the games have been thrilling, with some innovative strategies, cunning psychological tricks and phenomenal mechanical ability on display from players 
throughout the day. Seeing some young players do exceptionally well (three of the last 16 players in the event are 17) battling veterans that have been in the 
scene for over 10 years shows that Starcraft is still alive and kicking, and it really &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; seem like the gap might be closing. With GSL’s redemption and 
renaissance storylines in full swing, and the Koreans showing remarkable depth of talent in their league, I think this year’s international tournaments are 
set to be some of the most fiercely competed yet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="esports" /><summary type="html">I had a lot of productive things on my todo list this week, including a lot of work on this website and the Guernsey chess site as well, but then today I woke up, checked reddit, and saw this beautiful game at the top of r/starcraft and realised that I was not in fact going to get anything done today whatsoever. It’s been a lovely evening of being sat in front of my desk, sipping my matcha juice trying to recover from my hangover, and watching the best Starcraft that everywhere-except-Korea has to offer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Ode to the Love Shack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/17/an-ode-to-love-shack" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Ode to the Love Shack" /><published>2019-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/17/an-ode-to-love-shack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/05/17/an-ode-to-love-shack">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you see a faded sign at the end of the road that says
“15 miles to the 
Love Shack”
Love Shack, yeah, yeah”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to pay homage to what is comfortably the best fast food place in Guernsey. It is of course, (the) Love Shack, situated 
near the bottom of St Julian’s Avenue, and it is a 2am institution. While it’s primary fare may be kebabs, it does not deserve the low 
reputation associated with many establishments of its ilk, as the food is consistently delicious, and while not exactly being healthy, 
it is far from the greasy, oily late-night feast that one might usually expect to find after getting kicked out of the club. I think 
that the best possible endorsement I can give is that Sam and I periodically visit the Shack for dinner when we are &lt;em&gt;stone cold sober&lt;/em&gt;, 
on a weeknight no less. The Shack is always open, seemingly neverendlingly staffed by its proprietor, whose name regretfully I do not know, 
but who I have infinite respect for, for his hardwork, level of customer service and dedication to his craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless Love Shack.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Fine Dining" /><summary type="html">If you see a faded sign at the end of the road that says “15 miles to the Love Shack” Love Shack, yeah, yeah”</summary></entry></feed>