<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Favourite Albums of All Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot in the past few days about how music makes me really, really happy in a way that few other things do.
Originally I was going to try and write a “top 10 favourite albums” post but that ended up bleeding into 50, which subsequently
bled further into 100, which finally resulted in a list of roughly 150 albums. That seemed like a terrible number though, so I
managed to cull it down to a nice even hundo, and here they are in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alexisonfire - alexisonfire (2002, post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alexisonfire - Watch Out! (2004, post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alexisonfire - Crisis (2006, post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring Me The Horizon - Count Your Blessings (2006, deathcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring Me The Horizon - Suicide Season (2008, metalcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Teens of Denial (2016,  indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Twin Fantasy (2011, indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brand New - Your Favourite Weapon (2001, pop punk/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brand New - Deja Entendu (2003, alt rock/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brand New - The Devil and God Are Raging Inside Me (2006, alt rock/emo/post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brand New - Daisy (2009, alt rock/post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brand New - Science Fiction (2017, alt rock/post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Front Bottoms - The Front Bottoms (indie rock/folk punk/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Front Bottoms - Talon of the Hawk (2013, indie rock/folk punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My Chemical Romance - Three Cheers For Sweet Revenge (2004, alt rock/post-hardcore/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My Chemical Romance - The Black Parade (2006, alt rock/post-hardcore/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modern Baseball - Sports (2012, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modern Baseball - You’re Gonna Miss It All (2014, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Breaking Benjamin - Phobia (2006, alt metal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Day To Remember - Homesick (2009, metalcore/pop punk/post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bombay Bicycle Club - I Had The Blues But I Shook Them Loose (2009, indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System Of A Down - Mezmerize (2005, nu metal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Escape The Fate - Dying Is Your Latest Fashion (2006, emo/post-hardcore/metalcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Say Anything - …Is A Real Boy (2004, emo/indie rock/pop punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Say Anything - Say Anything (2009, emo/indie rock/pop punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trivium - Ascendancy (2005, metalcore/thrash)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joy Division - Unknown Pleasures (1979, post-punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Panic! At The Disco - A Fever You Can’t Sweat Out (2005, emo/pop punk/alt rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Streetlight Manifesto - Keasbey Nights (2006, ska punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Streetlight Manifesto - Somewhere In The Between (2007, ska punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Biffy Clyro - Only Revolutions (2009, alt rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marina and the Diamonds - The Family Jewels (2010, alt pop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Caravan Palace - &amp;lt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;°_°&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&amp;gt; (2015, electro swing)&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three Days Grace - Three Days Grace (2003, alt metal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The White Stripes - Elephant (2003, blues rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darwin Deez - Darwin Deez (2010, indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joyce Manor - Joyce Manor (2011, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joyce Manor - Never Hungover Again (2014, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeff Rosenstock - We Cool? (2015, punk/indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeff Rosenstock - WORRY. (2016, punk/indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blink-182 - blink-182 (2003, pop punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blink-182 - Enema Of The State (1999, pop punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blink-182 - Take Off Your Pants And Jacket (2001, pop punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TTNG - 13.0.0.0.0 (2013, math rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neutral Milk Hotel - In The Aeroplane Over The Sea (1998, indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arcade Fire - Funeral (2004, indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modest Mouse - Good News For People Who Love Bad News (2004, alt rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weezer - Weezer (Blue Album) (1994, alt rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weezer - Pinkerton (1996, alt rock/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Tribe Called Quest - The Low End Theory (1991, hip hop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kanye West - The College Dropout (2004, hip hop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PUP - PUP (2013, punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PUP - The Dream Is Over (2016, punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slipknot - All Hope Is Gone (2008, heavy metal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arctic Monkeys - Whatever People Say I Am, That’s What I’m Not (2006, indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metronomy - The English Riviera (2011, new wave)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fall Out Boy - Take This To Your Grave (2003, pop punk/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fall Out Boy - From Under The Cork Tree (2005, pop punk/emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Veil of Maya - Matriarch (2015, djent)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mitski - Bury Me At Makeout Creek (2014, indie rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Violent Soho - Hungry Ghost (2013, grunge)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tricot - T H E (2013, math rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glocca Morra - Just Married (2012, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capn Jazz - Burritos, Inspiration Point, Fork Balloon Sports, Cards in the Spokes, Automatic Biographies, Kites, Kung Fu, Trophies, Banana Peels We’ve Slipped On and Egg Shells We’ve Tippy Toed Over (1995, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remo Drive - Greatest Hits (2017, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Polyphia - New Levels New Devils (2018, prog metal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epica - Design Your Universe (2009, symphonic metal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Covet - effloresce (2018, math rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;McCafferty - Beachboy (2013, dance punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mom Jeans. - Best Buds (2016, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blue Sky, Black Death - Noir (2011, instrumental hip hop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DZ Deathrays - Black Rat (2014, dance punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduating Life - An Introduction To Rock And Roll (2017, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ceremony - Rohnert Park (2010, punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowing - I Could Do Whatever I Wanted If I Wanted (2011, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Julien Baker - Sprained Ankle (2015, folk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IDLES - Joy as an Act of Resistance. (2018, punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protest The Hero - Kezia (2005, prog metal/mathcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FIDLAR - FIDLAR (2013, skate punk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter Shikari - A Flash Flood of Colour (2012, post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alvvays - Antisocialites (2017, indie pop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonobo - Migration (2017, electronica)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonobo - The North Borders (2013, electronica)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I Kill Giants - I Kill Giants (2013, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;King Gizzard And The Lizard Wizard - Nonagon Infinity (2016, pysch rock/prog rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;King Gizzard And The Lizard Wizard - Polygondwanaland (2017, psych rock/prog rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strawberry Girls - French Ghetto (2013, prog rock/math rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vulfpeck - The Beautiful Game (2016, funk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forests - Sun Eat Moon Grave Party (2017, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;black midi - Schlagenheim (2019, experimental rock/noise rock/post-punk/math rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title Fight - Floral Green (2012, emo/post-hardcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nekrogoblikon - Welcome to Bonkers (2018, melodic death metal/power metal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prince Daddy And The Hyena - I Thought You Didn’t Even Like Leaving (2016, emo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grimes - Art Angels (2015, synth-pop/art pop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hobo Johnson - The Fall of Hobo Johnson (2019, emo rap)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Totorro - Home Alone (2016, noise rock)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boards of Canada - Music Has The Right To Children (1998, electronica)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fall of Troy - Doppelgänger (2005, mathcore)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Animals As Leaders - Animals As Leaders (2009, prog metal/djent)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Animals As Leaders - The Joy of Motion (2014, prog metal/djent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/29/100-favourite-albums-of-all-time</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/29/100-favourite-albums-of-all-time</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teamwork</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend is the Global Game Jam, and this year we have been infinitely more organised than last - we’ve got a full team of 6(!)
before the event has even started, and we’ve already decided on an engine and a version control system. It will be fun to try and
learn some Unity and make a game, but the thing I am most looking forward to is certainly the element of working in a team with
five of my friends. We even have a name - I Can’t Believe It’s Not Beta - and you can follow any progress we make on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ICantBelieveItsNotBeta&quot;&gt;Github.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/28/teamwork</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/28/teamwork</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Correspondence Chess Tournaments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year is my third year playing in the Chess.com annual correspondence tournament, and I believe everywhere year has surpassed
the previous iteration as the largest correspondence chess tournament in history. A remarkable 16831 players registered for the 2020
edition, and at the time of writing, 3634 of those players remain, with myself amongst their number. For the past two years I’ve
failed to make it past my first group (the format is quite brutal, with groups of 12 players yielding only a single one who will
advance to the next round), despite being very close both times, and so this year I’m happy to report that I’ve finally broke my
streak of poor form and made it through to round two, acquiring 21 wins and one loss in the process. It’s been a pleasant
experience, both to feel part of something so big and also to feel relatively competent compared to others playing in the
tournament, and while I think it is very unlikely I will progress any further as the standard will increase dramatically, I am
nonetheless hopeful that numerous rabbits can be pulled out of hats and I’ll be able to cause some big upsets to make it to round
three.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/27/correspondence-chess-tournaments</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/27/correspondence-chess-tournaments</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can Jonny Actually Read Challenge 2.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I read no books whatsoever, and so last year I set myself the lofty goal of reading 52 in 52 weeks. Obviously, I failed, managing a measly 6, but at least that was
an infinite improvement. This year I have decided to set a goal that is a little more achievable - to read a single book. The only problem is that that book is David Foster
Wallace’s legendary epic, &lt;em&gt;Infinite Jest&lt;/em&gt;. At 1079 pages long, it may well compromise more than the sum of the 6 books that I read last year, and will most likely make for a
much denser read. Still, that is the point of settings oneself a challenge right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look forward to my review sometime around December…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/26/can-jonny-actually-read-challenge-20</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/26/can-jonny-actually-read-challenge-20</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Home Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This evening I am delighted to report that I have the opportunity to play in a home game, which may in fact be the second most +EV spot I’ve ever been in - the first is naturally this bet. I can’t remember the
last time I played holdem, and the format is going to be essentially hyper SNGs, but these people won’t even be able to spell ICM, and I smell blood in the water. Hopefully tomorrow I will be able to treat myself to
a nice steak dinner with their money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/25/home-games</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/25/home-games</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome Back to the Black Parade</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tickets for My Chemical Romance’s first show in the UK since 2011 went on sale today at 9:30am. On the 20th June, the band will be
playing in Milton Keynes as part of their reunion that started last month in LA. The ticket vendors’ sites struggled to keep up
with demand, with one crashing pretty much immediately as the clock struck half past, with others placing would-be concert goers
into queues in order to try to process them in an orderly manner. Unsurprisingly, the show sold out quickly. Fortunately, I got
three tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June, I am going to have the experience of standing in a crowd of tens of thousands of people as the band play the first note
to their beyond iconic song, “Welcome to the Black Parade”, the legendary G note which is embedded deep within all of our psyches.
I can’t think of the last time I was this excited about something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/24/welcome-back-to-the-black-parade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/24/welcome-back-to-the-black-parade</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Goryachkina v Ju</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today saw the 12th game of the FIDE Women’s World Championship match between Aleksandra Goryachkina and Wenjun Ju, and much
like the 2018 men’s match between Carlsen and Caruana, after the classical portion of the match the score is tied at 6 points
a piece. The huge difference between the two matches however, is that the women’s match has seen 6 decisive games, including
Goryachkina spectacularly winning on demand today in round 12, compared to none whatsoever in the men’s match. I think
the Russian almost certainly has the advantage going into the tie-breaks, both due to her momentum and morale from the last match,
and also that she is now on home soil, playing in Vladivostock. After storming the Candidates’ match and winning with a whole round
to spare, for the 21 year old to unseat the Chinese powerhouse would certainly have people to start to wonder how high Goryachkina’s
ceiling is - she looks set to surpass 2600 rating this year, but can she surpass Hou Yifan? A 2700 rating? Even surpassing Judit
Polgar’s rating and being able to compete in super-elite invitationals looks possible, albeit there is a very long way still to go
in order to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, the ladies seem to be outclassing their male counterparts when it comes to producing entertaining games and storylines,
and Dvorkovich’s decision to have both world championships follow the same format is looking to have paid off and then some. If
Goryachkina does win then I think it could draw a decent amount of mainstream media attention, which would undoubtedly be a good
thing for the game, and I am certainly looking forward to watching the rapid games at the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/23/goryachkina-v-ju</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/23/goryachkina-v-ju</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lunch &amp;&amp; Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today saw the reincarnation of Guernsey techie meetup Lunch &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Code, sponsored by the wonderful
company that employs yours truly. I have always felt a little uncomfortable at these kinds of events previously (perhaps this is
the case for the majority of attendees, given their nature as software-type-people and their propensity for having poor social
skills), but today I’m pleased to report I felt a lot more at home amongst their number. In part I think it is partially an easing
of my anxiety in general (as discussed &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2020/01/20/say-yes&quot;&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt;) and in part because I have formed connections
of some description with enough of the regulars that I can overcome some amount of initial awkwardness. My entire “professional”
life I have struggled hugely with networking, habitually being struck by overwhelming nerves to the extent I’ve abhored and avoided
the practice for years. Today though, I actually managed to have a couple of fairly reasonable conversations that could possibly
be described as at least networking-adjacent… Progress?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/22/lunch-code</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/22/lunch-code</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Line Film Synopses</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my recent absence from blogging, I managed to make my way through a respectable number of films, and I thought it’d be fun to
write one-line synopses for them all - these all have spoilers to some degree!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;train-to-busan&quot;&gt;Train to Busan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hot-shot stock trader has head so far up his own rectum it takes the literal apocalypse for him to realise that he should spend more
time with his daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dead-dont-die&quot;&gt;The Dead Don’t Die&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Driver and Bull Murray are weird, Tilda Swinton is extremely weird, Chloe Sevigny is the only person who reacts proportionately
to anything that goes on in this film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zombieland-2&quot;&gt;Zombieland 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesse Eisenberg’s continued romantic success with Emma Stone in this movie continues to perpetuate my own incredibly unrealistic
expectations about beautiful girls reciprocating my affection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-centipede-1&quot;&gt;Human Centipede 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weird fetish-horror-porn with no self awareness whatsoever; the dialogue was so bad I was honestly somewhat relieved when the
characters were sewn together so they could no longer speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-centipede-2&quot;&gt;Human Centipede 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weirder, more horrific horror-porn catering to an even nicher fetish; despite obviously knowing it’s not real, probably more
disturbing to me than any of the myriad of things I have seen on the internet that I am reasonably certain were real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-centipede-3&quot;&gt;Human Centipede 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writers finally acquired some self-awareness, a budget, and Bree Olson, making this film actually somewhat enjoyable once
you’ve been desensitised to the absurdity of the trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hereditary&quot;&gt;Hereditary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 25 year old highschool student accidentally kills his sister and subsequently becomes the earthly incarnation of Satan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;midsommar&quot;&gt;Midsommar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The penny finally drops for an American student that she deserves better than her boyfriend when they join a pagan cult in rural Sweden and they offer to murder him for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-lighthouse&quot;&gt;The Lighthouse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Pattinson suffers a psychotic break after extensive bullying by a seagull while Willem Defoe mistakenly believes this is an
adaptation of a Shakespeare tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/21/one-line-film-synopses</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/21/one-line-film-synopses</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Say Yes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Historically I have had a lot of trouble leaving my comfort zone, which has had a sort of self-perpetuating nature - the longer one remains in their comfort zone, the smaller it becomes. I’ve experienced generalised
anxiety for the majority of my adult life to a greater or lesser degree, and it has at times been debilitating. It has certainly prevented me from doing a great many things that I might otherwise have done. Recently
though I’ve somewhat made a breakthrough on this front, although perhaps not for the right reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s become painfully clear to me now that actually there is great &lt;em&gt;dis&lt;/em&gt;comfort within my so-called comfort zone, and that pain is in fact comparable with my worst-case scenario were I to leave it and dive into
whatever it is I might have anxiety about. It’s a very bizarre conclusion to come to, that what I had previously thought was the low risk, safe option is actually the high risk one, and subsequently any paths
previously judged to be high risk are at worst equally dicey in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, my anxiety has diminished a lot in recent weeks, although admittedly that changes seems to have been borne from a sense of nihilism. But so far, I have said yes to a handful of things that the old me
would not have, and I’ve yet to have any go badly wrong. I want to keep saying yes, and forge a new comfort zone within the novel and unknown, embracing new experiences wherever I can, regardless of any fears I might
have, even to some extent willing to take greater legitimate risks. I know that it won’t all go smoothly, and there will be some amount of pain incurred by this, but there will be pain on my previous path anyway,
so what does it matter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing I have said yes to is going swimming in the sea at 7am on Thursday. Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/20/say-yes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/01/20/say-yes</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>