<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-17T19:31:21+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">High Standards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/17/high-standards" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High Standards" /><published>2019-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/17/high-standards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/17/high-standards">&lt;p&gt;
  Ever since I was a kid, I've wanted to write a book. I remember when I was in
  primary school, resolving to pen a story 100 pages long, which at the time
  seemed like a feat that would bring me untold recognition and praise upon its
  completion. Naturally I didn't even come close to finishing it - my lack of
  execution obviously set in early in my life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  About 15 months ago I first considered writing short stories, as a way to
  express myself and the struggles I was dealing with in a less self-absorbed
  way than chronicling my own experiences factually. Obviously I didn't
  ever get round to doing that either, because I am a perennially weak-willed,
  lazy individual.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Recently I read a blog post (that I have not been able to rediscover
  in order to link or give credit to, sadly) that pointed out that if you wrote 200
  words a day for a mere 125 days, you would be left with 25,000 words of writing,
  and many would consider that to be approximately one book's-worth. Well, I thought
  to myself, I write approximate 200 words a day, and I have done for the past
  125 days or thereabouts. The issues were that firstly those writings
  were solely non-fictional, and I would have no interest in writing anything
  other than fiction; secondly that they are separate pieces and these incongruent
  and incoherent when viewed together; and thirdly that they are, by and large,
  perfectly fucking awful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I doubt there is much I will be able to do about the last one, but with some
  kind of concerted effort, I could surely remedy the former two problems. I
  clearly have it in me to write consistently enough to produce enough words
  to fill a book. Furthermore, when I was creating my &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reading list
  for this year,&lt;/a&gt; I tried to fill it with authors who I thought would inspire me,
  and whose influence I might be able to draw upon if and when I tried my own
  hand at writing fiction.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Talking to an old school friend this week, who is infinitely better read than I,
  I realised another hurdle I would have to jump over. If I tried to write a book,
  I would want it to be of an insanely high standard. I'd want to write like
  Proust or Dostoevsky. I'd want my text to be as deep and nuanced as Infinite Jest.
  I might write 200 words a day, but I'd spend the next fortnight redrafting them.
  I would reject a million good ideas before finally settling on one, not because
  I thought it was perfect, but because I was frustrated at my own lack of progress.
  My vision of the plot would inevitably change often through the process of both
  planning, drafting and then editing. I would envariable find myself trapped
  betwixt a desire to both emulate my literary heroes and also to produce
  something unique and original.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Despite all this, perhaps I'll write a book one day. It might be fun, in a
  masochistic kinda way.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">Ever since I was a kid, I've wanted to write a book. I remember when I was in primary school, resolving to pen a story 100 pages long, which at the time seemed like a feat that would bring me untold recognition and praise upon its completion. Naturally I didn't even come close to finishing it - my lack of execution obviously set in early in my life. About 15 months ago I first considered writing short stories, as a way to express myself and the struggles I was dealing with in a less self-absorbed way than chronicling my own experiences factually. Obviously I didn't ever get round to doing that either, because I am a perennially weak-willed, lazy individual. Recently I read a blog post (that I have not been able to rediscover in order to link or give credit to, sadly) that pointed out that if you wrote 200 words a day for a mere 125 days, you would be left with 25,000 words of writing, and many would consider that to be approximately one book's-worth. Well, I thought to myself, I write approximate 200 words a day, and I have done for the past 125 days or thereabouts. The issues were that firstly those writings were solely non-fictional, and I would have no interest in writing anything other than fiction; secondly that they are separate pieces and these incongruent and incoherent when viewed together; and thirdly that they are, by and large, perfectly fucking awful. I doubt there is much I will be able to do about the last one, but with some kind of concerted effort, I could surely remedy the former two problems. I clearly have it in me to write consistently enough to produce enough words to fill a book. Furthermore, when I was creating my reading list for this year, I tried to fill it with authors who I thought would inspire me, and whose influence I might be able to draw upon if and when I tried my own hand at writing fiction. Talking to an old school friend this week, who is infinitely better read than I, I realised another hurdle I would have to jump over. If I tried to write a book, I would want it to be of an insanely high standard. I'd want to write like Proust or Dostoevsky. I'd want my text to be as deep and nuanced as Infinite Jest. I might write 200 words a day, but I'd spend the next fortnight redrafting them. I would reject a million good ideas before finally settling on one, not because I thought it was perfect, but because I was frustrated at my own lack of progress. My vision of the plot would inevitably change often through the process of both planning, drafting and then editing. I would envariable find myself trapped betwixt a desire to both emulate my literary heroes and also to produce something unique and original. Despite all this, perhaps I'll write a book one day. It might be fun, in a masochistic kinda way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mom Jeans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/16/mom-jeans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mom Jeans" /><published>2019-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/16/mom-jeans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/16/mom-jeans">&lt;p&gt;
  Last night I got to see Just Friends and Mom Jeans life, and both were incredible.
  Watching the 10 piece ska-punk collective Just Friends all going nuts on stage
  in a tiny, sold-out venue that was essentially a pub was a heart-warming experience.
  Mom Jeans had tech problems and played without monitors and were phenomenal regardless.
  Gabe told truly awful jokes. Bart tuned Gabe's bass. Eric almost made me cry.
  Austin looked cute in the back, thereby fulfilling the entirety of his responsibilities
  as a drummer. They were perfect. Throughout their set, all I could think about
  was how purely, genuinely happy I was.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Tonight I am exhausted and feel kinda sad, and tomorrow I have to go to work.
  But I know that in the future, I will have the same feeling as I had last night
  once more.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">Last night I got to see Just Friends and Mom Jeans life, and both were incredible. Watching the 10 piece ska-punk collective Just Friends all going nuts on stage in a tiny, sold-out venue that was essentially a pub was a heart-warming experience. Mom Jeans had tech problems and played without monitors and were phenomenal regardless. Gabe told truly awful jokes. Bart tuned Gabe's bass. Eric almost made me cry. Austin looked cute in the back, thereby fulfilling the entirety of his responsibilities as a drummer. They were perfect. Throughout their set, all I could think about was how purely, genuinely happy I was. Tonight I am exhausted and feel kinda sad, and tomorrow I have to go to work. But I know that in the future, I will have the same feeling as I had last night once more.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5am</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/15/5am" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5am" /><published>2019-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/15/5am</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/15/5am">&lt;p&gt;
  I am writing this at 5:15am, and have to leave in 30 minutes to catch a flight,
  so it is going to be quick.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Today I get to go floating, see one of my favourite bands live and stay with
  one of my oldest friends. It has the potential to be an amazing day, and I
  am very excited. Without getting my hopes up too much, I think I'm going to be
  really happy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm sure I'll tell you all about it tomorrow.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I am writing this at 5:15am, and have to leave in 30 minutes to catch a flight, so it is going to be quick. Today I get to go floating, see one of my favourite bands live and stay with one of my oldest friends. It has the potential to be an amazing day, and I am very excited. Without getting my hopes up too much, I think I'm going to be really happy. I'm sure I'll tell you all about it tomorrow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">People Are My Religion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/14/people-are-my-religion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People Are My Religion" /><published>2019-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/14/people-are-my-religion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/14/people-are-my-religion">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-u05Yc5zurI&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  People are my religion.&lt;/a&gt; Well, they are now at least. Having spent my entire
  adult life largely being a misanthrope, perpetually bitter at numerous perceived
  sleights, I am finally making an effort to get over myself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My loudly professed distate for humanity is a byproduct of my
  own insecurities is surely obvious to everyone but me. Perhaps it is even my
  Soul Toupee (or, one of them). It may have once served some purpose to insulate
  my fragile ego from the barbs of reality, but now it is obselete - and I would
  like to consign it to history, an artifact of my personality that is no more
  than a milestone for growth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In the past month or so, I have come to realise how pivotal other people are
  in my own happiness. Maintaining healthy, vulnerable relationships with the people
  that I care about is going to give me a feeling of connectedness that will stave
  off the icy grip of depression. Striving to be able to interact openly and easily with
  strangers and acquaintances is going to be integral to vanquishing my anxieties.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Inspired by reading &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Models,&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8fkTdr3snLQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  Elon Musk high as a kite,&lt;/a&gt; by my friend Ongun and by a great many other things,
  the hermetic life is not for me. As much as I would love to pretend that I am better
  than everyone around me, that I don't need them, today I begin to make a conscious
  effort to change that, to see the good in everyone, as corny as that might sound.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'm not going to flip and become a hippy or a Buddhist monk overnight - I'm sure
  I will still get angry and frustrated by people, and lash out sometimes. But
  the important thing is that I'm going to try to make a positive difference.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">People are my religion. Well, they are now at least. Having spent my entire adult life largely being a misanthrope, perpetually bitter at numerous perceived sleights, I am finally making an effort to get over myself. My loudly professed distate for humanity is a byproduct of my own insecurities is surely obvious to everyone but me. Perhaps it is even my Soul Toupee (or, one of them). It may have once served some purpose to insulate my fragile ego from the barbs of reality, but now it is obselete - and I would like to consign it to history, an artifact of my personality that is no more than a milestone for growth. In the past month or so, I have come to realise how pivotal other people are in my own happiness. Maintaining healthy, vulnerable relationships with the people that I care about is going to give me a feeling of connectedness that will stave off the icy grip of depression. Striving to be able to interact openly and easily with strangers and acquaintances is going to be integral to vanquishing my anxieties. Inspired by reading Models, by Elon Musk high as a kite, by my friend Ongun and by a great many other things, the hermetic life is not for me. As much as I would love to pretend that I am better than everyone around me, that I don't need them, today I begin to make a conscious effort to change that, to see the good in everyone, as corny as that might sound. I'm not going to flip and become a hippy or a Buddhist monk overnight - I'm sure I will still get angry and frustrated by people, and lash out sometimes. But the important thing is that I'm going to try to make a positive difference.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Reviews: Models by Mark Manson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Reviews&amp;#58; Models by Mark Manson" /><published>2019-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/13/book-reviews-models-by-mark-manson">&lt;p&gt;
  Thirteen days into the year and I have already read more books in 2019 than
  I did in 2018. I'm not quite on track for &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2018/12/23/reading-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  reading 52 books in a year,&lt;/a&gt; but it's a good start.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have actually already read Models, about 2.5 years ago, and I can confidently
  say it changed my life. It provided the slap in the face I needed to finally
  cut off someone incredibly toxic in my life, by providing a blueprint for what
  a healthy, mutually fulfilling relationship should look like.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  While ostensibly a book about dating, the premise of its advice could be boiled
  down to 'if you improve yourself as a person, it will have the convenient side
  effect that women will be more attracted to you'. This might seem obvious, but
  the point Manson makes is that many men, when lamenting their romantic misfortune,
  focus too much on irrelevant details, like when to text a girl, whether or not
  to be mean to her, whether or not to pay for dinner etc. If you want to be luckier
  in love, then Manson prescribes a diet of self improvement: work on your insecurities
  and your anxieties, take an interest in the world around you, be confident in
  your intentions and actions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Upon first read, I was fairly enamoured with 100% of the content in this book,
  however with a couple more years of wisdom and experience (and of self-improvement)
  there are some things I am not so sure about anymore. Written in 2011, at one
  point the author references writing in a 'post-feminist age', but that landscape
  has shifted significantly, so perhaps the book needs updating to include
  post-post-feminist thinking. The chapter about sex (as in, what to do when you're
  actually between the sheets) was in my opinion, unnecessarily graphic. Figuring
  out what to put where is half the fun, and learning to communicate with an intimate
  partner is something that I have no desire to learn about from a book - even if
  the author of said book has had sex with infinitely more women than I have.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  With that being said, there are a lot of things I still love about Models.
  Its stated aim is to provide a model for modern masculinity (hence the title),
  and by and large I think it does a good job. It offers practical, no nonsense
  advice for overcoming one's anxieties and growing in confidence. All of the
  commentary on the psychology of romance and attraction is at least plausible,
  even if there are frequent mentions of wholly uncited research.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Naturally, it's a self help book, so the million dollar question is whether or
  not it helped me - and the answer is yes, I think it did. There's a lot I will
  take away from Models and apply to my day to day life. Even reading it made me feel more confident -
  its emphasis on honesty and genuine expression, rather than trying to say
  certain things or act a certain way, felt like it was giving me permission to
  be myself and worry less about what everyone else thinks. It wasn't as life-changing
  as my first read, which hopefully is a sign that I have matured as a person in
  the interim, but it was worth it nonetheless. A solid 7/10.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Books read this year: 1/52
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Next book: Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><category term="Dating and Relationships" /><summary type="html">Thirteen days into the year and I have already read more books in 2019 than I did in 2018. I'm not quite on track for reading 52 books in a year, but it's a good start. I have actually already read Models, about 2.5 years ago, and I can confidently say it changed my life. It provided the slap in the face I needed to finally cut off someone incredibly toxic in my life, by providing a blueprint for what a healthy, mutually fulfilling relationship should look like. While ostensibly a book about dating, the premise of its advice could be boiled down to 'if you improve yourself as a person, it will have the convenient side effect that women will be more attracted to you'. This might seem obvious, but the point Manson makes is that many men, when lamenting their romantic misfortune, focus too much on irrelevant details, like when to text a girl, whether or not to be mean to her, whether or not to pay for dinner etc. If you want to be luckier in love, then Manson prescribes a diet of self improvement: work on your insecurities and your anxieties, take an interest in the world around you, be confident in your intentions and actions. Upon first read, I was fairly enamoured with 100% of the content in this book, however with a couple more years of wisdom and experience (and of self-improvement) there are some things I am not so sure about anymore. Written in 2011, at one point the author references writing in a 'post-feminist age', but that landscape has shifted significantly, so perhaps the book needs updating to include post-post-feminist thinking. The chapter about sex (as in, what to do when you're actually between the sheets) was in my opinion, unnecessarily graphic. Figuring out what to put where is half the fun, and learning to communicate with an intimate partner is something that I have no desire to learn about from a book - even if the author of said book has had sex with infinitely more women than I have. With that being said, there are a lot of things I still love about Models. Its stated aim is to provide a model for modern masculinity (hence the title), and by and large I think it does a good job. It offers practical, no nonsense advice for overcoming one's anxieties and growing in confidence. All of the commentary on the psychology of romance and attraction is at least plausible, even if there are frequent mentions of wholly uncited research. Naturally, it's a self help book, so the million dollar question is whether or not it helped me - and the answer is yes, I think it did. There's a lot I will take away from Models and apply to my day to day life. Even reading it made me feel more confident - its emphasis on honesty and genuine expression, rather than trying to say certain things or act a certain way, felt like it was giving me permission to be myself and worry less about what everyone else thinks. It wasn't as life-changing as my first read, which hopefully is a sign that I have matured as a person in the interim, but it was worth it nonetheless. A solid 7/10. Books read this year: 1/52 Next book: Notes from Underground by Fyodor Dostoevsky</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In the Aeroplane Over The Sea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In the Aeroplane Over The Sea" /><published>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/12/in-the-aeroplane-over-the-sea">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/5COXoP5kj2DWfCDg0vxi4F?si=nTRqRsXyRHyoLtd7D82aFw&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  In the Aeroplane Over the Sea&lt;/a&gt; was the second and last album by the mysterious
  and oddly-named Neutral Milk Hotel, released in 1998 to little commercial success
  initially. Over the years however, its popularity has grown massively, and the
  record is now a critics' favourite, appearing on numerous
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Aeroplane_Over_the_Sea#Accolades&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  'Top X' style lists.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  For all its influence and acclaim, this album is... weird. It has a wonderfully
  lo-fi quality to it, and some of the instrumentation is uncommon - for example
  the uilleann pipes, which I had to Google (they're Irish bagpipes). Then there's
  the lyrics, which are abstract and &lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Neutral-milk-hotel-communist-daughter-lyrics&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  sometimes sexual in a very confusing way.&lt;/a&gt; The most bizarre thing about the
  album is without doubt that it appears to chronicle frontman Jeff Mangum's fascination
  with Anne Frank, including the line:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
      I wished I could save her in some sort of time machine
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Which seems like a strange premise for an album, but Mangum was apparently greatly
  moved by Frank's story, and understandably so. He seems like a odd dude, and
  its an odd album.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  But the critics are absolutely right - this is one of the best records ever made.
  It's beautiful and evocative, despite its bizarre nature. The fact that it is so
  rough around the edges lends a sense of authenticity to the music, allowing the
  listener to emotionally connect with it. It is 39 minutes of raw, unfiltered
  human expression, and that is what art should be, even if you don't agree or
  empathise with what the artist is expressing. This is a true masterpiece, one
  of the greatest albums ever made. Go listen to it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">In the Aeroplane Over the Sea was the second and last album by the mysterious and oddly-named Neutral Milk Hotel, released in 1998 to little commercial success initially. Over the years however, its popularity has grown massively, and the record is now a critics' favourite, appearing on numerous 'Top X' style lists. For all its influence and acclaim, this album is... weird. It has a wonderfully lo-fi quality to it, and some of the instrumentation is uncommon - for example the uilleann pipes, which I had to Google (they're Irish bagpipes). Then there's the lyrics, which are abstract and sometimes sexual in a very confusing way. The most bizarre thing about the album is without doubt that it appears to chronicle frontman Jeff Mangum's fascination with Anne Frank, including the line: I wished I could save her in some sort of time machine Which seems like a strange premise for an album, but Mangum was apparently greatly moved by Frank's story, and understandably so. He seems like a odd dude, and its an odd album. But the critics are absolutely right - this is one of the best records ever made. It's beautiful and evocative, despite its bizarre nature. The fact that it is so rough around the edges lends a sense of authenticity to the music, allowing the listener to emotionally connect with it. It is 39 minutes of raw, unfiltered human expression, and that is what art should be, even if you don't agree or empathise with what the artist is expressing. This is a true masterpiece, one of the greatest albums ever made. Go listen to it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yudkowsky Ambititon Scale</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yudkowsky Ambititon Scale" /><published>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/11/yudkowsky-ambition-scale">&lt;p&gt;
  While trawling through various 'best of Hacker News' articles, I learned of
  the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4509934&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Yudkowsky Ambition Scale.&lt;/a&gt; It's naturally meant to be tongue-in-cheek, and
  I think it's pretty funny - now we're living in 2019 it seems hard to list Apple and Facebook
  as entirely separate tiers of ambition. The mention of seasteading also caused
  me to go down a wiki-rabbithole for a few hours during which I became enamoured
  with the idea, but in a science fiction kinda way rather than a this-has-practical-applications 
  kinda way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Ambition is something I value highly in people, and until reading the scale,
  I would've labelled myself ambitious (as well as arrogant) .Naturally, the scale
  pertains to start-ups, but I am not a start-up, I'm just a guy,
  trying to figure out how to become a better guy. It's commonly
  given advice to be more ambitious, and I can see why that is - if you aim high
  and fail, you will invariably have achieved more than if you aimed lower and
  failed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This advice is a double edged sword though - high ambitions are good, but high
  expectations can be damaging, especially in the context of 'being a better guy'.
  The easiest way to be happier is to lower your expectations. When considering
  ambition and expectation, it seems important to be consciously aware of this
  disconnect, and so with that in mind, should I be more ambitious? In terms
  of my career, my personal relationship, my romantic prospects, my mental health?
  Maybe I'll come up with a new scale. The Spicer Ambitionish Scale™, coming soon.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Entrepreneurism" /><summary type="html">While trawling through various 'best of Hacker News' articles, I learned of the Yudkowsky Ambition Scale. It's naturally meant to be tongue-in-cheek, and I think it's pretty funny - now we're living in 2019 it seems hard to list Apple and Facebook as entirely separate tiers of ambition. The mention of seasteading also caused me to go down a wiki-rabbithole for a few hours during which I became enamoured with the idea, but in a science fiction kinda way rather than a this-has-practical-applications kinda way. Ambition is something I value highly in people, and until reading the scale, I would've labelled myself ambitious (as well as arrogant) .Naturally, the scale pertains to start-ups, but I am not a start-up, I'm just a guy, trying to figure out how to become a better guy. It's commonly given advice to be more ambitious, and I can see why that is - if you aim high and fail, you will invariably have achieved more than if you aimed lower and failed. This advice is a double edged sword though - high ambitions are good, but high expectations can be damaging, especially in the context of 'being a better guy'. The easiest way to be happier is to lower your expectations. When considering ambition and expectation, it seems important to be consciously aware of this disconnect, and so with that in mind, should I be more ambitious? In terms of my career, my personal relationship, my romantic prospects, my mental health? Maybe I'll come up with a new scale. The Spicer Ambitionish Scale™, coming soon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In Defence of Popular Music</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/10/in-defence-of-popular-music" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In Defence of Popular Music" /><published>2019-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/10/in-defence-of-popular-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/10/in-defence-of-popular-music">&lt;p&gt;
  In a &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/01/05/youtube&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent post&lt;/a&gt; I
  talked about my pathological contrarianism and my need to dislike things people like
  to fuel some narcisstic superiority complex. It is, obviously, a negative quality
  to possess and one I would duly like to correct. So today, I'd like to briefly
  admit that I actually quite like some pop music.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Having watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1YcYTdwEfoc&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  this video with pop musician and producer Grimes&lt;/a&gt;, I was struck by something
  she said in one of the clips. For her, it was an obvious choice to pursue pop,
  despite any criticims that it's a vapid or unfulfilling genre, because it's
  primary focus is the listeners happiness, or in her words:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    It's music that just seeks to hit the pleasure centre.
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And really, if I was critical of something with such pure intentions (let's pretend
  capitalism isn't a thing), I would be the asshole. My central criticism of pop
  is usually that it is not as interesting and emotionally engaging as other genres,
  and its over-commercialisation. If I were to start decrying everything I thought
  was unnecessarily commercialised, there wouldn't be a whole lot left. And just
  because something isn't emotionally engaging to me, especially given my melancholy
  disposition, doesn't mean it's not a valid art form.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Besides, I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; actually like some pop songs and artists, I'm just too proud
  to admit it. The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AX3Bsiq-13k&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  Dua Lipa feat Blackpink song&lt;/a&gt; is awesome - admittedly I unashamedly loved Blackpink
  before hearing it. I adored &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Alice Merton's
  No Roots&lt;/a&gt; which was all over the radio last year.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCiGm_E4ZwYSHV3bcW1pnSeQ&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Billie Eilish&lt;/a&gt;
  is as much my Sad Queen as anyone else's. I am a big fan of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/Marinaandthediamonds&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marina and the Diamonds,&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/kimbramusic&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kimbra,&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/LordeMusic&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lorde,&lt;/a&gt;
  and the aforementioned
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/Grimezsz&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Grimes.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Maybe if I got over myself and listened to more of it, I'd be happier. Everyone
  else must like it for a reason.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html">In a recent post I talked about my pathological contrarianism and my need to dislike things people like to fuel some narcisstic superiority complex. It is, obviously, a negative quality to possess and one I would duly like to correct. So today, I'd like to briefly admit that I actually quite like some pop music. Having watched this video with pop musician and producer Grimes, I was struck by something she said in one of the clips. For her, it was an obvious choice to pursue pop, despite any criticims that it's a vapid or unfulfilling genre, because it's primary focus is the listeners happiness, or in her words: It's music that just seeks to hit the pleasure centre. And really, if I was critical of something with such pure intentions (let's pretend capitalism isn't a thing), I would be the asshole. My central criticism of pop is usually that it is not as interesting and emotionally engaging as other genres, and its over-commercialisation. If I were to start decrying everything I thought was unnecessarily commercialised, there wouldn't be a whole lot left. And just because something isn't emotionally engaging to me, especially given my melancholy disposition, doesn't mean it's not a valid art form. Besides, I do actually like some pop songs and artists, I'm just too proud to admit it. The new Dua Lipa feat Blackpink song is awesome - admittedly I unashamedly loved Blackpink before hearing it. I adored Alice Merton's No Roots which was all over the radio last year. Billie Eilish is as much my Sad Queen as anyone else's. I am a big fan of Marina and the Diamonds, Kimbra, Lorde, and the aforementioned Grimes. Maybe if I got over myself and listened to more of it, I'd be happier. Everyone else must like it for a reason.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When it's easy, it's easy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/09/when-its-easy-its-easy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When it&amp;#39;s easy&amp;#44; it&amp;#39;s easy" /><published>2019-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/09/when-its-easy-its-easy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/09/when-its-easy-its-easy">&lt;p&gt;
  For the last 10 days I've been far less depressed than usual. So much so, you
  might say that for the last 10 days I haven't been depressed &lt;i&gt;at all.&lt;/i&gt; Neat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One thing that strikes me about not being constantly fucking miserable is
  how easier pretty much everything is. It's easier to get up and go to bed earlier,
  it's easier to eat healthier, to go to the gym, to talk to friends. It's easier to
  sit down and write these posts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  When I feel down, I still want to do all those things, but they take a lot of
  willpower. Even though they are relatively basic, getting them all done can
  take a lot out of me. Thinking about it now, I think this is one of the worst
  aspect of depression - performing simple tasks, tasks that you want to
  do, which will make you happier, becomes exhausting and can feel impossible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Whenever I'm in a period of time where I'm vaguely mentally healthy, I usually
  have two goals; firstly, to enjoy it fully, and secondly, to try to prepare for
  the next time things go south. I'm doing a pretty good job of the former, and I
  want to progress with the latter, particularly in relation to making the basics
  less tiresome. Other than trying to be disciplined, build routines and internalise
  the habits as much as possible... I am open to suggestions.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Mental Health" /><summary type="html">For the last 10 days I've been far less depressed than usual. So much so, you might say that for the last 10 days I haven't been depressed at all. Neat. One thing that strikes me about not being constantly fucking miserable is how easier pretty much everything is. It's easier to get up and go to bed earlier, it's easier to eat healthier, to go to the gym, to talk to friends. It's easier to sit down and write these posts. When I feel down, I still want to do all those things, but they take a lot of willpower. Even though they are relatively basic, getting them all done can take a lot out of me. Thinking about it now, I think this is one of the worst aspect of depression - performing simple tasks, tasks that you want to do, which will make you happier, becomes exhausting and can feel impossible. Whenever I'm in a period of time where I'm vaguely mentally healthy, I usually have two goals; firstly, to enjoy it fully, and secondly, to try to prepare for the next time things go south. I'm doing a pretty good job of the former, and I want to progress with the latter, particularly in relation to making the basics less tiresome. Other than trying to be disciplined, build routines and internalise the habits as much as possible... I am open to suggestions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Repeated Mistakes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Repeated Mistakes" /><published>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/01/08/repeated-mistakes">&lt;p&gt;
  Yesterday was my first session back in the gym after two weeks off, due to
  the holiday season and being ill. The building is a converted warehouse, so there's no
  heating and it's very cold in the winter, so even if you warm up, taking long rests
  in between sets can cause your temperature to drop quite quickly. Between
  that, still not being over my illness, and diving straight back into my
  programme after a fortnight's break, I should have been cogniscent of having
  a much higher injury risk than normal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are no prizes for guessing what I did next. After 3 of 5 of my sets of
  squats, I felt my right hamstring become incredibly tight, and considered
  whether or not to continue. I knew it was the sensible thing to stop and doing
  something else, but for whatever reason I didn't, and proceeded to do my
  last two sets while trying to load my right leg as little as possible - hardly ideal for squatting. I
  massively compensated using my back and today it's inflamed and very painful;
  walking is difficult and I had to skip the gym. I saw this coming,
  so why did still I make the decision I did?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Obviously it was calulcated risk - injury wasn't a certainty. But I have
  been injured in this exact scenario before, so it was highly probable. My
  decision making process broke down, and there are several reasons for that:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      ego - not finishing would be 'weak' mentally, and in this case physically;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      desire for improvement - I am not content with where I am presently in my
      training, and I know I need to do the sets to get to where I want to be. I
      can't afford to make excuses, or I will not progess;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      guilt - I'd just taken two weeks off, I need to make up for lost time;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      expectation - I'd already set my expectations to do the whole session that
      evening, I did not want to fall short;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      laziness (of a kind) - making a conscious effort to change your plan takes
      effort, and a lot of times it is easier to simply stick with the way things
      are and deal with any potential consequences later.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Of course, this is a relatively minor example of a bad decision. But, life is a
  series of decisions, and this one was something of a trap - furthermore, a trap
  I think we all fall victim to. Humans repeat their own poor decisions with such
  frequency that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/surprised-pikachu&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  meme flavour of the month is very much dedicated to it (and a personal favourite
  of mine too).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  If I can improve the mushy grey inference engine between my ears then perhaps
  I will become a better, happier person. Another very human trait is to shirk
  our responsibility to confront our mistakes (especially if this isn't the first time we've made them),
  and simply tell ourselves we will do better next time. Perhaps this sounds familiar
  to you. But I think autopsying those decisions can provide a huge amount of value
  and direction on how to overcome wider issues in your life. I guess I just gotta
  get my hands dirty more often.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Health and Fitness" /><summary type="html">Yesterday was my first session back in the gym after two weeks off, due to the holiday season and being ill. The building is a converted warehouse, so there's no heating and it's very cold in the winter, so even if you warm up, taking long rests in between sets can cause your temperature to drop quite quickly. Between that, still not being over my illness, and diving straight back into my programme after a fortnight's break, I should have been cogniscent of having a much higher injury risk than normal. There are no prizes for guessing what I did next. After 3 of 5 of my sets of squats, I felt my right hamstring become incredibly tight, and considered whether or not to continue. I knew it was the sensible thing to stop and doing something else, but for whatever reason I didn't, and proceeded to do my last two sets while trying to load my right leg as little as possible - hardly ideal for squatting. I massively compensated using my back and today it's inflamed and very painful; walking is difficult and I had to skip the gym. I saw this coming, so why did still I make the decision I did? Obviously it was calulcated risk - injury wasn't a certainty. But I have been injured in this exact scenario before, so it was highly probable. My decision making process broke down, and there are several reasons for that: ego - not finishing would be 'weak' mentally, and in this case physically; desire for improvement - I am not content with where I am presently in my training, and I know I need to do the sets to get to where I want to be. I can't afford to make excuses, or I will not progess; guilt - I'd just taken two weeks off, I need to make up for lost time; expectation - I'd already set my expectations to do the whole session that evening, I did not want to fall short; laziness (of a kind) - making a conscious effort to change your plan takes effort, and a lot of times it is easier to simply stick with the way things are and deal with any potential consequences later. Of course, this is a relatively minor example of a bad decision. But, life is a series of decisions, and this one was something of a trap - furthermore, a trap I think we all fall victim to. Humans repeat their own poor decisions with such frequency that the meme flavour of the month is very much dedicated to it (and a personal favourite of mine too). If I can improve the mushy grey inference engine between my ears then perhaps I will become a better, happier person. Another very human trait is to shirk our responsibility to confront our mistakes (especially if this isn't the first time we've made them), and simply tell ourselves we will do better next time. Perhaps this sounds familiar to you. But I think autopsying those decisions can provide a huge amount of value and direction on how to overcome wider issues in your life. I guess I just gotta get my hands dirty more often.</summary></entry></feed>