<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Folding at Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve deliberately refrained from writing about &lt;em&gt;la grippe du jour&lt;/em&gt; because it feels
like it’s all anyone else is writing about and I am forever a contrarian, however
today’s post is at least somewhat related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that SETI@home has gone into ‘hibernation’ while Berkeley scientists focus on
analysing their existing dataset, which admittedly must be pretty huge by now, and
given cryptos recent swan dive back to pre-2017 prices, there’s huge swathes of GPUs
simply idling across the globe, when they could all be doing their tiny little part
to better society. One pretty neat way to do so is to join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://foldingathome.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Folding@home&lt;/a&gt; party and put your spare processor cycles to
work by simulating protein folding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DeepMind recently brought &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepmind.com/blog/article/AlphaFold-Using-AI-for-scientific-discovery&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;protein folding to the attention of the wider tech community&lt;/a&gt; and while I won’t
pretend to understand any of the biochemistry involve, the computing aspect is pretty
interesting, and it’s an application of modern technology that is refreshing not-evil.
Sure, I might not have quite the hardware that Google are hooking DeepMind up with
to achieve such stellar results, but the idea that the handful of proteins I can
compute on my lowly GTX 970 might contribute to research into the &lt;em&gt;C-Word&lt;/em&gt; warms
my soul a little.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/14/folding-at-home</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/14/folding-at-home</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hand Anger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I was enjoying the recent uptick in player liquidity on Run It Once and was happily clicking buttons when a particular hand made me really &lt;em&gt;angry&lt;/em&gt;. The nice thing about
being a fun player is that now I can simply stop playing, take a step back and evaluate why exactly this hand irked me so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hand went as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Folds to hero in CO with AhKhQc8d, raises to 3.5bb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BTN calls, blinds fold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flop Ks8s2x hero bets 4.5bb, villain calls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;turn Ks8s2xAs pot 16.5bb, hero checks, villain bets 11bb, hero calls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;river Ks8s2xAs2x pot 38.5bb hero pots, villain calls and tables…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T663sssx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction is to inwardly chastise villain for making such a bad play - I think preflop is definitely -EV and every other street is at best breakeven. Why am I so angry?
It’s a sense of entitlement, one of the ways ego manifests itself in poker, because he made a ‘bad’ play, he doesn’t deserve to win my money. But maybe he had a sick read on me,
he felt he could outplay me in position despite having mediocre holdings, perhaps my large lead OTR was actually a lot more exploitable than I had thought. It’s also a spot
where in reality I think I am making a lot of EV, just in this case I happened to lose actual money. Even after a couple of million hands of poker, those spots still hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much my poker mental game is influenced by my mental health off the felt. If I needed less external validation, the kind I might get from winning money at poker and
thus proving some kind of intellectual superiority, I can’t help but feel that these spots wouldn’t tilt me so much. The obvious &lt;em&gt;sequitur&lt;/em&gt; is that I should work on my IRL
mental game and then things will fall into place at the tables, but perhaps the reverse might also be true?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/13/hand-anger</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/13/hand-anger</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nietzsche Quotes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was taking to a friend and referenced an aphorism which I then duly attributed to everybody’s favourite German
cultural critic Friedrich Nietzsche. Except for the fact that I got it wrong, and missed out an important clause which
added very necessary context. And I completely misinterpreted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson here is to not try and quote Nietzsche to your friends (or to anyone for that matter) because the only possible
outcome is that you end up looking like a pretentious twat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/12/nietzsche-quotes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/12/nietzsche-quotes</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Hour of Nothing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First off, I am attempting to write this post in nano, and if that doesn’t make me a real developer then I don’t know what does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, this week I am trying out a new rule for myself (rule sounds a little bit draconian - let’s call it a &lt;em&gt;heuristic&lt;/em&gt; instead). Every day I have to spend a whole hour
doing something unproductive. No work, no exercise, no cooking, no cleaning, no writing a blog post, no nothing. A whole hour of being a vegetable in some way, shape or form,
contributing nothing whatsoever to society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/11/an-hour-of-nothing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/11/an-hour-of-nothing</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You're Welcome, Ted</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine trying to write a blog post needling one of your friends, but then misspelling misstepped and
not resizing any of your images so they all overflow their containers. It’s truly remarkable I managed
to lose a bet to someone like that…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you’re welcome, and don’t worry, I’ll be dining on your dollar in return soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/10/youre-welcome-ted</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/10/youre-welcome-ted</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open-Jaw Flights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Extracting maximum value from flights seems to be something of a dark art, and there is a whole world
of airmiles, alliances and error fares to try and wrap one’s head around. Airfare pricing in general
still seems completely nonsenical to me, but today I discovered the existence of so-caled “open-jaw” 
flights, which could prove to be an important piece of the affordable travel puzzle. For example, a
direct flight from Edinburgh to NYC with Delta, one way - £1700. But a multi-city roundtrip, with
the return flight from Las Vegas to London? £500 for both flights. I assume they make the one-way
prices ridiculous to incentivise flying both ways on the same carrier, but still, 3.5x seems nuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m glad I’ve learned about this one small machination of the aviation industry. As I dive deeper
down the rabbit hole, I’m sure I’ll provide more details of GTO flying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/09/openjaw-flights</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/09/openjaw-flights</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Itachi Uchiha</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about what kind of man I want to be lately, and looking for suitable male role models in our post-feminist age. It struck me while running today that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Itachi_Uchiha&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Itachi Uchicha&lt;/a&gt;, while not quite being a role model per se (not least because of his fictitious nature), embodies many qualities that I aspire
to. He’s a man who is willing to do what must be done - one trait from old male archetypes I think worth still praising - he puts his brother before anything, has a bulletproof sense of 
loyalty and honour, he’s smart, and he’s an insanely powerful ninja who can set things on fire with his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the last one is less than attainable, but I quite like the rest of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/08/itachi-uchiha</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/08/itachi-uchiha</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Food is Food for the Soul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of my coworkers have started drinking &lt;a href=&quot;https://huel.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Huel&lt;/a&gt; as part of their diet, and for a while I seriously considered joining them. It seems like a way to
regulate my caloric intake with relatively little mental effort required, and I still haven’t broken the habit of thinking that my self esteem is inversely proportional to my weight. After
giving it some thought, I rejected the idea; life is far, far too short not to eat food. Even if in many ways I have an unhealthy relationship with food, that doesn’t mean that all of it is
impure, unthinking and devoid of wholesomeness - perhaps recognising those moments and leaning into them more could even be a catalyst for better overall eating patterns?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this post is really just my way of trying to justify to myself that I’ve been out for breakfast and lunch already today, and I’m going out for dinner later. I’m not even sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/07/food-is-food-for-the-soul</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/07/food-is-food-for-the-soul</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Puppeteer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finally had the chance to play around with Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/puppeteer/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Puppeteer,&lt;/a&gt; it’s nifty Node library for manipulating a Chrome browser via API, head
optional. It’s a powerful tool for automation, and getting it hooked up
to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; in order to automate website audits was virtually
painless. I’ll definitely be using it a lot more to write tests for
my projects, expect to see some cools things in my repos soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/06/puppeteer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/06/puppeteer</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sometimes Laziness Pays Off</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning it seems like Flybe are poised to immediately cease being
an airline, and with it, thousands of promises to fly someone from A to
B will vanish into the ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning a lot of flights in the near future, but for once, my
laziness has been a boon - I haven’t got round to booking any of them
yet, unlike some of my friends, who have awoken this morning to find
that they’re going to need to further dent their bank balance. Hehehe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/05/sometimes-laziness-pays-off</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/05/sometimes-laziness-pays-off</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>