<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-08T08:27:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jonny Spicer | Thoughts From Tartarus</title><subtitle>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thoughts and Words</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/08/thoughts-and-words" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts and Words" /><published>2019-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/08/thoughts-and-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/08/thoughts-and-words">&lt;p&gt;Unless you’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TM427B7qerE&quot;&gt;that weird Radical Honesty dude&lt;/a&gt;,
then there is a significant gap between the thoughts and feelings you experience
and the words you use to communicate them to the world around you. It seems
intuitive to me that in general, the smaller the gap, the happier the person.
Mine is definitely significantly larger than I would like it to be, and I feel
like I am constantly trying to make it smaller - but it is a steep mountain to
climb, and I am very scared to do so. I suppose I will have to channel my inner
&lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/03/31/celeste&quot;&gt;Madeline&lt;/a&gt; and get it done though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">Unless you’re that weird Radical Honesty dude, then there is a significant gap between the thoughts and feelings you experience and the words you use to communicate them to the world around you. It seems intuitive to me that in general, the smaller the gap, the happier the person. Mine is definitely significantly larger than I would like it to be, and I feel like I am constantly trying to make it smaller - but it is a steep mountain to climb, and I am very scared to do so. I suppose I will have to channel my inner Madeline and get it done though.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Land of the Free</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/07/land-of-the-free" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Land of the Free" /><published>2019-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/07/land-of-the-free</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/07/land-of-the-free">&lt;p&gt;
  I've now spent roughly one whole day in the land of the free (not as in beer).
  My impressions so far are largely that everything is just much bigger here...
  the cars, the coffee cups, the government public debt. I'm pretty sure I even saw
  the biggest flag I've ever seen yesterday, proudly flying high above the
  idyllic Port Jefferson. The people have been very friendly so far, and nobody
  has interrogated me about my English accent either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This morning we are embarking on one of what I hope will be many authentic American
  experiences - the diner breakfast. I've been told that essentially everything
  on the menu is excellent and so I am sure I will inevitably be transfixed
  by the paralysis that comes with excessive choice, but hopefully the bottomless
  coffee will be enough to snap me out of it and see me through.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And then this afternoon, we will be moving on to the main event for the day -
  several wine tastings at several vineyards. As far as I can tell, binge
  drinking culture is far less ingrained in the average American psyche - perhaps
  I will be able to show them the light?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">I've now spent roughly one whole day in the land of the free (not as in beer). My impressions so far are largely that everything is just much bigger here... the cars, the coffee cups, the government public debt. I'm pretty sure I even saw the biggest flag I've ever seen yesterday, proudly flying high above the idyllic Port Jefferson. The people have been very friendly so far, and nobody has interrogated me about my English accent either. This morning we are embarking on one of what I hope will be many authentic American experiences - the diner breakfast. I've been told that essentially everything on the menu is excellent and so I am sure I will inevitably be transfixed by the paralysis that comes with excessive choice, but hopefully the bottomless coffee will be enough to snap me out of it and see me through. And then this afternoon, we will be moving on to the main event for the day - several wine tastings at several vineyards. As far as I can tell, binge drinking culture is far less ingrained in the average American psyche - perhaps I will be able to show them the light?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yet Another Post About Losing Weight</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/06/yet-another-post-about-losing-weight" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yet Another Post About Losing Weight" /><published>2019-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/06/yet-another-post-about-losing-weight</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/06/yet-another-post-about-losing-weight">&lt;p&gt;
  I am going to get to under 83kg if it is the last thing I do. Well, not quite,
  because I am similarly determined to achieve my goal through healthy means,
  so ideally it will not even be close to the last thing I do, but you know
  what I mean.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Whenever I write one of these posts, I am acutely aware of how many predecessors
  they have, in both blog and oral form. I must sound deluded at this point,
  long past the point of naivete. The question is, as always, what am I going to
  do differently? I am still convinced that if I try enough strategies, one will
  eventually work for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There are a couple of answers this time. The first two are relatively small
  and easy - to try to meal prep larger portions (so less potential to snack/binge
  outside of these) and to try to apply &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/2016/04/second-order-thinking/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  seconrd-order thinking&lt;/a&gt; to the problems of dieting. The biggest change,
  undoubtedly the most difficult to enact but equally the most likely to produce
  meaningful results, is to better handle the emotions that cause my frequent
  bouts of comfort eating, which for the past few months has been stress. My
  specific stress-reduction plan will have to wait for another day though, as I have
  a plane to catch!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Diet and Fitness" /><summary type="html">I am going to get to under 83kg if it is the last thing I do. Well, not quite, because I am similarly determined to achieve my goal through healthy means, so ideally it will not even be close to the last thing I do, but you know what I mean. Whenever I write one of these posts, I am acutely aware of how many predecessors they have, in both blog and oral form. I must sound deluded at this point, long past the point of naivete. The question is, as always, what am I going to do differently? I am still convinced that if I try enough strategies, one will eventually work for me. There are a couple of answers this time. The first two are relatively small and easy - to try to meal prep larger portions (so less potential to snack/binge outside of these) and to try to apply seconrd-order thinking to the problems of dieting. The biggest change, undoubtedly the most difficult to enact but equally the most likely to produce meaningful results, is to better handle the emotions that cause my frequent bouts of comfort eating, which for the past few months has been stress. My specific stress-reduction plan will have to wait for another day though, as I have a plane to catch!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Adventure Begins</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/05/the-adventure-begins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Adventure Begins" /><published>2019-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/05/the-adventure-begins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/05/the-adventure-begins">&lt;p&gt;
  Today a new adventure begins, and I couldn't be more excited. This time tomorrow
  I'll be in Heathrow airport, eagerly waiting to board a flight to JFK airport
  and explore New York, one of the greatest cities in the world (allegedly). It
  will be my second trip there, but I undertook the first when I was 3 years old,
  so that doesn't really count. I'm going to subside solely on pizza, cheesecake,
  and shitty American piss-beer, and my goal is to perfect my caricaturish Yank
  accent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Bizarrely, I have much less anxiety about the journey now then I did a couple
  of weeks ago - my worries of being depressed and bringing my fellow travelers
  down have evaporated, and now I suspect the opposite is going to be true.
  I am ready to be inspired by the places and people around me, and I think
  it has potential to be a transformative experience - at this point I can't
  wait to get on the plane.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">Today a new adventure begins, and I couldn't be more excited. This time tomorrow I'll be in Heathrow airport, eagerly waiting to board a flight to JFK airport and explore New York, one of the greatest cities in the world (allegedly). It will be my second trip there, but I undertook the first when I was 3 years old, so that doesn't really count. I'm going to subside solely on pizza, cheesecake, and shitty American piss-beer, and my goal is to perfect my caricaturish Yank accent. Bizarrely, I have much less anxiety about the journey now then I did a couple of weeks ago - my worries of being depressed and bringing my fellow travelers down have evaporated, and now I suspect the opposite is going to be true. I am ready to be inspired by the places and people around me, and I think it has potential to be a transformative experience - at this point I can't wait to get on the plane.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Glut</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/04/book-glut" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Glut" /><published>2019-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/04/book-glut</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/04/book-glut">&lt;p&gt;
  Today I lost all self control and bought far, far too many books. It will take
  me years to read all these, and it is slightly upsetting to me that I will
  inevitably achieve that - hopefully I can find the motivation to try
  though. In case you were wondering, here they are:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Master and Margarita - Mikhail Bulgakov&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Complete Novels of Fyodor Dostoyevsky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Complete Novels of Leo Tolstoy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Complete Novels of George Orwell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Collected Works of Rene Descartes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Collected Works of Friedrich Wilhelm Nietzsche&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Complete Works of Plato&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Complete Works of James Joyce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Essential Jung: Selected Writings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Search of Lost Time (7 Book Collection) - Marcel Proust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infinite Jest - David Foster Wallace&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Happy Death - Albert Camus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Outsider - Albert Camus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Myth of Sisyphus - Albert Camus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Plague - Albert Camus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Things You Should Already Know About Dating, You Fucking Idiot - Ben Schwartz &amp; Laura Moses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Drunkard's Walk - Leonard Mlodinow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lolita - Vladimir Nabokov&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foundation - Isaac Asimov&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foundation and Empire - Isaac Asimov&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dead Souls - Nikolay Gogol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eugene Onegin - Alexander Pushkin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tales of Belkin - Alexander Pushkin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doctor Zhivago - Boris Pasternak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flowers For Algernon - Daniel Keyes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Grapes Of Wrath - John Steinbeck&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;East of Eden - John Steinbeck&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lord of the Flies - William Golding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Factfulness - Hans Rosling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistics Done Wrong - Alex Reinhart&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Jujitsu - DJ Patil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ethics and Data Science - Mike Loukides, Hilary Mason &amp; DJ Patil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strangers Drowning - Larissa MacFarquhar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Divine Comedy - Dante Aligheri&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moscow Stations - Venedikt Yerofeev&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python For Everybody - Charles Severance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html">Today I lost all self control and bought far, far too many books. It will take me years to read all these, and it is slightly upsetting to me that I will inevitably achieve that - hopefully I can find the motivation to try though. In case you were wondering, here they are: The Master and Margarita - Mikhail Bulgakov The Complete Novels of Fyodor Dostoyevsky The Complete Novels of Leo Tolstoy The Complete Novels of George Orwell The Collected Works of Rene Descartes The Collected Works of Friedrich Wilhelm Nietzsche The Complete Works of Plato The Complete Works of James Joyce The Essential Jung: Selected Writings In Search of Lost Time (7 Book Collection) - Marcel Proust Infinite Jest - David Foster Wallace A Happy Death - Albert Camus The Outsider - Albert Camus The Myth of Sisyphus - Albert Camus The Plague - Albert Camus Things You Should Already Know About Dating, You Fucking Idiot - Ben Schwartz &amp; Laura Moses The Drunkard's Walk - Leonard Mlodinow Lolita - Vladimir Nabokov Foundation - Isaac Asimov Foundation and Empire - Isaac Asimov Dead Souls - Nikolay Gogol Eugene Onegin - Alexander Pushkin Tales of Belkin - Alexander Pushkin Doctor Zhivago - Boris Pasternak Flowers For Algernon - Daniel Keyes The Grapes Of Wrath - John Steinbeck East of Eden - John Steinbeck Lord of the Flies - William Golding Factfulness - Hans Rosling Statistics Done Wrong - Alex Reinhart Data Jujitsu - DJ Patil Ethics and Data Science - Mike Loukides, Hilary Mason &amp; DJ Patil Strangers Drowning - Larissa MacFarquhar The Divine Comedy - Dante Aligheri Moscow Stations - Venedikt Yerofeev Python For Everybody - Charles Severance</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 3, 2011 III</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/03/october-3-2011-iii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 3, 2011 III" /><published>2019-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/03/october-3-2011-iii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/03/october-3-2011-iii">&lt;p&gt;
  I suppose now it's my turn.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I've been in my new place about two months now, and living with one of my best
  friends has been amazing. Coming home from work and being able to hang out
  with one of your buddies who will make you laugh after a rough day is incredible
  and has made me life better. We're surrounded by older, more successful people -
  my shitty car sticks out like a sore thumb in a garage full of Porsches and
  Mercedes - but I don't mind. In a way, it is funny to me that I am living in
  the same place as them, perhaps it makes me feel successful already.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Recently my only motivation has been simple, to be. I spent far too much time
  thinking and doing, and not enough time simply being, but now I am conscious
  of that, I already find myself enjoying innumerable small moments of joy
  that would've otherwise passed me by. I hope this motivation does not wane.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I really want to help out my brother. We've always been really close too, and
  similarly, I think he deserves to be happier than he is. I want to spend more
  time and invest more effort into him, because I love him more than anything in
  the world. I guess that makes him my pet project as well - although I don't
  think he is in the top quartile for open-mindedness in 16 year olds. Hopefully
  I can learn to love trying to help him.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I suppose now it's my turn. I've been in my new place about two months now, and living with one of my best friends has been amazing. Coming home from work and being able to hang out with one of your buddies who will make you laugh after a rough day is incredible and has made me life better. We're surrounded by older, more successful people - my shitty car sticks out like a sore thumb in a garage full of Porsches and Mercedes - but I don't mind. In a way, it is funny to me that I am living in the same place as them, perhaps it makes me feel successful already. Recently my only motivation has been simple, to be. I spent far too much time thinking and doing, and not enough time simply being, but now I am conscious of that, I already find myself enjoying innumerable small moments of joy that would've otherwise passed me by. I hope this motivation does not wane. I really want to help out my brother. We've always been really close too, and similarly, I think he deserves to be happier than he is. I want to spend more time and invest more effort into him, because I love him more than anything in the world. I guess that makes him my pet project as well - although I don't think he is in the top quartile for open-mindedness in 16 year olds. Hopefully I can learn to love trying to help him.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 3, 2011 II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/02/october-3-2011-ii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 3, 2011 II" /><published>2019-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/02/october-3-2011-ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/02/october-3-2011-ii">&lt;p&gt;
  Dear Ted,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  When I posted the oldest blog I could find of yours for April Fool's Day, I was
  of course trying to wind you up a little, although I hope you don't think that
  I was mocking you or the post, because actually I love it. Posts like this
  are exactly the reason we made that bet in the first place, and even if you
  may have cringed a little rereading it (I'm happy to report your spelling has
  improved significantly in the past 8.5 years), I hope you enjoy it at least
  some fraction of the amount I do.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It's candid and vulnerable and even if it might not be the most prosaic thing
  in the entire world, I wish more people communicated like this. It shows
  what's changed over time, something which is easily forgotten, and probably
  kept you at least a little accountable along the way. I'd love to read an
  updated version of it, and I hope I enjoy reading my old posts in the future
  as much as I enjoyed this one of yours.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Blogging" /><summary type="html">Dear Ted, When I posted the oldest blog I could find of yours for April Fool's Day, I was of course trying to wind you up a little, although I hope you don't think that I was mocking you or the post, because actually I love it. Posts like this are exactly the reason we made that bet in the first place, and even if you may have cringed a little rereading it (I'm happy to report your spelling has improved significantly in the past 8.5 years), I hope you enjoy it at least some fraction of the amount I do. It's candid and vulnerable and even if it might not be the most prosaic thing in the entire world, I wish more people communicated like this. It shows what's changed over time, something which is easily forgotten, and probably kept you at least a little accountable along the way. I'd love to read an updated version of it, and I hope I enjoy reading my old posts in the future as much as I enjoyed this one of yours.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">October 3, 2011</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/01/october-3-2011" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="October 3, 2011" /><published>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/01/october-3-2011</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/04/01/october-3-2011">&lt;p&gt;
  I want to write down my thoughts somewhere where I wont be able to loose them or
  throw them away.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I moved in to my new place today. Living with some hippy lady and her crazy
  amount of animals. Who has a goose. I think it will go somewhere great and okay;
  time will tell.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Lately I have been very motivated. But the problem every week it is another thing.
  One week it's fitness, the next it is school, then golf, now saving/earning money.
  Guess it's better than not being motivated at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Recently I have been trying to help out my grandpa. We have always been really
  close. He is not all that happy with his life, in my opinion. And i'm trying
  to get him back on track. If anybody deserves to be happy, without a doubt, it
  is him. He is my pet project for the foreseeable future. Its going good so far
  but we got a ways to go. At least he is intelligent and open-minded, I would imagine
  change stands no chance verse most 78 year old men. Not him. I love him and
  love trying to help him.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I want to write down my thoughts somewhere where I wont be able to loose them or throw them away. I moved in to my new place today. Living with some hippy lady and her crazy amount of animals. Who has a goose. I think it will go somewhere great and okay; time will tell. Lately I have been very motivated. But the problem every week it is another thing. One week it's fitness, the next it is school, then golf, now saving/earning money. Guess it's better than not being motivated at all. Recently I have been trying to help out my grandpa. We have always been really close. He is not all that happy with his life, in my opinion. And i'm trying to get him back on track. If anybody deserves to be happy, without a doubt, it is him. He is my pet project for the foreseeable future. Its going good so far but we got a ways to go. At least he is intelligent and open-minded, I would imagine change stands no chance verse most 78 year old men. Not him. I love him and love trying to help him.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celeste</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/31/celeste" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celeste" /><published>2019-03-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/31/celeste</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/31/celeste">&lt;p&gt;
  I finally got round to playing (and beating) Celeste after having not given it
  the attention that it deserves for roughly a year. Now that I have, I'm incredibly
  glad I did so - this game is engaging, challenging and gorgeous. The gameplay is
  great, a solid and polished platformer with some interesting mechanics, but what
  really shines is the story. I can't remember the last time I was so emotionally
  involved in a single player experience like this - Celeste hit worryingly close
  to him and I was moved to tears on multiple occasions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I was aware beforehand that the themes in the game were mental health-ish, but
  when I began playing and realised that my objective was not only to climb
  Celeste Mountain but was also to overcome the protagonist's anxieties and self
  doubt, it quickly became analagous to my own life. After only playing for an hour
  or so, I knew I was going to have to complete the entire game, no matter how
  long it took - not overcoming Madeline's internal demons felt like it would be
  losing to my own.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  A truly remarkable game, thoroughly worthy of the deluge of praise it has
  experienced since its inception, and birthed from a game jam no less! Now to
  get all the collectibles...
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Games" /><summary type="html">I finally got round to playing (and beating) Celeste after having not given it the attention that it deserves for roughly a year. Now that I have, I'm incredibly glad I did so - this game is engaging, challenging and gorgeous. The gameplay is great, a solid and polished platformer with some interesting mechanics, but what really shines is the story. I can't remember the last time I was so emotionally involved in a single player experience like this - Celeste hit worryingly close to him and I was moved to tears on multiple occasions. I was aware beforehand that the themes in the game were mental health-ish, but when I began playing and realised that my objective was not only to climb Celeste Mountain but was also to overcome the protagonist's anxieties and self doubt, it quickly became analagous to my own life. After only playing for an hour or so, I knew I was going to have to complete the entire game, no matter how long it took - not overcoming Madeline's internal demons felt like it would be losing to my own. A truly remarkable game, thoroughly worthy of the deluge of praise it has experienced since its inception, and birthed from a game jam no less! Now to get all the collectibles...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/30/advice" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advice" /><published>2019-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/30/advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mendokusai/2019/03/30/advice">&lt;p&gt;
  Upon reflection, giving advice is a pretty interesting thing that we humans
  do, or at least the way we approach it is. I think by and large we do it pretty
  inefficiently, but aren't cogniscent of our own biases or lack of knowledge
  to realise our mistakes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Decision making is essentially about information - the more relevant information
  available, then by and large, the better the resulting decision will be.
  Giving advice is interesting because there is always an information mismatch,
  and the two parties will have differing experiences and knowledge on the matter
  at hand. Sometimes the amount of information is roughly equal, and sometimes
  one party simply has more information than the other. I think the majority
  of bad advice is borne of the giver having less than the receiver, although
  I could be swayed by the argument that in some edge cases less information
  could offer a certain amount of clarity compared to a large amount of unnecessary
  noise in the decision making process.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Conversely, when the giver has significantly more information than the receiver,
  the product is more often than not good advice - for example, if I were to ask
  my father for career advice. A particularly interesting flavour advice is that
  of relationship advice, where the informational mismatch is frequently huge. The
  giver essentially always has less advice than the receiver about the specific
  relationship, and relationships are full of complication and nuance. Perhaps
  the giver may have more experience with relationships in general, but intuitively
  I feel like he simply has less knowledge, but is unaware of that and happy
  to give advice regardless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Really, giving advice should be about pooling information, and effectively
  communicating any knowledge that you have to the other party, without necessarily
  giving advice per se. That way, even if there is a mismatch, the receiver can
  still reasonably benefit from the advice of the giver, and make a more informed
  decision.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This post, if you hadn't guessed, has been a result of recently receiving
  both awful and amazing advice.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonny Spicer</name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Upon reflection, giving advice is a pretty interesting thing that we humans do, or at least the way we approach it is. I think by and large we do it pretty inefficiently, but aren't cogniscent of our own biases or lack of knowledge to realise our mistakes. Decision making is essentially about information - the more relevant information available, then by and large, the better the resulting decision will be. Giving advice is interesting because there is always an information mismatch, and the two parties will have differing experiences and knowledge on the matter at hand. Sometimes the amount of information is roughly equal, and sometimes one party simply has more information than the other. I think the majority of bad advice is borne of the giver having less than the receiver, although I could be swayed by the argument that in some edge cases less information could offer a certain amount of clarity compared to a large amount of unnecessary noise in the decision making process. Conversely, when the giver has significantly more information than the receiver, the product is more often than not good advice - for example, if I were to ask my father for career advice. A particularly interesting flavour advice is that of relationship advice, where the informational mismatch is frequently huge. The giver essentially always has less advice than the receiver about the specific relationship, and relationships are full of complication and nuance. Perhaps the giver may have more experience with relationships in general, but intuitively I feel like he simply has less knowledge, but is unaware of that and happy to give advice regardless. Really, giving advice should be about pooling information, and effectively communicating any knowledge that you have to the other party, without necessarily giving advice per se. That way, even if there is a mismatch, the receiver can still reasonably benefit from the advice of the giver, and make a more informed decision. This post, if you hadn't guessed, has been a result of recently receiving both awful and amazing advice.</summary></entry></feed>