<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Food is Food for the Soul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of my coworkers have started drinking &lt;a href=&quot;https://huel.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Huel&lt;/a&gt; as part of their diet, and for a while I seriously considered joining them. It seems like a way to
regulate my caloric intake with relatively little mental effort required, and I still haven’t broken the habit of thinking that my self esteem is inversely proportional to my weight. After
giving it some thought, I rejected the idea; life is far, far too short not to eat food. Even if in many ways I have an unhealthy relationship with food, that doesn’t mean that all of it is
impure, unthinking and devoid of wholesomeness - perhaps recognising those moments and leaning into them more could even be a catalyst for better overall eating patterns?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this post is really just my way of trying to justify to myself that I’ve been out for breakfast and lunch already today, and I’m going out for dinner later. I’m not even sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/07/food-is-food-for-the-soul</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/07/food-is-food-for-the-soul</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Puppeteer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finally had the chance to play around with Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/puppeteer/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Puppeteer,&lt;/a&gt; it’s nifty Node library for manipulating a Chrome browser via API, head
optional. It’s a powerful tool for automation, and getting it hooked up
to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; in order to automate website audits was virtually
painless. I’ll definitely be using it a lot more to write tests for
my projects, expect to see some cools things in my repos soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/06/puppeteer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/06/puppeteer</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sometimes Laziness Pays Off</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning it seems like Flybe are poised to immediately cease being
an airline, and with it, thousands of promises to fly someone from A to
B will vanish into the ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning a lot of flights in the near future, but for once, my
laziness has been a boon - I haven’t got round to booking any of them
yet, unlike some of my friends, who have awoken this morning to find
that they’re going to need to further dent their bank balance. Hehehe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/05/sometimes-laziness-pays-off</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/05/sometimes-laziness-pays-off</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travis CI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I have finally got Travic set up for this site, thanks a lot to &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacquesdonnelly.github.io/posts/travis-ci/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jacques&lt;/a&gt; for the idea. For a free service
it’s quite impressive, and it integrates nicely with Jekyll and GitHub Pages. At the moment
all it does is run the generated static content through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gjtorikian/html-proofer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;htmlproofer,&lt;/a&gt; but that’s already dug up some links in old posts
that were broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is going to be getting GitHubt Actions setup, and that really will be the nail
in your ethereum coffin, slvrsluger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/04/travis-ci</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/04/travis-ci</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Disco Elysium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The game that I choose to accompany me on my journey through the barren &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2020/03/01/life-without-wifi&quot;&gt;internetless wasteland&lt;/a&gt; was ZA/UM’s isometric RPG, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zaumstudio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Disco Elysium.&lt;/a&gt; Had I realised earlier that it was heavily inspired by the  &lt;br /&gt;
Infinity Engine games of yore, then I think I would’ve found time to play it sooner, especially
given its widespread critical acclaim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt;. The art style is stunning (it’s quite reminiscent of Dishonored, another
gorgeous game), the sound design is excellent, and the dialogue is hilarious - I can’t remember a
game that has made me laugh out loud in the way Disco Elysium does. It’s self aware, meta AF and
wholly unafraid of breaking the fourth wall, which means it feels a lot like playing with an actual
DM. The gameplay is complex and challenging, and it genuinely feels like your choices matter as
you navigate both the open world of Revichol and the unique skill tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today is has also been nominated for six BAFTAs, both best game and best game design, and
I can absolutely see why. I will be sinking 100% of my free time into this until I have completed
it, and I could not recommend it more strongly - 9.5/10.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/03/disco-elysium</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/03/disco-elysium</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Victimhood Identity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I have got to know a certain &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2020/01/30/almost-smart&quot;&gt;almost smart&lt;/a&gt; individual even
better, and one of the things that they fail to be self aware about is how much of their identity
is built upon the notion that they are inherently a victim. Seeing it in another person was
incredibly jarring, and made me desperate to ensure that I don’t allow myself to fall into the
same trip (or at the very least - to not do so outwardly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem though is that sometimes I still need to talk about Bad Stuff - man feelings, etc -
but with a focus on doing so constructively and without self pity, I’ve suddenly found my
previously flourishing lexicon to have been diminished significantly. So, today begins a new
journey to learn a language to talk about such things again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/02/victimhood-identity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/02/victimhood-identity</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life Without Wifi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our ISP shit the bed today (again) and so we’re left without WiFi, at this point as much of a dietary staple as bread or coffee. In its absence, I found myself listing atop the ocean of distractions, teetering precariously on the brink of having to be alone
with my own thoughts. In order to fill the void, I booted up my Steam library, and was soon marvelling at the abundance of wonderful choices that I had - there were so many games here I wanted to play, and thought I would derive great joy from each. But for
some reason, whenever I have an internet connection, I always find something far less tangible to occupy me, something that seems to occupy a higher priority in my mind but is far more fleeting in nature. I truly believe video games are art, and I am
determined to make more time in my schedule for their consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/01/life-without-wifi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/03/01/life-without-wifi</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diabotical</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend is the first closed beta testing for Diabotical, the long-awaited (i.e. since 2013) arena FPS from former-Quake-pro-turned-esports-ass-turned-game-studio-owner,
James ‘2GD’ Harding. I backed this game on Kickstarter in the late 18th century and have been dutiful awaiting its arrival ever since, all the while my expectations increasing
inversely proportional to my hopes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my great surprise, Yames has actually delivered - Diabotical feels phenomenal. The engine, movement and weapon systems all flow smoothly and feel intuitive. The game manages
to give the impression that its skill ceiling is stratospheric, while still being fun and accessible for an AFPS rookie such as myself. The matchmaking system is, currently,
akin to being lit on fire and shot from a cannon into a vat of boiling pitch, but still, beggars can’t be choosers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they can fix the server issues (which admittedly is the whole point of the beta testing I’m currently participating in), Diabotical really could be a spiritual successor to
Quake, shiny and polished for the modern audience. I’m excited to see how many former pros come out of the woodwork to try their hand once some moeny starts being thrown at
tournaments, and I’m sure I’ll be tuning in to see the best in the world duke it out in Diabotical’s colourful frenzy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/29/diabotical</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/29/diabotical</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Satire's Golden Age</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are living in a bizarro timeline where satire and authenticity are homogenous and indistinguishable, such that the former is wholly effortless, and I worry that satire-as-an
-artform is soon to be lost to the sands of time. I recently watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CEVdca9U9LM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;We Like Sportz&lt;/a&gt;, a mere 11 years old, and
it already feels a little forced and somewhat out of place amongst today’s ultra-meta satirical landscape (although I still think it’s hilarious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the barrier for legitimately excellent satire is simply much higher, now it is easier to come by in mediocrity… Maybe if I ever get round to writing my novel, it’ll
be a caricaturish magnum opus. Did I mention I’m reading Infinite Jest?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/28/satires-golden-age</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/28/satires-golden-age</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Barkley Marathons II</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows what The Barkley Marathons is, knows that you have to be insane to enter it. To actually complete it, you have to be a physical and psychological freak of
nature - a case study for textbooks spanning a variety of fields - make sure you donate your body and brain to science after you die trying to swim across the Atlantic etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, there is Jared Campbell. His trail and ultrarunning CV is certainly impressive: he’s completed the legendary Hardrock 100 ten times, including winning it in 2010.
But it’s his accomplishments at the Barkley that mark him as a one-of-a-kind. He is one of only 15 people to have ever completed the Barkley Marathons, one of two to have
repeated that feat, and the only person to have made it through all 5 gruelling loops three times. And on top of all that… he keeps entering. He had to drop out last year
after his first loop because of an ankle injury. Why, when you accomplish something so utterly ludicrous as completing the Barkley, would you not be satisfied, nor when you
have done so twice or thrice, and you feel the need to repeatedly push yourself to the farthest extremes of your soul over and over?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat ironically, I think being the kind of person who will enter the Barkley after having already completed it three times is one of the few indicators that you are the
kind of person who might actually complete the infernal task a single time in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/27/the-barkley-marathons-ii</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2020/02/27/the-barkley-marathons-ii</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>