<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Jonny Spicer's personal website and blog, where he writes about mental health, technology, esports, but primarily trash.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Some Jumbled Reflections at 25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty five is a pretty cosy number for all us base 10 users. It only has prime factors. It can be part of a Pythagorean triplet.
It’s a multiple of 5, second only to multiples of 10 in terms of comfort of use. As a number, I think everyone would agree that it
is a good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as an age, I am struggling to say I find it quite so enjoyable. At least, so far - it’s only been a day. Perhaps it’ll grow
on me. My housemate turned 25 in September, and I think he summed it up best when I asked him how it felt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you’re younger, you look forward to your birthday. And then when you get a bit older, you’re not really excited about it anymore; it’s just like “oh, I’m getting old”. But this year it was like, “oh… fucking hell”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, my 25th birthday seems like as good an arbitrary point as any to bury a time capsule of my thoughts on the internet, and
so despite my recent absence from writing, I didn’t want to let this opportunity pass me by. Seeing as I haven’t written anything
for a while, there has naturally been plenty on my mind and plenty of things I could write about, but it’s all a bit jumbled, so
here are some rather disordered thoughts and faux-reflections on life, for the benefit and likely amusement of my future self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self esteem (something I crave) and arrogance (something I abhor) often seem like they might be two sides of the same coin. If you see some good quality in yourself
that you might derive self esteem from, there is inevitably a myriad of things you are not considering, with some inherent bluster and naivete, ergo, you are being
arrogant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a lot of situations in life, we get taught not to engage with our emotions, both explicitly or otherwise. In therapy, if you tell your therapist that you feel
hopeless and worthless, they may say to you that you do have worth, and that there is hope, and over time one learns that for some reason those feelings aren’t “real”.
Our emotions inform our actions though, and so if we stop engaging with our emotions because we are led to believe they are not proportionate or in touch with reality
or constitute part of some unforunate imbalance of brain chemistry, how then are we supposed to act, without our feelings to guide us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I was lucky enough to watch a video of the process of my friend painting a huge canvas. I didn’t have many expectations of what the video was going to be like
or how the painting would turn out, but it turned out to be an emotional journey. The painting was incredibly beautiful, and I felt a deep connection to its artist simply
by being party to its creation after the fact. It was a wholly unexpected, but very welcome inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of pain that we are capable of causing to people we love and care about is unintuitively large. Equally, sharing in the pain of those we love and care about
is one of the most life-affirming experiences possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgiveness is weird. I always thought it was about the other person, but it turns out that it’s about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, today is my annual listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YTFAXK-f4N4&quot;&gt;this masterpiece.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/11/08/some-jumbled-reflections-at-25</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/11/08/some-jumbled-reflections-at-25</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Reviews&amp;#58; Foundation by Isaac Asimov</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;52 books in 2019 is now well and truly out of reach, but I am hoping that with a mad dash effort in the last two months of the year,
I might still be able to make it to 12, which would be a respectable effort in my eyes. To that end, I wanted to read something
comparatively light and easy-going, so I choose to reattempt Isaac Asimov’s &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;, the first book in the trilogy bearing the
same name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been especially into sci-fi (although I’ve never been especially averse to it either), and have for a while now that it
is one of the few missing pieces in me becoming the complete nerd-puzzle. Asimov seems like a pretty great place to start, and
fortunately I knew I could get through &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; fairly quickly in order to accrue some more geek kudos. The book’s style is
interesting, relatively sparse on detail, but still more than capable of painting a vivid picture of a complex world very far 
removed from our own. I certainly felt immersed, and perhaps that was in part due to having to use my imagination to fill in some
of the gaps and add my own embellishments to the tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my main criticism of the novel has to be that a lot of Asimov’s characters are a little predictable and one-dimensional (not
withstanding the fact that the book doesn’t even come close to passing the Bechdel test), although perhaps that could be forgiven if
we note that Asimov arguably laid the groundwork for a lot of modern sci-fi tropes. Overall, pretty solid but not going to make it
into my favourite books ever, 7.5/10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books read this year: 5/52&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next book: Foundation &amp;amp; Empire by Isaac Asimov&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/21/book-reviews-foundation-by-isaac-asimov</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/21/book-reviews-foundation-by-isaac-asimov</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ineos 1&amp;#58;59 Challenge III&amp;#58; Inspiration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Kipchoge’s historic weekend caught the attention of more of the world than I’d anticipated - over 5 million people have watched the
video of the livestream on YouTube alone, most of my coworkers watched the event - even my mum did. The stated aim was to make
history, to inspire people, and to allow them to realise that they can do a lot more than they might think if they believe in
themselves that they can; in other words, our limits are arbitrary. With the event gaining a lot of mainstream attention, perhaps
it actually will capture hearts and minds, as hoped?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has certainly captured mine, as I have (probably naively) signed up for the Edinburgh Marathon in May. Motivation is at an all
time high at the moment, and while I am sure it won’t last forever (and indeed, might not last long at all given how rapidly the
cold, dark winter months are approaching), I am hoping having set a marathon as a goal will allow me to remain focused and
motivated, even when I don’t feel like putting my running shoes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the expense of being ultra-preachy, I have found running to be really good for my health. It’s difficult to put an objective
measure of its effect on me physically, but I have lost a meaningful amount of weight, and have clearly seen a significant 
improvement in my running ability, which hopefully correlates to better cardiovascular fitness and general health. It also
feels good for my mental health as well - I find it very difficult to be sad while I’m running. I’ve stopped listening to 
anything and simply allow myself to be alone with my thoughts, it provides a good opportunity to think things through and
try and gain some mental clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliud has certainly inspired me; in May we shall see if I have cultivated enough self belief to break my limits as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/18/ineos-159-challenge-iii-inspiration</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/18/ineos-159-challenge-iii-inspiration</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ineos 1&amp;#58;59 Challenge II&amp;#58; Results</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, the world watched as Eliud Kipchoge landed on the moon, running a full marathon in a time of 1:59:40.2, becoming the
first person to do so in under two hours. It isn’t an official record, because of the nature of the event - pacers swapped in and
out, multiple cars broke the wind for Kipchoge the whole way, and it wasn’t really a race per se. Regardless, Kipchoge’s achievement
is a monumental one, maintaining a blistering average pace of 2:50/km is a true testament to his endurance, and the limits of human
ability in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere in the Prater was electric - thousands of people lined the 4.3km stretch of road, and raucously cheered every time
Kipchoge and his team of pacers strode past. There were interviews (including from the Vice President of Kenya, the Mayor of Vienna,
and Chris Froome), music (most notably including Stronger by Kelly Clarkson, allegedly one of Eliud’s favourite songs) and big
screens showing his progress and kilometre splits. People were running and cycling on the adjacent paths for the whole event, and
it felt like a party atmosphere, a festival to celebrate running and the possibilities therein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I predicted that Kipchoge would do it, as did pretty much everyone else I have seen make a prediction, including the friends I
travelled to the event with. I still had some doubt though, I wasn’t 100% sure he would make it, until roughly 90 minutes in.
For the first handful of times that we’d watched the formation run past us, Kipchoge had looked laser-focused, in the zone,
contemplating only the task at hand. But as he ran past us after approximately 30km, to a voluminous cheer from the surrounding
crowd, he had an entirely different look on his face - a smile. They say that when he smiles, that is his way of dealing with
pain, and it is a sign he is struggling, but from where I was standing, it certainly didn’t look like that. It seemed to be the
smile of a man who knew exactly what he was about to accomplish, and that he was on the brink of making history, that nothing
could stop him now. Up until that point, we thought he would probably do it, but we didn’t &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; - I think he, however, knew
from the moment he stood on the start line that there was only one possible outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/17/ineos-159-challenge-ii-results</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/17/ineos-159-challenge-ii-results</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ineos 1&amp;#58;59 Challenge I&amp;#58; Predictions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is the Ineos 1:59 Challenge, where Eliud Kipchoge will attempt to be the first person to break the 2 hour marathon barrier,
making history in the process and proving that, as he says, no human is limited. The event will be held in Vienna (I am
incredibly excited to say that I will be flying there later today to watch), and it seems that Kipchoge and the Ineos team have
accounted for every variable they possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kipchoge is an inspiration, but not just for his athletic prowess, for his humility and sense of appreciation for the simple things
in life. He is a multimillionaire, but chooses to maintain the same lifestyle he had growing up in rural Kenya, working on his farm,
spending time with his family and sharing toilet-cleaning duties at his training camp with the rest of his team. He knows what makes
him happy, and he refuses to be taken in by any of the false promises undoubtedly being made to him as a result of his fame and
fortune. I’m jealous of him for that - I hope one day I will live as simply and peacefully as he does, and it will bring me as much
joy as it evidently does to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the entire internet is trying to predict whether or not the barrier will actually be broken. I can’t even really
comprehend quite how difficult a feat it will be if he manages to do it - it requires him to run 100m in 17 seconds, 422 times
consecutively, and I can’t even do it once. With that being said, I believe wholeheartedly he will do it - there is nothing really
to suggest that he won’t. I actually think he will smash the 2 hour mark, and take a whole minute off his 2017 attempt in Monza,
cruising to victory in 1:59:25 - and I can’t wait to find out tomorrow whether or not I’m right.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/11/ineos-159-challenge-i-predictions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/10/11/ineos-159-challenge-i-predictions</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Three Catchers In The Rye</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my life so far, I have gone through three distinct interpretations of JD Salinger’s classic,
&lt;em&gt;The Catcher In The Rye&lt;/em&gt;, particularly due to being an exceptionally privileged white male.
They can be summarised approximately as follows (in chronological order from my first read as 
a teenager until now):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Holden Caulfield finds himself alienated by his peers and surroundings, and really struggles
to fit in and find his place in this world. He is better than those around him,
and the fault is all theirs, they are the ones that need to change in order
to appease him, and they would, if only there were as intelligent and self-aware as he is.
He really sees the world clearly and it’s so refreshing to read a
novel where I can empathise so strongly with the protagonist! The world &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; unfair and Holden
deserves all the sympathy going. I am exactly like Holden.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Holden Caulfield alienates himself from his peers and surroundings, and refuses to fit in
or find his place in this world. He is not better than anyone around him, and the fault is all
his own, he needs to bury his self absorbed sense of narcissism, grow up and change in order
to integrate with his social environment. Holden is an asshole, an example of everything that
is wrong with young privileged men, and needs to undergo a huge shift in perspective before I
will have even one iota of respect for him. I am nothing like Holden.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Holden Caulfield alienates himself from his peers and surroundings, and refuses to fit in
or find his place in this world. He is not better than anyone around him, and the fault is all
his own, he needs to bury his self absorbed sense of narcissism, grow up and change in order
to integrate with his social environment. Holden is an asshole, an example of everything that
is wrong with young privileged men, and needs to undergo a huge shift in perspective before I
will have even one iota of respect for him. I am exactly like Holden.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been about 10 years since I first read the book, so perhaps in another 10 years time I’ll
have more thoughts about it. I’ll be sure to keep you all updated - as tiresome as that may be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/30/the-three-catchers-in-the-rye</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/30/the-three-catchers-in-the-rye</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Size Medium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After years of buying size large shirts, I decided to optimistically get a medium off the
internet, where I wouldn’t be able to try it on. I’ve lost a tiny amount of weight recently,
nothing exciting, but enough to be a little hopeful that it’d fit, and I figured if not, it’d
be extra motivation to keep going. It arrived yesterday, and it fits. What a relief.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/27/size-medium</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/27/size-medium</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Slave to One's Emotions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a slave to one’s emotions is tedious and draining, pulled apart in all directions even
during the course of a day, knowing full well what is happening but still unable to stop it. I
wish it weren’t the case, but it frustrates me a lot. Mindfulness alleges that it can help
create a pause in between emotional stimulus and response, and perhaps that is exactly what I
need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/26/a-slave-to-ones-emotions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/26/a-slave-to-ones-emotions</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sea and Cliffs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This might be a bit of a preachy one, so if you don’t like that kind of thing, kindly avert your gaze now. Arguably I shouldn’t
write posts I know are preachy in the first place, but given that I reinforced yesterday that this blog is an exercise in pure
self-service, I’ll permit myself to indulge my own ego a little further today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I went out for a run along the cliffs, to the southeastern most point of the island. I say run, I walked a great deal of
it, especially those sections that involved going up steps, there was also some plodding, some pussyfooting, and at times even
a complete cessation of movement. It was raining, windy, muddy, and dark when I set off, such that I had to take a headtorch to
avoid falling fall of some gnarled root or inconsiderately placed granite outcrop. After some amount of shuffling through the early
morning, including a handful of precarious slips, I emerged from the forest path onto a spit of land overlooking St Martin’s Point.
From said point, no other land is visible, the water stretches to the horizon, and in today’s tempestuous conditions, blue bled into
white bled into grey, and I felt a peculiar and unexpected feeling as I stared out into the tumult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was filled with a joy which I have not felt for weeks, almost overcome with my emotions, simply turning round and round on the spot
to survey all of the world that I could from that place. The power of the wind and the waves, the landscape seeming so bleak and
inhospitable, whisked away any of my fears, doubts and pains, and left behind only a palpable sense that life was all worth it for
moments like these, and nothing else really matters. I wanted to howl into the blustery void, knowing that my voice would be lost
immediately and that in that moment, I was powerless, and in so being absolved of all and any responsibilities and obligations,
for a few blissful moments on the cliffs I was free and at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/25/sea-and-cliffs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/25/sea-and-cliffs</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Purpose Of The Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After reflecting &lt;a href=&quot;/mendokusai/2019/09/23/listening&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; that I wanted to be better at listening,
I have been wondering whether writing this blog every day would be in contradiction of that stated aim.
At least for now, I don’t think they are, but it seems appropriate to reiterate the whole point of
writing this blog once again, for clarity in my own mind if nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These posts are not written with the expectation of being read - in many ways I would prefer the 
opposite were true. There are no illusions on my part about my voice being worthy of recognition or
deserving of being heard, the act of speaking into the void is what the aim is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In writing about difficult, stigmatised, shameful things on the internet, they are easier to talk about
in person, now I know that anybody could go and read them already should they so choose, and I have less
to hide. In writing about positive, wholesome things I can remind myself that there is enough beauty in
the world not to be disparaged by what I read in the news. Everything in between is a journal of sorts,
snapshots of the present that I can look back on and re-immerse myself in at some unspecified point in
the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s a nice balance to have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/24/the-purpose-of-the-blog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//mendokusai/2019/09/24/the-purpose-of-the-blog</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>